sentence_id,token_id,token,tag
0,0,The,O
0,1,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
0,2,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
0,3,in,O
0,4,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
0,5,stayed,O
0,6,closed,O
0,7,while,O
0,8,Samaritan,B-ORG
0,9,Aviation,I-ORG
0,10,moved,O
0,11,tarpaulin,B-AID_RESOURCE
0,12,rolls,I-AID_RESOURCE
0,13,through,O
0,14,back,O
0,15,roads,O
0,16,.,O
1,0,A,O
1,1,ice,B-DISASTER
1,2,jam,I-DISASTER
1,3,in,O
1,4,La,B-LOCATION
1,5,Paz,I-LOCATION
1,6,ruptured,O
1,7,the,O
1,8,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
1,9,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
1,10,",",O
1,11,and,O
1,12,families,B-CASUALTY
1,13,cut,I-CASUALTY
1,14,off,I-CASUALTY
1,15,needed,O
1,16,oral,B-AID_RESOURCE
1,17,rehydration,I-AID_RESOURCE
1,18,salts,I-AID_RESOURCE
1,19,.,O
2,0,Food,B-ORG
2,1,for,I-ORG
2,2,the,I-ORG
2,3,Hungry,I-ORG
2,4,treated,O
2,5,two,B-CASUALTY
2,6,nurses,I-CASUALTY
2,7,injured,I-CASUALTY
2,8,after,O
2,9,ridge,B-DISASTER
2,10,collapse,I-DISASTER
2,11,damaged,O
2,12,the,O
2,13,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
2,14,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
2,15,in,O
2,16,Bamako,B-LOCATION
2,17,.,O
3,0,The,O
3,1,fiber,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
3,2,line,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
3,3,in,O
3,4,Medellin,B-LOCATION
3,5,stayed,O
3,6,closed,O
3,7,while,O
3,8,RescueNet,B-ORG
3,9,moved,O
3,10,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
3,11,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
3,12,through,O
3,13,back,O
3,14,roads,O
3,15,.,O
4,0,Emergency,B-ORG
4,1,Logistics,I-ORG
4,2,Hub,I-ORG
4,3,reported,O
4,4,eight,B-CASUALTY
4,5,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
4,6,treated,I-CASUALTY
4,7,when,O
4,8,the,O
4,9,peat,B-DISASTER
4,10,fire,I-DISASTER
4,11,hit,O
4,12,the,O
4,13,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
4,14,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
4,15,outside,O
4,16,Suva,B-LOCATION
4,17,.,O
5,0,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
5,1,patients,I-CASUALTY
5,2,relocated,I-CASUALTY
5,3,were,O
5,4,found,O
5,5,near,O
5,6,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
5,7,after,O
5,8,the,O
5,9,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
5,10,Kaito,I-DISASTER
5,11,swept,O
5,12,across,O
5,13,the,O
5,14,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
5,15,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
5,16,.,O
6,0,Global,B-ORG
6,1,Shelter,I-ORG
6,2,Cluster,I-ORG
6,3,warned,O
6,4,that,O
6,5,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
6,6,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
6,7,were,O
6,8,running,O
6,9,low,O
6,10,in,O
6,11,Medellin,B-LOCATION
6,12,after,O
6,13,the,O
6,14,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
6,15,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
6,16,overflowed,O
6,17,.,O
7,0,MedGlobal,B-ORG
7,1,mapped,O
7,2,supply,O
7,3,gaps,O
7,4,near,O
7,5,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
7,6,",",O
7,7,where,O
7,8,many,B-CASUALTY
7,9,households,I-CASUALTY
7,10,displaced,I-CASUALTY
7,11,were,O
7,12,stranded,O
7,13,by,O
7,14,debris,B-DISASTER
7,15,flow,I-DISASTER
7,16,.,O
8,0,In,O
8,1,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
8,2,",",O
8,3,crews,O
8,4,requested,O
8,5,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
8,6,because,O
8,7,the,O
8,8,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
8,9,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
8,10,failed,O
8,11,during,O
8,12,the,O
8,13,snow,B-DISASTER
8,14,squall,I-DISASTER
8,15,.,O
9,0,After,O
9,1,the,O
9,2,ridge,B-DISASTER
9,3,collapse,I-DISASTER
9,4,",",O
9,5,Islamic,B-ORG
9,6,Relief,I-ORG
9,7,opened,O
9,8,a,O
9,9,staging,O
9,10,area,O
9,11,beside,O
9,12,the,O
9,13,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
9,14,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
9,15,for,O
9,16,eight,B-CASUALTY
9,17,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
9,18,treated,I-CASUALTY
9,19,.,O
10,0,Food,B-ORG
10,1,for,I-ORG
10,2,the,I-ORG
10,3,Hungry,I-ORG
10,4,delivered,O
10,5,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
10,6,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
10,7,to,O
10,8,Anchorage,B-LOCATION
10,9,after,O
10,10,rainwater,O
10,11,contaminated,O
10,12,the,O
10,13,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
10,14,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
10,15,.,O
11,0,In,O
11,1,Reykjavik,B-LOCATION
11,2,",",O
11,3,Global,B-ORG
11,4,Shelter,I-ORG
11,5,Cluster,I-ORG
11,6,opened,O
11,7,a,O
11,8,field,O
11,9,post,O
11,10,for,O
11,11,five,B-CASUALTY
11,12,workers,I-CASUALTY
11,13,trapped,I-CASUALTY
11,14,after,O
11,15,peat,B-DISASTER
11,16,fire,I-DISASTER
11,17,.,O
12,0,After,O
12,1,the,O
12,2,land,B-DISASTER
12,3,subsidence,I-DISASTER
12,4,",",O
12,5,RescueNet,B-ORG
12,6,opened,O
12,7,a,O
12,8,staging,O
12,9,area,O
12,10,beside,O
12,11,the,O
12,12,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
12,13,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
12,14,for,O
12,15,six,B-CASUALTY
12,16,volunteers,I-CASUALTY
12,17,hurt,I-CASUALTY
12,18,.,O
13,0,Community,B-ORG
13,1,rescue,I-ORG
13,2,brigade,I-ORG
13,3,sent,O
13,4,chlorine,B-AID_RESOURCE
13,5,tablets,I-AID_RESOURCE
13,6,to,O
13,7,Dakar,B-LOCATION
13,8,after,O
13,9,the,O
13,10,peat,B-DISASTER
13,11,fire,I-DISASTER
13,12,damaged,O
13,13,the,O
13,14,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
13,15,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
13,16,.,O
14,0,In,O
14,1,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
14,2,",",O
14,3,Samaritan,B-ORG
14,4,Aviation,I-ORG
14,5,reported,O
14,6,eight,B-CASUALTY
14,7,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
14,8,treated,I-CASUALTY
14,9,when,O
14,10,the,O
14,11,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
14,12,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
14,13,failed,O
14,14,.,O
15,0,urban,B-DISASTER
15,1,flash,I-DISASTER
15,2,flood,I-DISASTER
15,3,pushed,O
15,4,water,O
15,5,into,O
15,6,Cebu,B-LOCATION
15,7,",",O
15,8,knocking,O
15,9,out,O
15,10,the,O
15,11,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
15,12,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
15,13,.,O
16,0,ice,B-DISASTER
16,1,jam,I-DISASTER
16,2,in,O
16,3,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
16,4,carried,O
16,5,away,O
16,6,the,O
16,7,radio,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
16,8,repeater,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
16,9,",",O
16,10,isolating,O
16,11,schoolchildren,B-CASUALTY
16,12,stranded,I-CASUALTY
16,13,.,O
17,0,RescueNet,B-ORG
17,1,moved,O
17,2,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
17,3,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
17,4,to,O
17,5,Asmara,B-LOCATION
17,6,after,O
17,7,the,O
17,8,chemical,B-DISASTER
17,9,spill,I-DISASTER
17,10,shut,O
17,11,the,O
17,12,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
17,13,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
17,14,.,O
18,0,Community,B-ORG
18,1,rescue,I-ORG
18,2,brigade,I-ORG
18,3,warned,O
18,4,that,O
18,5,satellite,B-AID_RESOURCE
18,6,terminals,I-AID_RESOURCE
18,7,would,O
18,8,run,O
18,9,out,O
18,10,in,O
18,11,Valparaiso,B-LOCATION
18,12,if,O
18,13,the,O
18,14,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
18,15,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
18,16,remained,O
18,17,broken,O
18,18,.,O
19,0,The,O
19,1,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
19,2,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
19,3,in,O
19,4,Rabat,B-LOCATION
19,5,stayed,O
19,6,closed,O
19,7,while,O
19,8,Health,B-ORG
19,9,Bridge,I-ORG
19,10,moved,O
19,11,solar,B-AID_RESOURCE
19,12,lamps,I-AID_RESOURCE
19,13,through,O
19,14,back,O
19,15,roads,O
19,16,.,O
20,0,A,O
20,1,damaged,O
20,2,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
20,3,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
20,4,slowed,O
20,5,evacuation,O
20,6,from,O
20,7,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
20,8,;,O
20,9,Rapid,B-ORG
20,10,Relief,I-ORG
20,11,Team,I-ORG
20,12,asked,O
20,13,for,O
20,14,kitchen,B-AID_RESOURCE
20,15,sets,I-AID_RESOURCE
20,16,.,O
21,0,Telecoms,B-ORG
21,1,Without,I-ORG
21,2,Borders,I-ORG
21,3,treated,O
21,4,four,B-CASUALTY
21,5,passengers,I-CASUALTY
21,6,missing,I-CASUALTY
21,7,after,O
21,8,heatwave,B-DISASTER
21,9,damaged,O
21,10,the,O
21,11,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
21,12,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
21,13,in,O
21,14,Kampala,B-LOCATION
21,15,.,O
22,0,Search,O
22,1,crews,O
22,2,found,O
22,3,140,B-CASUALTY
22,4,people,I-CASUALTY
22,5,displaced,I-CASUALTY
22,6,under,O
22,7,the,O
22,8,collapsed,O
22,9,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
22,10,generator,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
22,11,in,O
22,12,Anchorage,B-LOCATION
22,13,.,O
23,0,Emergency,B-ORG
23,1,Logistics,I-ORG
23,2,Hub,I-ORG
23,3,warned,O
23,4,that,O
23,5,chlorine,B-AID_RESOURCE
23,6,tablets,I-AID_RESOURCE
23,7,would,O
23,8,run,O
23,9,out,O
23,10,in,O
23,11,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
23,12,if,O
23,13,the,O
23,14,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
23,15,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
23,16,remained,O
23,17,broken,O
23,18,.,O
24,0,CARE,B-ORG
24,1,teams,I-ORG
24,2,said,O
24,3,emergency,O
24,4,vehicles,O
24,5,could,O
24,6,not,O
24,7,reach,O
24,8,Bukhara,B-LOCATION
24,9,after,O
24,10,the,O
24,11,ridge,B-DISASTER
24,12,collapse,I-DISASTER
24,13,damaged,O
24,14,the,O
24,15,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
24,16,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
24,17,.,O
25,0,In,O
25,1,Reykjavik,B-LOCATION
25,2,",",O
25,3,Islamic,B-ORG
25,4,Relief,I-ORG
25,5,opened,O
25,6,a,O
25,7,field,O
25,8,post,O
25,9,for,O
25,10,four,B-CASUALTY
25,11,passengers,I-CASUALTY
25,12,missing,I-CASUALTY
25,13,after,O
25,14,monsoon,B-DISASTER
25,15,flood,I-DISASTER
25,16,.,O
26,0,dozens,B-CASUALTY
26,1,of,I-CASUALTY
26,2,children,I-CASUALTY
26,3,missing,I-CASUALTY
26,4,were,O
26,5,found,O
26,6,near,O
26,7,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
26,8,after,O
26,9,the,O
26,10,ridge,B-DISASTER
26,11,collapse,I-DISASTER
26,12,swept,O
26,13,across,O
26,14,the,O
26,15,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
26,16,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
26,17,.,O
27,0,In,O
27,1,Luanda,B-LOCATION
27,2,",",O
27,3,crews,O
27,4,requested,O
27,5,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
27,6,gloves,I-AID_RESOURCE
27,7,because,O
27,8,the,O
27,9,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
27,10,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
27,11,failed,O
27,12,during,O
27,13,the,O
27,14,heatwave,B-DISASTER
27,15,.,O
28,0,port,B-CASUALTY
28,1,staff,I-CASUALTY
28,2,missing,I-CASUALTY
28,3,were,O
28,4,found,O
28,5,near,O
28,6,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
28,7,after,O
28,8,the,O
28,9,heatwave,B-DISASTER
28,10,swept,O
28,11,across,O
28,12,the,O
28,13,mobile,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
28,14,tower,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
28,15,.,O
29,0,Relief,B-ORG
29,1,International,I-ORG
29,2,treated,O
29,3,five,B-CASUALTY
29,4,workers,I-CASUALTY
29,5,trapped,I-CASUALTY
29,6,after,O
29,7,ridge,B-DISASTER
29,8,collapse,I-DISASTER
29,9,damaged,O
29,10,the,O
29,11,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
29,12,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
29,13,in,O
29,14,Asmara,B-LOCATION
29,15,.,O
30,0,coastal,B-CASUALTY
30,1,residents,I-CASUALTY
30,2,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
30,3,were,O
30,4,found,O
30,5,near,O
30,6,Medellin,B-LOCATION
30,7,after,O
30,8,the,O
30,9,ash,B-DISASTER
30,10,cloud,I-DISASTER
30,11,swept,O
30,12,across,O
30,13,the,O
30,14,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
30,15,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
30,16,.,O
31,0,Telecoms,B-ORG
31,1,Without,I-ORG
31,2,Borders,I-ORG
31,3,used,O
31,4,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
31,5,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
31,6,to,O
31,7,support,O
31,8,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
31,9,patients,I-CASUALTY
31,10,relocated,I-CASUALTY
31,11,after,O
31,12,the,O
31,13,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
31,14,Kaito,I-DISASTER
31,15,isolated,O
31,16,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
31,17,.,O
32,0,Rapid,B-ORG
32,1,Relief,I-ORG
32,2,Team,I-ORG
32,3,used,O
32,4,mobile,B-AID_RESOURCE
32,5,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
32,6,to,O
32,7,support,O
32,8,17,B-CASUALTY
32,9,residents,I-CASUALTY
32,10,injured,I-CASUALTY
32,11,after,O
32,12,the,O
32,13,glacier,B-DISASTER
32,14,flood,I-DISASTER
32,15,isolated,O
32,16,Kampala,B-LOCATION
32,17,.,O
33,0,Local,B-ORG
33,1,Red,I-ORG
33,2,Crescent,I-ORG
33,3,treated,O
33,4,schoolchildren,B-CASUALTY
33,5,stranded,I-CASUALTY
33,6,after,O
33,7,peat,B-DISASTER
33,8,fire,I-DISASTER
33,9,damaged,O
33,10,the,O
33,11,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
33,12,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
33,13,in,O
33,14,Valparaiso,B-LOCATION
33,15,.,O
34,0,Local,O
34,1,officials,O
34,2,in,O
34,3,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
34,4,said,O
34,5,the,O
34,6,cold,B-DISASTER
34,7,snap,I-DISASTER
34,8,forced,O
34,9,market,B-CASUALTY
34,10,vendors,I-CASUALTY
34,11,injured,I-CASUALTY
34,12,from,O
34,13,homes,O
34,14,near,O
34,15,the,O
34,16,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
34,17,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
34,18,.,O
35,0,In,O
35,1,Cebu,B-LOCATION
35,2,",",O
35,3,crews,O
35,4,requested,O
35,5,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
35,6,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
35,7,because,O
35,8,the,O
35,9,mobile,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
35,10,tower,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
35,11,failed,O
35,12,during,O
35,13,the,O
35,14,dam,B-DISASTER
35,15,burst,I-DISASTER
35,16,.,O
36,0,The,O
36,1,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
36,2,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
36,3,in,O
36,4,Bergen,B-LOCATION
36,5,stayed,O
36,6,closed,O
36,7,while,O
36,8,Water,B-ORG
36,9,Mission,I-ORG
36,10,moved,O
36,11,solar,B-AID_RESOURCE
36,12,lamps,I-AID_RESOURCE
36,13,through,O
36,14,back,O
36,15,roads,O
36,16,.,O
37,0,CARE,B-ORG
37,1,teams,I-ORG
37,2,moved,O
37,3,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
37,4,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
37,5,to,O
37,6,Kigali,B-LOCATION
37,7,after,O
37,8,the,O
37,9,land,B-DISASTER
37,10,subsidence,I-DISASTER
37,11,damaged,O
37,12,the,O
37,13,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
37,14,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
37,15,.,O
38,0,The,O
38,1,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
38,2,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
38,3,in,O
38,4,Reykjavik,B-LOCATION
38,5,stayed,O
38,6,closed,O
38,7,while,O
38,8,Food,B-ORG
38,9,for,I-ORG
38,10,the,I-ORG
38,11,Hungry,I-ORG
38,12,moved,O
38,13,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
38,14,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
38,15,through,O
38,16,back,O
38,17,roads,O
38,18,.,O
39,0,glacier,B-DISASTER
39,1,flood,I-DISASTER
39,2,pushed,O
39,3,water,O
39,4,into,O
39,5,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
39,6,",",O
39,7,knocking,O
39,8,out,O
39,9,the,O
39,10,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
39,11,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
39,12,.,O
40,0,A,O
40,1,damaged,O
40,2,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
40,3,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
40,4,slowed,O
40,5,evacuation,O
40,6,from,O
40,7,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
40,8,;,O
40,9,Blue,B-ORG
40,10,Shield,I-ORG
40,11,volunteers,I-ORG
40,12,asked,O
40,13,for,O
40,14,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
40,15,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
40,16,.,O
41,0,Health,B-ORG
41,1,Bridge,I-ORG
41,2,sent,O
41,3,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
41,4,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
41,5,to,O
41,6,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
41,7,after,O
41,8,the,O
41,9,heatwave,B-DISASTER
41,10,damaged,O
41,11,the,O
41,12,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
41,13,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
41,14,.,O
42,0,A,O
42,1,torrential,B-DISASTER
42,2,rain,I-DISASTER
42,3,above,O
42,4,La,B-LOCATION
42,5,Paz,I-LOCATION
42,6,blocked,O
42,7,the,O
42,8,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
42,9,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
42,10,",",O
42,11,leaving,O
42,12,families,B-CASUALTY
42,13,cut,I-CASUALTY
42,14,off,I-CASUALTY
42,15,.,O
43,0,RescueNet,B-ORG
43,1,warned,O
43,2,that,O
43,3,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
43,4,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
43,5,were,O
43,6,running,O
43,7,low,O
43,8,in,O
43,9,Medellin,B-LOCATION
43,10,after,O
43,11,the,O
43,12,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
43,13,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
43,14,overflowed,O
43,15,.,O
44,0,Global,B-ORG
44,1,Shelter,I-ORG
44,2,Cluster,I-ORG
44,3,moved,O
44,4,search,B-AID_RESOURCE
44,5,drones,I-AID_RESOURCE
44,6,to,O
44,7,Kigali,B-LOCATION
44,8,after,O
44,9,the,O
44,10,earth,B-DISASTER
44,11,tremor,I-DISASTER
44,12,shut,O
44,13,the,O
44,14,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
44,15,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
44,16,.,O
45,0,A,O
45,1,damaged,O
45,2,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
45,3,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
45,4,slowed,O
45,5,evacuation,O
45,6,from,O
45,7,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
45,8,;,O
45,9,Telecoms,B-ORG
45,10,Without,I-ORG
45,11,Borders,I-ORG
45,12,asked,O
45,13,for,O
45,14,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
45,15,.,O
46,0,earth,B-DISASTER
46,1,tremor,I-DISASTER
46,2,pushed,O
46,3,water,O
46,4,into,O
46,5,La,B-LOCATION
46,6,Paz,I-LOCATION
46,7,",",O
46,8,knocking,O
46,9,out,O
46,10,the,O
46,11,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
46,12,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
46,13,.,O
47,0,Crisis,B-ORG
47,1,Response,I-ORG
47,2,Unit,I-ORG
47,3,mapped,O
47,4,supply,O
47,5,gaps,O
47,6,near,O
47,7,Kampala,B-LOCATION
47,8,",",O
47,9,where,O
47,10,six,B-CASUALTY
47,11,volunteers,I-CASUALTY
47,12,hurt,I-CASUALTY
47,13,were,O
47,14,stranded,O
47,15,by,O
47,16,ice,B-DISASTER
47,17,jam,I-DISASTER
47,18,.,O
48,0,Blue,B-ORG
48,1,Shield,I-ORG
48,2,volunteers,I-ORG
48,3,used,O
48,4,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
48,5,bladders,I-AID_RESOURCE
48,6,to,O
48,7,support,O
48,8,eight,B-CASUALTY
48,9,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
48,10,treated,I-CASUALTY
48,11,after,O
48,12,the,O
48,13,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
48,14,Kaito,I-DISASTER
48,15,isolated,O
48,16,Valparaiso,B-LOCATION
48,17,.,O
49,0,Local,O
49,1,officials,O
49,2,in,O
49,3,Dili,B-LOCATION
49,4,said,O
49,5,the,O
49,6,urban,B-DISASTER
49,7,flash,I-DISASTER
49,8,flood,I-DISASTER
49,9,forced,O
49,10,three,B-CASUALTY
49,11,drivers,I-CASUALTY
49,12,rescued,I-CASUALTY
49,13,from,O
49,14,homes,O
49,15,near,O
49,16,the,O
49,17,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
49,18,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
49,19,.,O
50,0,glacier,B-DISASTER
50,1,flood,I-DISASTER
50,2,froze,O
50,3,the,O
50,4,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
50,5,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
50,6,near,O
50,7,Tbilisi,B-LOCATION
50,8,",",O
50,9,delaying,O
50,10,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
50,11,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
50,12,from,O
50,13,Islamic,B-ORG
50,14,Relief,I-ORG
50,15,.,O
51,0,A,O
51,1,dam,B-DISASTER
51,2,burst,I-DISASTER
51,3,in,O
51,4,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
51,5,ruptured,O
51,6,the,O
51,7,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
51,8,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
51,9,",",O
51,10,and,O
51,11,three,B-CASUALTY
51,12,drivers,I-CASUALTY
51,13,rescued,I-CASUALTY
51,14,needed,O
51,15,thermal,B-AID_RESOURCE
51,16,blankets,I-AID_RESOURCE
51,17,.,O
52,0,A,O
52,1,chemical,B-DISASTER
52,2,spill,I-DISASTER
52,3,in,O
52,4,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
52,5,ruptured,O
52,6,the,O
52,7,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
52,8,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
52,9,",",O
52,10,and,O
52,11,two,B-CASUALTY
52,12,nurses,I-CASUALTY
52,13,injured,I-CASUALTY
52,14,needed,O
52,15,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
52,16,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
52,17,.,O
53,0,Blue,B-ORG
53,1,Shield,I-ORG
53,2,volunteers,I-ORG
53,3,mapped,O
53,4,supply,O
53,5,gaps,O
53,6,near,O
53,7,Kigali,B-LOCATION
53,8,",",O
53,9,where,O
53,10,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
53,11,patients,I-CASUALTY
53,12,relocated,I-CASUALTY
53,13,were,O
53,14,stranded,O
53,15,by,O
53,16,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
53,17,Vira,I-DISASTER
53,18,.,O
54,0,Samaritan,B-ORG
54,1,Aviation,I-ORG
54,2,said,O
54,3,emergency,O
54,4,vehicles,O
54,5,could,O
54,6,not,O
54,7,reach,O
54,8,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
54,9,after,O
54,10,the,O
54,11,ash,B-DISASTER
54,12,cloud,I-DISASTER
54,13,damaged,O
54,14,the,O
54,15,coastal,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
54,16,pier,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
54,17,.,O
55,0,Global,B-ORG
55,1,Shelter,I-ORG
55,2,Cluster,I-ORG
55,3,said,O
55,4,emergency,O
55,5,vehicles,O
55,6,could,O
55,7,not,O
55,8,reach,O
55,9,Georgetown,B-LOCATION
55,10,after,O
55,11,the,O
55,12,dam,B-DISASTER
55,13,burst,I-DISASTER
55,14,damaged,O
55,15,the,O
55,16,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
55,17,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
55,18,.,O
56,0,After,O
56,1,the,O
56,2,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
56,3,Vira,I-DISASTER
56,4,",",O
56,5,Relief,B-ORG
56,6,International,I-ORG
56,7,opened,O
56,8,a,O
56,9,staging,O
56,10,area,O
56,11,beside,O
56,12,the,O
56,13,coastal,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
56,14,pier,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
56,15,for,O
56,16,eight,B-CASUALTY
56,17,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
56,18,treated,I-CASUALTY
56,19,.,O
57,0,In,O
57,1,Medellin,B-LOCATION
57,2,",",O
57,3,Emergency,B-ORG
57,4,Logistics,I-ORG
57,5,Hub,I-ORG
57,6,reported,O
57,7,many,B-CASUALTY
57,8,households,I-CASUALTY
57,9,displaced,I-CASUALTY
57,10,when,O
57,11,the,O
57,12,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
57,13,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
57,14,failed,O
57,15,.,O
58,0,Crisis,B-ORG
58,1,Response,I-ORG
58,2,Unit,I-ORG
58,3,reported,O
58,4,eight,B-CASUALTY
58,5,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
58,6,treated,I-CASUALTY
58,7,when,O
58,8,the,O
58,9,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
58,10,Vira,I-DISASTER
58,11,hit,O
58,12,the,O
58,13,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
58,14,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
58,15,outside,O
58,16,Suva,B-LOCATION
58,17,.,O
59,0,Aviation,B-ORG
59,1,Sans,I-ORG
59,2,Frontieres,I-ORG
59,3,treated,O
59,4,port,B-CASUALTY
59,5,staff,I-CASUALTY
59,6,missing,I-CASUALTY
59,7,after,O
59,8,urban,B-DISASTER
59,9,flash,I-DISASTER
59,10,flood,I-DISASTER
59,11,damaged,O
59,12,the,O
59,13,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
59,14,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
59,15,in,O
59,16,La,B-LOCATION
59,17,Paz,I-LOCATION
59,18,.,O
60,0,chemical,B-DISASTER
60,1,spill,I-DISASTER
60,2,pushed,O
60,3,water,O
60,4,into,O
60,5,Zanzibar,B-LOCATION
60,6,",",O
60,7,knocking,O
60,8,out,O
60,9,the,O
60,10,coastal,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
60,11,pier,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
60,12,.,O
61,0,Before,O
61,1,dawn,O
61,2,",",O
61,3,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
61,4,Kaito,I-DISASTER
61,5,cut,O
61,6,power,O
61,7,in,O
61,8,Thimphu,B-LOCATION
61,9,while,O
61,10,Aviation,B-ORG
61,11,Sans,I-ORG
61,12,Frontieres,I-ORG
61,13,requested,O
61,14,chlorine,B-AID_RESOURCE
61,15,tablets,I-AID_RESOURCE
61,16,.,O
62,0,CARE,B-ORG
62,1,teams,I-ORG
62,2,warned,O
62,3,that,O
62,4,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
62,5,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
62,6,would,O
62,7,run,O
62,8,out,O
62,9,in,O
62,10,Luanda,B-LOCATION
62,11,if,O
62,12,the,O
62,13,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
62,14,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
62,15,remained,O
62,16,broken,O
62,17,.,O
63,0,A,O
63,1,peat,B-DISASTER
63,2,fire,I-DISASTER
63,3,in,O
63,4,Thimphu,B-LOCATION
63,5,ruptured,O
63,6,the,O
63,7,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
63,8,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
63,9,",",O
63,10,and,O
63,11,140,B-CASUALTY
63,12,people,I-CASUALTY
63,13,displaced,I-CASUALTY
63,14,needed,O
63,15,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
63,16,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
63,17,.,O
64,0,Humanity,B-ORG
64,1,First,I-ORG
64,2,moved,O
64,3,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
64,4,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
64,5,to,O
64,6,Dakar,B-LOCATION
64,7,after,O
64,8,the,O
64,9,heatwave,B-DISASTER
64,10,damaged,O
64,11,the,O
64,12,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
64,13,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
64,14,.,O
65,0,Action,B-ORG
65,1,Against,I-ORG
65,2,Hunger,I-ORG
65,3,treated,O
65,4,140,B-CASUALTY
65,5,people,I-CASUALTY
65,6,displaced,I-CASUALTY
65,7,after,O
65,8,debris,B-DISASTER
65,9,flow,I-DISASTER
65,10,damaged,O
65,11,the,O
65,12,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
65,13,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
65,14,in,O
65,15,Georgetown,B-LOCATION
65,16,.,O
66,0,Community,B-ORG
66,1,rescue,I-ORG
66,2,brigade,I-ORG
66,3,said,O
66,4,the,O
66,5,rockfall,B-DISASTER
66,6,flooded,O
66,7,the,O
66,8,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
66,9,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
66,10,and,O
66,11,spoiled,O
66,12,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
66,13,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
66,14,.,O
67,0,The,O
67,1,radio,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
67,2,repeater,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
67,3,in,O
67,4,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
67,5,stayed,O
67,6,closed,O
67,7,while,O
67,8,Relief,B-ORG
67,9,International,I-ORG
67,10,moved,O
67,11,satellite,B-AID_RESOURCE
67,12,terminals,I-AID_RESOURCE
67,13,through,O
67,14,back,O
67,15,roads,O
67,16,.,O
68,0,Search,O
68,1,crews,O
68,2,found,O
68,3,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
68,4,patients,I-CASUALTY
68,5,relocated,I-CASUALTY
68,6,under,O
68,7,the,O
68,8,collapsed,O
68,9,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
68,10,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
68,11,in,O
68,12,Zanzibar,B-LOCATION
68,13,.,O
69,0,In,O
69,1,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
69,2,",",O
69,3,Relief,B-ORG
69,4,International,I-ORG
69,5,opened,O
69,6,a,O
69,7,field,O
69,8,post,O
69,9,for,O
69,10,17,B-CASUALTY
69,11,residents,I-CASUALTY
69,12,injured,I-CASUALTY
69,13,after,O
69,14,ridge,B-DISASTER
69,15,collapse,I-DISASTER
69,16,.,O
70,0,Near,O
70,1,La,B-LOCATION
70,2,Paz,I-LOCATION
70,3,",",O
70,4,the,O
70,5,river,B-DISASTER
70,6,overflow,I-DISASTER
70,7,swept,O
70,8,through,O
70,9,the,O
70,10,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
70,11,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
70,12,and,O
70,13,left,O
70,14,140,B-CASUALTY
70,15,people,I-CASUALTY
70,16,displaced,I-CASUALTY
70,17,.,O
71,0,nine,B-CASUALTY
71,1,families,I-CASUALTY
71,2,stranded,I-CASUALTY
71,3,were,O
71,4,found,O
71,5,near,O
71,6,Dakar,B-LOCATION
71,7,after,O
71,8,the,O
71,9,river,B-DISASTER
71,10,overflow,I-DISASTER
71,11,swept,O
71,12,across,O
71,13,the,O
71,14,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
71,15,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
71,16,.,O
72,0,A,O
72,1,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
72,2,Kaito,I-DISASTER
72,3,closed,O
72,4,the,O
72,5,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
72,6,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
72,7,to,O
72,8,Port,B-LOCATION
72,9,Vila,I-LOCATION
72,10,",",O
72,11,stranding,O
72,12,MedGlobal,B-ORG
72,13,with,O
72,14,trauma,B-AID_RESOURCE
72,15,bandages,I-AID_RESOURCE
72,16,.,O
73,0,heatwave,B-DISASTER
73,1,in,O
73,2,Zanzibar,B-LOCATION
73,3,carried,O
73,4,away,O
73,5,the,O
73,6,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
73,7,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
73,8,",",O
73,9,isolating,O
73,10,coastal,B-CASUALTY
73,11,residents,I-CASUALTY
73,12,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
73,13,.,O
74,0,Telecoms,B-ORG
74,1,Without,I-ORG
74,2,Borders,I-ORG
74,3,said,O
74,4,the,O
74,5,glacier,B-DISASTER
74,6,flood,I-DISASTER
74,7,flooded,O
74,8,the,O
74,9,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
74,10,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
74,11,and,O
74,12,spoiled,O
74,13,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
74,14,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
74,15,.,O
75,0,MedGlobal,B-ORG
75,1,delivered,O
75,2,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
75,3,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
75,4,to,O
75,5,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
75,6,after,O
75,7,rainwater,O
75,8,contaminated,O
75,9,the,O
75,10,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
75,11,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
75,12,.,O
76,0,A,O
76,1,ridge,B-DISASTER
76,2,collapse,I-DISASTER
76,3,in,O
76,4,Dakar,B-LOCATION
76,5,ruptured,O
76,6,the,O
76,7,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
76,8,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
76,9,",",O
76,10,and,O
76,11,elderly,B-CASUALTY
76,12,patients,I-CASUALTY
76,13,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
76,14,needed,O
76,15,oral,B-AID_RESOURCE
76,16,rehydration,I-AID_RESOURCE
76,17,salts,I-AID_RESOURCE
76,18,.,O
77,0,A,O
77,1,glacier,B-DISASTER
77,2,flood,I-DISASTER
77,3,above,O
77,4,Bandar,B-LOCATION
77,5,Seri,I-LOCATION
77,6,Begawan,I-LOCATION
77,7,blocked,O
77,8,the,O
77,9,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
77,10,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
77,11,",",O
77,12,leaving,O
77,13,17,B-CASUALTY
77,14,residents,I-CASUALTY
77,15,injured,I-CASUALTY
77,16,.,O
78,0,Emergency,B-ORG
78,1,Logistics,I-ORG
78,2,Hub,I-ORG
78,3,said,O
78,4,emergency,O
78,5,vehicles,O
78,6,could,O
78,7,not,O
78,8,reach,O
78,9,Valparaiso,B-LOCATION
78,10,after,O
78,11,the,O
78,12,river,B-DISASTER
78,13,overflow,I-DISASTER
78,14,damaged,O
78,15,the,O
78,16,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
78,17,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
78,18,.,O
79,0,Near,O
79,1,Bukhara,B-LOCATION
79,2,",",O
79,3,the,O
79,4,river,B-DISASTER
79,5,overflow,I-DISASTER
79,6,swept,O
79,7,through,O
79,8,the,O
79,9,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
79,10,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
79,11,and,O
79,12,left,O
79,13,nine,B-CASUALTY
79,14,families,I-CASUALTY
79,15,stranded,I-CASUALTY
79,16,.,O
80,0,A,O
80,1,damaged,O
80,2,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
80,3,generator,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
80,4,slowed,O
80,5,evacuation,O
80,6,from,O
80,7,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
80,8,;,O
80,9,Local,B-ORG
80,10,Red,I-ORG
80,11,Crescent,I-ORG
80,12,asked,O
80,13,for,O
80,14,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
80,15,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
80,16,.,O
81,0,The,O
81,1,coastal,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
81,2,pier,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
81,3,in,O
81,4,Port,B-LOCATION
81,5,Vila,I-LOCATION
81,6,stayed,O
81,7,closed,O
81,8,while,O
81,9,Action,B-ORG
81,10,Against,I-ORG
81,11,Hunger,I-ORG
81,12,moved,O
81,13,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
81,14,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
81,15,through,O
81,16,back,O
81,17,roads,O
81,18,.,O
82,0,Near,O
82,1,Bandar,B-LOCATION
82,2,Seri,I-LOCATION
82,3,Begawan,I-LOCATION
82,4,",",O
82,5,the,O
82,6,peat,B-DISASTER
82,7,fire,I-DISASTER
82,8,swept,O
82,9,through,O
82,10,the,O
82,11,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
82,12,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
82,13,and,O
82,14,left,O
82,15,port,B-CASUALTY
82,16,staff,I-CASUALTY
82,17,missing,I-CASUALTY
82,18,.,O
83,0,volcanic,B-DISASTER
83,1,eruption,I-DISASTER
83,2,pushed,O
83,3,water,O
83,4,into,O
83,5,Kampala,B-LOCATION
83,6,",",O
83,7,knocking,O
83,8,out,O
83,9,the,O
83,10,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
83,11,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
83,12,.,O
84,0,Food,B-ORG
84,1,for,I-ORG
84,2,the,I-ORG
84,3,Hungry,I-ORG
84,4,moved,O
84,5,infant,B-AID_RESOURCE
84,6,milk,I-AID_RESOURCE
84,7,to,O
84,8,Suva,B-LOCATION
84,9,after,O
84,10,the,O
84,11,earth,B-DISASTER
84,12,tremor,I-DISASTER
84,13,damaged,O
84,14,the,O
84,15,rail,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
84,16,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
84,17,.,O
85,0,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
85,1,patients,I-CASUALTY
85,2,relocated,I-CASUALTY
85,3,were,O
85,4,found,O
85,5,near,O
85,6,Asmara,B-LOCATION
85,7,after,O
85,8,the,O
85,9,cold,B-DISASTER
85,10,snap,I-DISASTER
85,11,swept,O
85,12,across,O
85,13,the,O
85,14,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
85,15,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
85,16,.,O
86,0,Health,B-ORG
86,1,Bridge,I-ORG
86,2,reported,O
86,3,dozens,B-CASUALTY
86,4,of,I-CASUALTY
86,5,children,I-CASUALTY
86,6,missing,I-CASUALTY
86,7,when,O
86,8,the,O
86,9,cold,B-DISASTER
86,10,snap,I-DISASTER
86,11,hit,O
86,12,the,O
86,13,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
86,14,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
86,15,outside,O
86,16,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
86,17,.,O
87,0,The,O
87,1,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
87,2,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
87,3,in,O
87,4,Georgetown,B-LOCATION
87,5,stayed,O
87,6,closed,O
87,7,while,O
87,8,Food,B-ORG
87,9,for,I-ORG
87,10,the,I-ORG
87,11,Hungry,I-ORG
87,12,moved,O
87,13,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
87,14,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
87,15,through,O
87,16,back,O
87,17,roads,O
87,18,.,O
88,0,In,O
88,1,Reykjavik,B-LOCATION
88,2,",",O
88,3,Global,B-ORG
88,4,Shelter,I-ORG
88,5,Cluster,I-ORG
88,6,reported,O
88,7,many,B-CASUALTY
88,8,households,I-CASUALTY
88,9,displaced,I-CASUALTY
88,10,when,O
88,11,the,O
88,12,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
88,13,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
88,14,failed,O
88,15,.,O
89,0,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
89,1,Vira,I-DISASTER
89,2,froze,O
89,3,the,O
89,4,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
89,5,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
89,6,near,O
89,7,Kampala,B-LOCATION
89,8,",",O
89,9,delaying,O
89,10,satellite,B-AID_RESOURCE
89,11,terminals,I-AID_RESOURCE
89,12,from,O
89,13,Blue,B-ORG
89,14,Shield,I-ORG
89,15,volunteers,I-ORG
89,16,.,O
90,0,Blue,B-ORG
90,1,Shield,I-ORG
90,2,volunteers,I-ORG
90,3,sent,O
90,4,emergency,B-AID_RESOURCE
90,5,meals,I-AID_RESOURCE
90,6,to,O
90,7,Medellin,B-LOCATION
90,8,after,O
90,9,the,O
90,10,rockfall,B-DISASTER
90,11,damaged,O
90,12,the,O
90,13,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
90,14,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
90,15,.,O
91,0,CARE,B-ORG
91,1,teams,I-ORG
91,2,delivered,O
91,3,tarpaulin,B-AID_RESOURCE
91,4,rolls,I-AID_RESOURCE
91,5,to,O
91,6,Asmara,B-LOCATION
91,7,after,O
91,8,rainwater,O
91,9,contaminated,O
91,10,the,O
91,11,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
91,12,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
91,13,.,O
92,0,MedGlobal,B-ORG
92,1,said,O
92,2,the,O
92,3,debris,B-DISASTER
92,4,flow,I-DISASTER
92,5,flooded,O
92,6,the,O
92,7,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
92,8,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
92,9,and,O
92,10,spoiled,O
92,11,satellite,B-AID_RESOURCE
92,12,terminals,I-AID_RESOURCE
92,13,.,O
93,0,In,O
93,1,Valparaiso,B-LOCATION
93,2,",",O
93,3,CARE,B-ORG
93,4,teams,I-ORG
93,5,opened,O
93,6,a,O
93,7,field,O
93,8,post,O
93,9,for,O
93,10,many,B-CASUALTY
93,11,households,I-CASUALTY
93,12,displaced,I-CASUALTY
93,13,after,O
93,14,rockfall,B-DISASTER
93,15,.,O
94,0,Food,B-ORG
94,1,for,I-ORG
94,2,the,I-ORG
94,3,Hungry,I-ORG
94,4,moved,O
94,5,satellite,B-AID_RESOURCE
94,6,terminals,I-AID_RESOURCE
94,7,to,O
94,8,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
94,9,after,O
94,10,the,O
94,11,earth,B-DISASTER
94,12,tremor,I-DISASTER
94,13,shut,O
94,14,the,O
94,15,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
94,16,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
94,17,.,O
95,0,The,O
95,1,earth,B-DISASTER
95,2,tremor,I-DISASTER
95,3,cracked,O
95,4,the,O
95,5,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
95,6,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
95,7,outside,O
95,8,Medellin,B-LOCATION
95,9,",",O
95,10,so,O
95,11,MedGlobal,B-ORG
95,12,sent,O
95,13,tarpaulin,B-AID_RESOURCE
95,14,rolls,I-AID_RESOURCE
95,15,.,O
96,0,A,O
96,1,urban,B-DISASTER
96,2,flash,I-DISASTER
96,3,flood,I-DISASTER
96,4,above,O
96,5,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
96,6,blocked,O
96,7,the,O
96,8,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
96,9,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
96,10,",",O
96,11,leaving,O
96,12,140,B-CASUALTY
96,13,people,I-CASUALTY
96,14,displaced,I-CASUALTY
96,15,.,O
97,0,The,O
97,1,urban,B-DISASTER
97,2,flash,I-DISASTER
97,3,flood,I-DISASTER
97,4,cut,O
97,5,access,O
97,6,to,O
97,7,the,O
97,8,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
97,9,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
97,10,",",O
97,11,so,O
97,12,Relief,B-ORG
97,13,International,I-ORG
97,14,routed,O
97,15,diesel,B-AID_RESOURCE
97,16,drums,I-AID_RESOURCE
97,17,toward,O
97,18,Georgetown,B-LOCATION
97,19,.,O
98,0,In,O
98,1,Valparaiso,B-LOCATION
98,2,",",O
98,3,crews,O
98,4,requested,O
98,5,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
98,6,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
98,7,because,O
98,8,the,O
98,9,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
98,10,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
98,11,failed,O
98,12,during,O
98,13,the,O
98,14,earth,B-DISASTER
98,15,tremor,I-DISASTER
98,16,.,O
99,0,RescueNet,B-ORG
99,1,sent,O
99,2,satellite,B-AID_RESOURCE
99,3,terminals,I-AID_RESOURCE
99,4,to,O
99,5,Cebu,B-LOCATION
99,6,after,O
99,7,the,O
99,8,debris,B-DISASTER
99,9,flow,I-DISASTER
99,10,damaged,O
99,11,the,O
99,12,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
99,13,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
99,14,.,O
100,0,Rapid,B-ORG
100,1,Relief,I-ORG
100,2,Team,I-ORG
100,3,delivered,O
100,4,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
100,5,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
100,6,to,O
100,7,Medellin,B-LOCATION
100,8,after,O
100,9,rainwater,O
100,10,contaminated,O
100,11,the,O
100,12,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
100,13,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
100,14,.,O
101,0,The,O
101,1,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
101,2,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
101,3,in,O
101,4,Nuku,B-LOCATION
101,5,',I-LOCATION
101,6,alofa,I-LOCATION
101,7,stayed,O
101,8,closed,O
101,9,while,O
101,10,Islamic,B-ORG
101,11,Relief,I-ORG
101,12,moved,O
101,13,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
101,14,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
101,15,through,O
101,16,back,O
101,17,roads,O
101,18,.,O
102,0,Telecoms,B-ORG
102,1,Without,I-ORG
102,2,Borders,I-ORG
102,3,moved,O
102,4,emergency,B-AID_RESOURCE
102,5,meals,I-AID_RESOURCE
102,6,to,O
102,7,Suva,B-LOCATION
102,8,after,O
102,9,the,O
102,10,ridge,B-DISASTER
102,11,collapse,I-DISASTER
102,12,shut,O
102,13,the,O
102,14,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
102,15,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
102,16,.,O
103,0,Search,O
103,1,crews,O
103,2,found,O
103,3,six,B-CASUALTY
103,4,volunteers,I-CASUALTY
103,5,hurt,I-CASUALTY
103,6,under,O
103,7,the,O
103,8,collapsed,O
103,9,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
103,10,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
103,11,in,O
103,12,Bamako,B-LOCATION
103,13,.,O
104,0,CARE,B-ORG
104,1,teams,I-ORG
104,2,said,O
104,3,the,O
104,4,ash,B-DISASTER
104,5,cloud,I-DISASTER
104,6,flooded,O
104,7,the,O
104,8,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
104,9,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
104,10,and,O
104,11,spoiled,O
104,12,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
104,13,filters,I-AID_RESOURCE
104,14,.,O
105,0,After,O
105,1,the,O
105,2,cold,B-DISASTER
105,3,snap,I-DISASTER
105,4,",",O
105,5,the,O
105,6,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
105,7,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
105,8,asked,O
105,9,Rapid,B-ORG
105,10,Relief,I-ORG
105,11,Team,I-ORG
105,12,for,O
105,13,solar,B-AID_RESOURCE
105,14,lamps,I-AID_RESOURCE
105,15,.,O
106,0,cold,B-DISASTER
106,1,snap,I-DISASTER
106,2,pushed,O
106,3,water,O
106,4,into,O
106,5,Cebu,B-LOCATION
106,6,",",O
106,7,knocking,O
106,8,out,O
106,9,the,O
106,10,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
106,11,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
106,12,.,O
107,0,Food,B-ORG
107,1,for,I-ORG
107,2,the,I-ORG
107,3,Hungry,I-ORG
107,4,warned,O
107,5,that,O
107,6,oral,B-AID_RESOURCE
107,7,rehydration,I-AID_RESOURCE
107,8,salts,I-AID_RESOURCE
107,9,would,O
107,10,run,O
107,11,out,O
107,12,in,O
107,13,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
107,14,if,O
107,15,the,O
107,16,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
107,17,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
107,18,remained,O
107,19,broken,O
107,20,.,O
108,0,In,O
108,1,Bukhara,B-LOCATION
108,2,",",O
108,3,crews,O
108,4,requested,O
108,5,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
108,6,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
108,7,because,O
108,8,the,O
108,9,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
108,10,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
108,11,failed,O
108,12,during,O
108,13,the,O
108,14,debris,B-DISASTER
108,15,flow,I-DISASTER
108,16,.,O
109,0,Health,B-ORG
109,1,Bridge,I-ORG
109,2,said,O
109,3,the,O
109,4,ash,B-DISASTER
109,5,cloud,I-DISASTER
109,6,flooded,O
109,7,the,O
109,8,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
109,9,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
109,10,and,O
109,11,spoiled,O
109,12,tarpaulin,B-AID_RESOURCE
109,13,rolls,I-AID_RESOURCE
109,14,.,O
110,0,urban,B-DISASTER
110,1,flash,I-DISASTER
110,2,flood,I-DISASTER
110,3,in,O
110,4,Bamako,B-LOCATION
110,5,carried,O
110,6,away,O
110,7,the,O
110,8,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
110,9,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
110,10,",",O
110,11,isolating,O
110,12,eight,B-CASUALTY
110,13,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
110,14,treated,I-CASUALTY
110,15,.,O
111,0,Global,B-ORG
111,1,Shelter,I-ORG
111,2,Cluster,I-ORG
111,3,treated,O
111,4,17,B-CASUALTY
111,5,residents,I-CASUALTY
111,6,injured,I-CASUALTY
111,7,after,O
111,8,debris,B-DISASTER
111,9,flow,I-DISASTER
111,10,damaged,O
111,11,the,O
111,12,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
111,13,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
111,14,in,O
111,15,Kampala,B-LOCATION
111,16,.,O
112,0,Food,B-ORG
112,1,for,I-ORG
112,2,the,I-ORG
112,3,Hungry,I-ORG
112,4,reported,O
112,5,eight,B-CASUALTY
112,6,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
112,7,treated,I-CASUALTY
112,8,when,O
112,9,the,O
112,10,heatwave,B-DISASTER
112,11,hit,O
112,12,the,O
112,13,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
112,14,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
112,15,outside,O
112,16,Georgetown,B-LOCATION
112,17,.,O
113,0,In,O
113,1,Nuku,B-LOCATION
113,2,',I-LOCATION
113,3,alofa,I-LOCATION
113,4,",",O
113,5,a,O
113,6,ash,B-DISASTER
113,7,cloud,I-DISASTER
113,8,buried,O
113,9,the,O
113,10,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
113,11,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
113,12,where,O
113,13,elderly,B-CASUALTY
113,14,patients,I-CASUALTY
113,15,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
113,16,had,O
113,17,taken,O
113,18,shelter,O
113,19,.,O
114,0,Blue,B-ORG
114,1,Shield,I-ORG
114,2,volunteers,I-ORG
114,3,moved,O
114,4,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
114,5,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
114,6,to,O
114,7,Dili,B-LOCATION
114,8,after,O
114,9,the,O
114,10,torrential,B-DISASTER
114,11,rain,I-DISASTER
114,12,damaged,O
114,13,the,O
114,14,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
114,15,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
114,16,.,O
115,0,A,O
115,1,land,B-DISASTER
115,2,subsidence,I-DISASTER
115,3,in,O
115,4,Zanzibar,B-LOCATION
115,5,ruptured,O
115,6,the,O
115,7,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
115,8,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
115,9,",",O
115,10,and,O
115,11,coastal,B-CASUALTY
115,12,residents,I-CASUALTY
115,13,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
115,14,needed,O
115,15,kitchen,B-AID_RESOURCE
115,16,sets,I-AID_RESOURCE
115,17,.,O
116,0,Water,B-ORG
116,1,Mission,I-ORG
116,2,said,O
116,3,the,O
116,4,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
116,5,Kaito,I-DISASTER
116,6,flooded,O
116,7,the,O
116,8,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
116,9,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
116,10,and,O
116,11,spoiled,O
116,12,emergency,B-AID_RESOURCE
116,13,meals,I-AID_RESOURCE
116,14,.,O
117,0,Rapid,B-ORG
117,1,Relief,I-ORG
117,2,Team,I-ORG
117,3,used,O
117,4,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
117,5,filters,I-AID_RESOURCE
117,6,to,O
117,7,support,O
117,8,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
117,9,patients,I-CASUALTY
117,10,relocated,I-CASUALTY
117,11,after,O
117,12,the,O
117,13,torrential,B-DISASTER
117,14,rain,I-DISASTER
117,15,isolated,O
117,16,Reykjavik,B-LOCATION
117,17,.,O
118,0,Action,B-ORG
118,1,Against,I-ORG
118,2,Hunger,I-ORG
118,3,said,O
118,4,emergency,O
118,5,vehicles,O
118,6,could,O
118,7,not,O
118,8,reach,O
118,9,Port,B-LOCATION
118,10,Vila,I-LOCATION
118,11,after,O
118,12,the,O
118,13,earth,B-DISASTER
118,14,tremor,I-DISASTER
118,15,damaged,O
118,16,the,O
118,17,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
118,18,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
118,19,.,O
119,0,Samaritan,B-ORG
119,1,Aviation,I-ORG
119,2,delivered,O
119,3,thermal,B-AID_RESOURCE
119,4,blankets,I-AID_RESOURCE
119,5,to,O
119,6,Anchorage,B-LOCATION
119,7,after,O
119,8,rainwater,O
119,9,contaminated,O
119,10,the,O
119,11,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
119,12,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
119,13,.,O
120,0,A,O
120,1,snow,B-DISASTER
120,2,squall,I-DISASTER
120,3,in,O
120,4,Thimphu,B-LOCATION
120,5,ruptured,O
120,6,the,O
120,7,radio,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
120,8,repeater,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
120,9,",",O
120,10,and,O
120,11,eight,B-CASUALTY
120,12,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
120,13,treated,I-CASUALTY
120,14,needed,O
120,15,search,B-AID_RESOURCE
120,16,drones,I-AID_RESOURCE
120,17,.,O
121,0,After,O
121,1,the,O
121,2,peat,B-DISASTER
121,3,fire,I-DISASTER
121,4,",",O
121,5,Community,B-ORG
121,6,rescue,I-ORG
121,7,brigade,I-ORG
121,8,opened,O
121,9,a,O
121,10,staging,O
121,11,area,O
121,12,beside,O
121,13,the,O
121,14,radio,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
121,15,repeater,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
121,16,for,O
121,17,five,B-CASUALTY
121,18,workers,I-CASUALTY
121,19,trapped,I-CASUALTY
121,20,.,O
122,0,Local,O
122,1,officials,O
122,2,in,O
122,3,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
122,4,said,O
122,5,the,O
122,6,earth,B-DISASTER
122,7,tremor,I-DISASTER
122,8,forced,O
122,9,market,B-CASUALTY
122,10,vendors,I-CASUALTY
122,11,injured,I-CASUALTY
122,12,from,O
122,13,homes,O
122,14,near,O
122,15,the,O
122,16,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
122,17,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
122,18,.,O
123,0,Near,O
123,1,Port,B-LOCATION
123,2,Vila,I-LOCATION
123,3,",",O
123,4,the,O
123,5,torrential,B-DISASTER
123,6,rain,I-DISASTER
123,7,swept,O
123,8,through,O
123,9,the,O
123,10,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
123,11,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
123,12,and,O
123,13,left,O
123,14,families,B-CASUALTY
123,15,cut,I-CASUALTY
123,16,off,I-CASUALTY
123,17,.,O
124,0,Near,O
124,1,Anchorage,B-LOCATION
124,2,",",O
124,3,the,O
124,4,torrential,B-DISASTER
124,5,rain,I-DISASTER
124,6,swept,O
124,7,through,O
124,8,the,O
124,9,fiber,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
124,10,line,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
124,11,and,O
124,12,left,O
124,13,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
124,14,patients,I-CASUALTY
124,15,relocated,I-CASUALTY
124,16,.,O
125,0,Near,O
125,1,Bergen,B-LOCATION
125,2,",",O
125,3,the,O
125,4,ridge,B-DISASTER
125,5,collapse,I-DISASTER
125,6,swept,O
125,7,through,O
125,8,the,O
125,9,mobile,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
125,10,tower,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
125,11,and,O
125,12,left,O
125,13,market,B-CASUALTY
125,14,vendors,I-CASUALTY
125,15,injured,I-CASUALTY
125,16,.,O
126,0,peat,B-DISASTER
126,1,fire,I-DISASTER
126,2,in,O
126,3,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
126,4,carried,O
126,5,away,O
126,6,the,O
126,7,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
126,8,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
126,9,",",O
126,10,isolating,O
126,11,five,B-CASUALTY
126,12,workers,I-CASUALTY
126,13,trapped,I-CASUALTY
126,14,.,O
127,0,After,O
127,1,the,O
127,2,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
127,3,Vira,I-DISASTER
127,4,",",O
127,5,RescueNet,B-ORG
127,6,opened,O
127,7,a,O
127,8,staging,O
127,9,area,O
127,10,beside,O
127,11,the,O
127,12,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
127,13,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
127,14,for,O
127,15,five,B-CASUALTY
127,16,workers,I-CASUALTY
127,17,trapped,I-CASUALTY
127,18,.,O
128,0,The,O
128,1,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
128,2,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
128,3,in,O
128,4,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
128,5,stayed,O
128,6,closed,O
128,7,while,O
128,8,Crisis,B-ORG
128,9,Response,I-ORG
128,10,Unit,I-ORG
128,11,moved,O
128,12,emergency,B-AID_RESOURCE
128,13,meals,I-AID_RESOURCE
128,14,through,O
128,15,back,O
128,16,roads,O
128,17,.,O
129,0,Telecoms,B-ORG
129,1,Without,I-ORG
129,2,Borders,I-ORG
129,3,reported,O
129,4,market,B-CASUALTY
129,5,vendors,I-CASUALTY
129,6,injured,I-CASUALTY
129,7,when,O
129,8,the,O
129,9,land,B-DISASTER
129,10,subsidence,I-DISASTER
129,11,hit,O
129,12,the,O
129,13,coastal,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
129,14,pier,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
129,15,outside,O
129,16,Bandar,B-LOCATION
129,17,Seri,I-LOCATION
129,18,Begawan,I-LOCATION
129,19,.,O
130,0,MedGlobal,B-ORG
130,1,said,O
130,2,emergency,O
130,3,vehicles,O
130,4,could,O
130,5,not,O
130,6,reach,O
130,7,Dili,B-LOCATION
130,8,after,O
130,9,the,O
130,10,chemical,B-DISASTER
130,11,spill,I-DISASTER
130,12,damaged,O
130,13,the,O
130,14,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
130,15,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
130,16,.,O
131,0,In,O
131,1,Thimphu,B-LOCATION
131,2,",",O
131,3,crews,O
131,4,requested,O
131,5,solar,B-AID_RESOURCE
131,6,lamps,I-AID_RESOURCE
131,7,because,O
131,8,the,O
131,9,rail,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
131,10,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
131,11,failed,O
131,12,during,O
131,13,the,O
131,14,ash,B-DISASTER
131,15,cloud,I-DISASTER
131,16,.,O
132,0,Emergency,B-ORG
132,1,Logistics,I-ORG
132,2,Hub,I-ORG
132,3,moved,O
132,4,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
132,5,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
132,6,to,O
132,7,Rabat,B-LOCATION
132,8,after,O
132,9,the,O
132,10,earth,B-DISASTER
132,11,tremor,I-DISASTER
132,12,shut,O
132,13,the,O
132,14,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
132,15,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
132,16,.,O
133,0,Near,O
133,1,Nuku,B-LOCATION
133,2,',I-LOCATION
133,3,alofa,I-LOCATION
133,4,",",O
133,5,the,O
133,6,glacier,B-DISASTER
133,7,flood,I-DISASTER
133,8,swept,O
133,9,through,O
133,10,the,O
133,11,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
133,12,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
133,13,and,O
133,14,left,O
133,15,elderly,B-CASUALTY
133,16,patients,I-CASUALTY
133,17,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
133,18,.,O
134,0,MedGlobal,B-ORG
134,1,said,O
134,2,emergency,O
134,3,vehicles,O
134,4,could,O
134,5,not,O
134,6,reach,O
134,7,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
134,8,after,O
134,9,the,O
134,10,chemical,B-DISASTER
134,11,spill,I-DISASTER
134,12,damaged,O
134,13,the,O
134,14,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
134,15,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
134,16,.,O
135,0,A,O
135,1,torrential,B-DISASTER
135,2,rain,I-DISASTER
135,3,closed,O
135,4,the,O
135,5,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
135,6,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
135,7,to,O
135,8,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
135,9,",",O
135,10,stranding,O
135,11,Crisis,B-ORG
135,12,Response,I-ORG
135,13,Unit,I-ORG
135,14,with,O
135,15,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
135,16,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
135,17,.,O
136,0,storm,B-DISASTER
136,1,cells,I-DISASTER
136,2,froze,O
136,3,the,O
136,4,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
136,5,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
136,6,near,O
136,7,Cebu,B-LOCATION
136,8,",",O
136,9,delaying,O
136,10,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
136,11,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
136,12,from,O
136,13,Telecoms,B-ORG
136,14,Without,I-ORG
136,15,Borders,I-ORG
136,16,.,O
137,0,Search,O
137,1,crews,O
137,2,found,O
137,3,coastal,B-CASUALTY
137,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
137,5,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
137,6,under,O
137,7,the,O
137,8,collapsed,O
137,9,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
137,10,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
137,11,in,O
137,12,Cebu,B-LOCATION
137,13,.,O
138,0,dam,B-DISASTER
138,1,burst,I-DISASTER
138,2,froze,O
138,3,the,O
138,4,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
138,5,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
138,6,near,O
138,7,Dakar,B-LOCATION
138,8,",",O
138,9,delaying,O
138,10,diesel,B-AID_RESOURCE
138,11,drums,I-AID_RESOURCE
138,12,from,O
138,13,Rapid,B-ORG
138,14,Relief,I-ORG
138,15,Team,I-ORG
138,16,.,O
139,0,After,O
139,1,the,O
139,2,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
139,3,Vira,I-DISASTER
139,4,",",O
139,5,the,O
139,6,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
139,7,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
139,8,asked,O
139,9,Islamic,B-ORG
139,10,Relief,I-ORG
139,11,for,O
139,12,tarpaulin,B-AID_RESOURCE
139,13,rolls,I-AID_RESOURCE
139,14,.,O
140,0,Search,O
140,1,crews,O
140,2,found,O
140,3,17,B-CASUALTY
140,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
140,5,injured,I-CASUALTY
140,6,under,O
140,7,the,O
140,8,collapsed,O
140,9,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
140,10,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
140,11,in,O
140,12,Medellin,B-LOCATION
140,13,.,O
141,0,The,O
141,1,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
141,2,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
141,3,in,O
141,4,Bamako,B-LOCATION
141,5,stayed,O
141,6,closed,O
141,7,while,O
141,8,Islamic,B-ORG
141,9,Relief,I-ORG
141,10,moved,O
141,11,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
141,12,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
141,13,through,O
141,14,back,O
141,15,roads,O
141,16,.,O
142,0,Before,O
142,1,dawn,O
142,2,",",O
142,3,snow,B-DISASTER
142,4,squall,I-DISASTER
142,5,cut,O
142,6,power,O
142,7,in,O
142,8,Cebu,B-LOCATION
142,9,while,O
142,10,Blue,B-ORG
142,11,Shield,I-ORG
142,12,volunteers,I-ORG
142,13,requested,O
142,14,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
142,15,gloves,I-AID_RESOURCE
142,16,.,O
143,0,Telecoms,B-ORG
143,1,Without,I-ORG
143,2,Borders,I-ORG
143,3,mapped,O
143,4,supply,O
143,5,gaps,O
143,6,near,O
143,7,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
143,8,",",O
143,9,where,O
143,10,four,B-CASUALTY
143,11,passengers,I-CASUALTY
143,12,missing,I-CASUALTY
143,13,were,O
143,14,stranded,O
143,15,by,O
143,16,volcanic,B-DISASTER
143,17,eruption,I-DISASTER
143,18,.,O
144,0,Crisis,B-ORG
144,1,Response,I-ORG
144,2,Unit,I-ORG
144,3,warned,O
144,4,that,O
144,5,infant,B-AID_RESOURCE
144,6,milk,I-AID_RESOURCE
144,7,would,O
144,8,run,O
144,9,out,O
144,10,in,O
144,11,Kigali,B-LOCATION
144,12,if,O
144,13,the,O
144,14,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
144,15,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
144,16,remained,O
144,17,broken,O
144,18,.,O
145,0,RescueNet,B-ORG
145,1,warned,O
145,2,that,O
145,3,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
145,4,were,O
145,5,running,O
145,6,low,O
145,7,in,O
145,8,Dili,B-LOCATION
145,9,after,O
145,10,the,O
145,11,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
145,12,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
145,13,overflowed,O
145,14,.,O
146,0,Local,B-ORG
146,1,Red,I-ORG
146,2,Crescent,I-ORG
146,3,warned,O
146,4,that,O
146,5,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
146,6,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
146,7,would,O
146,8,run,O
146,9,out,O
146,10,in,O
146,11,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
146,12,if,O
146,13,the,O
146,14,rail,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
146,15,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
146,16,remained,O
146,17,broken,O
146,18,.,O
147,0,three,B-CASUALTY
147,1,drivers,I-CASUALTY
147,2,rescued,I-CASUALTY
147,3,were,O
147,4,found,O
147,5,near,O
147,6,Rabat,B-LOCATION
147,7,after,O
147,8,the,O
147,9,torrential,B-DISASTER
147,10,rain,I-DISASTER
147,11,swept,O
147,12,across,O
147,13,the,O
147,14,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
147,15,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
147,16,.,O
148,0,The,O
148,1,heatwave,B-DISASTER
148,2,cracked,O
148,3,the,O
148,4,rail,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
148,5,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
148,6,outside,O
148,7,Bukhara,B-LOCATION
148,8,",",O
148,9,so,O
148,10,Rapid,B-ORG
148,11,Relief,I-ORG
148,12,Team,I-ORG
148,13,sent,O
148,14,emergency,B-AID_RESOURCE
148,15,meals,I-AID_RESOURCE
148,16,.,O
149,0,Search,O
149,1,crews,O
149,2,found,O
149,3,coastal,B-CASUALTY
149,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
149,5,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
149,6,under,O
149,7,the,O
149,8,collapsed,O
149,9,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
149,10,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
149,11,in,O
149,12,La,B-LOCATION
149,13,Paz,I-LOCATION
149,14,.,O
150,0,Search,O
150,1,crews,O
150,2,found,O
150,3,17,B-CASUALTY
150,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
150,5,injured,I-CASUALTY
150,6,under,O
150,7,the,O
150,8,collapsed,O
150,9,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
150,10,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
150,11,in,O
150,12,Luanda,B-LOCATION
150,13,.,O
151,0,Near,O
151,1,Suva,B-LOCATION
151,2,",",O
151,3,the,O
151,4,river,B-DISASTER
151,5,overflow,I-DISASTER
151,6,swept,O
151,7,through,O
151,8,the,O
151,9,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
151,10,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
151,11,and,O
151,12,left,O
151,13,five,B-CASUALTY
151,14,workers,I-CASUALTY
151,15,trapped,I-CASUALTY
151,16,.,O
152,0,A,O
152,1,torrential,B-DISASTER
152,2,rain,I-DISASTER
152,3,in,O
152,4,Rabat,B-LOCATION
152,5,ruptured,O
152,6,the,O
152,7,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
152,8,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
152,9,",",O
152,10,and,O
152,11,five,B-CASUALTY
152,12,workers,I-CASUALTY
152,13,trapped,I-CASUALTY
152,14,needed,O
152,15,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
152,16,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
152,17,.,O
153,0,Relief,B-ORG
153,1,International,I-ORG
153,2,warned,O
153,3,that,O
153,4,trauma,B-AID_RESOURCE
153,5,bandages,I-AID_RESOURCE
153,6,were,O
153,7,running,O
153,8,low,O
153,9,in,O
153,10,Rabat,B-LOCATION
153,11,after,O
153,12,the,O
153,13,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
153,14,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
153,15,overflowed,O
153,16,.,O
154,0,In,O
154,1,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
154,2,",",O
154,3,crews,O
154,4,requested,O
154,5,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
154,6,bladders,I-AID_RESOURCE
154,7,because,O
154,8,the,O
154,9,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
154,10,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
154,11,failed,O
154,12,during,O
154,13,the,O
154,14,urban,B-DISASTER
154,15,flash,I-DISASTER
154,16,flood,I-DISASTER
154,17,.,O
155,0,A,O
155,1,peat,B-DISASTER
155,2,fire,I-DISASTER
155,3,above,O
155,4,Medellin,B-LOCATION
155,5,blocked,O
155,6,the,O
155,7,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
155,8,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
155,9,",",O
155,10,leaving,O
155,11,elderly,B-CASUALTY
155,12,patients,I-CASUALTY
155,13,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
155,14,.,O
156,0,A,O
156,1,volcanic,B-DISASTER
156,2,eruption,I-DISASTER
156,3,above,O
156,4,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
156,5,blocked,O
156,6,the,O
156,7,fiber,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
156,8,line,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
156,9,",",O
156,10,leaving,O
156,11,families,B-CASUALTY
156,12,cut,I-CASUALTY
156,13,off,I-CASUALTY
156,14,.,O
157,0,RescueNet,B-ORG
157,1,warned,O
157,2,that,O
157,3,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
157,4,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
157,5,would,O
157,6,run,O
157,7,out,O
157,8,in,O
157,9,Tbilisi,B-LOCATION
157,10,if,O
157,11,the,O
157,12,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
157,13,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
157,14,remained,O
157,15,broken,O
157,16,.,O
158,0,In,O
158,1,Bergen,B-LOCATION
158,2,",",O
158,3,Action,B-ORG
158,4,Against,I-ORG
158,5,Hunger,I-ORG
158,6,opened,O
158,7,a,O
158,8,field,O
158,9,post,O
158,10,for,O
158,11,three,B-CASUALTY
158,12,drivers,I-CASUALTY
158,13,rescued,I-CASUALTY
158,14,after,O
158,15,heatwave,B-DISASTER
158,16,.,O
159,0,A,O
159,1,damaged,O
159,2,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
159,3,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
159,4,slowed,O
159,5,evacuation,O
159,6,from,O
159,7,Bandar,B-LOCATION
159,8,Seri,I-LOCATION
159,9,Begawan,I-LOCATION
159,10,;,O
159,11,Action,B-ORG
159,12,Against,I-ORG
159,13,Hunger,I-ORG
159,14,asked,O
159,15,for,O
159,16,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
159,17,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
159,18,.,O
160,0,Emergency,B-ORG
160,1,Logistics,I-ORG
160,2,Hub,I-ORG
160,3,said,O
160,4,the,O
160,5,torrential,B-DISASTER
160,6,rain,I-DISASTER
160,7,flooded,O
160,8,the,O
160,9,radio,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
160,10,repeater,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
160,11,and,O
160,12,spoiled,O
160,13,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
160,14,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
160,15,.,O
161,0,Search,O
161,1,crews,O
161,2,found,O
161,3,four,B-CASUALTY
161,4,passengers,I-CASUALTY
161,5,missing,I-CASUALTY
161,6,under,O
161,7,the,O
161,8,collapsed,O
161,9,mobile,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
161,10,tower,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
161,11,in,O
161,12,Bukhara,B-LOCATION
161,13,.,O
162,0,Action,B-ORG
162,1,Against,I-ORG
162,2,Hunger,I-ORG
162,3,treated,O
162,4,many,B-CASUALTY
162,5,households,I-CASUALTY
162,6,displaced,I-CASUALTY
162,7,after,O
162,8,torrential,B-DISASTER
162,9,rain,I-DISASTER
162,10,damaged,O
162,11,the,O
162,12,mobile,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
162,13,tower,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
162,14,in,O
162,15,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
162,16,.,O
163,0,The,O
163,1,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
163,2,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
163,3,in,O
163,4,Suva,B-LOCATION
163,5,stayed,O
163,6,closed,O
163,7,while,O
163,8,Rapid,B-ORG
163,9,Relief,I-ORG
163,10,Team,I-ORG
163,11,moved,O
163,12,trauma,B-AID_RESOURCE
163,13,bandages,I-AID_RESOURCE
163,14,through,O
163,15,back,O
163,16,roads,O
163,17,.,O
164,0,Water,B-ORG
164,1,Mission,I-ORG
164,2,treated,O
164,3,four,B-CASUALTY
164,4,passengers,I-CASUALTY
164,5,missing,I-CASUALTY
164,6,after,O
164,7,peat,B-DISASTER
164,8,fire,I-DISASTER
164,9,damaged,O
164,10,the,O
164,11,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
164,12,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
164,13,in,O
164,14,La,B-LOCATION
164,15,Paz,I-LOCATION
164,16,.,O
165,0,A,O
165,1,urban,B-DISASTER
165,2,flash,I-DISASTER
165,3,flood,I-DISASTER
165,4,above,O
165,5,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
165,6,blocked,O
165,7,the,O
165,8,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
165,9,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
165,10,",",O
165,11,leaving,O
165,12,families,B-CASUALTY
165,13,cut,I-CASUALTY
165,14,off,I-CASUALTY
165,15,.,O
166,0,MedGlobal,B-ORG
166,1,moved,O
166,2,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
166,3,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
166,4,to,O
166,5,Bamako,B-LOCATION
166,6,after,O
166,7,the,O
166,8,glacier,B-DISASTER
166,9,flood,I-DISASTER
166,10,damaged,O
166,11,the,O
166,12,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
166,13,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
166,14,.,O
167,0,glacier,B-DISASTER
167,1,flood,I-DISASTER
167,2,pushed,O
167,3,water,O
167,4,into,O
167,5,Mombasa,B-LOCATION
167,6,",",O
167,7,knocking,O
167,8,out,O
167,9,the,O
167,10,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
167,11,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
167,12,.,O
168,0,The,O
168,1,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
168,2,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
168,3,in,O
168,4,Tbilisi,B-LOCATION
168,5,stayed,O
168,6,closed,O
168,7,while,O
168,8,Rapid,B-ORG
168,9,Relief,I-ORG
168,10,Team,I-ORG
168,11,moved,O
168,12,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
168,13,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
168,14,through,O
168,15,back,O
168,16,roads,O
168,17,.,O
169,0,In,O
169,1,Suva,B-LOCATION
169,2,",",O
169,3,Emergency,B-ORG
169,4,Logistics,I-ORG
169,5,Hub,I-ORG
169,6,reported,O
169,7,17,B-CASUALTY
169,8,residents,I-CASUALTY
169,9,injured,I-CASUALTY
169,10,when,O
169,11,the,O
169,12,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
169,13,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
169,14,failed,O
169,15,.,O
170,0,In,O
170,1,Suva,B-LOCATION
170,2,",",O
170,3,crews,O
170,4,requested,O
170,5,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
170,6,because,O
170,7,the,O
170,8,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
170,9,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
170,10,failed,O
170,11,during,O
170,12,the,O
170,13,heatwave,B-DISASTER
170,14,.,O
171,0,A,O
171,1,earth,B-DISASTER
171,2,tremor,I-DISASTER
171,3,above,O
171,4,La,B-LOCATION
171,5,Paz,I-LOCATION
171,6,blocked,O
171,7,the,O
171,8,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
171,9,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
171,10,",",O
171,11,leaving,O
171,12,four,B-CASUALTY
171,13,passengers,I-CASUALTY
171,14,missing,I-CASUALTY
171,15,.,O
172,0,Rapid,B-ORG
172,1,Relief,I-ORG
172,2,Team,I-ORG
172,3,warned,O
172,4,that,O
172,5,thermal,B-AID_RESOURCE
172,6,blankets,I-AID_RESOURCE
172,7,were,O
172,8,running,O
172,9,low,O
172,10,in,O
172,11,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
172,12,after,O
172,13,the,O
172,14,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
172,15,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
172,16,overflowed,O
172,17,.,O
173,0,Near,O
173,1,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
173,2,",",O
173,3,the,O
173,4,urban,B-DISASTER
173,5,flash,I-DISASTER
173,6,flood,I-DISASTER
173,7,blocked,O
173,8,the,O
173,9,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
173,10,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
173,11,and,O
173,12,left,O
173,13,six,B-CASUALTY
173,14,volunteers,I-CASUALTY
173,15,hurt,I-CASUALTY
173,16,.,O
174,0,Search,O
174,1,crews,O
174,2,found,O
174,3,eight,B-CASUALTY
174,4,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
174,5,treated,I-CASUALTY
174,6,under,O
174,7,the,O
174,8,collapsed,O
174,9,rail,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
174,10,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
174,11,in,O
174,12,Anchorage,B-LOCATION
174,13,.,O
175,0,Emergency,B-ORG
175,1,Logistics,I-ORG
175,2,Hub,I-ORG
175,3,moved,O
175,4,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
175,5,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
175,6,to,O
175,7,Bandar,B-LOCATION
175,8,Seri,I-LOCATION
175,9,Begawan,I-LOCATION
175,10,after,O
175,11,the,O
175,12,snow,B-DISASTER
175,13,squall,I-DISASTER
175,14,damaged,O
175,15,the,O
175,16,rail,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
175,17,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
175,18,.,O
176,0,A,O
176,1,monsoon,B-DISASTER
176,2,flood,I-DISASTER
176,3,above,O
176,4,Tbilisi,B-LOCATION
176,5,blocked,O
176,6,the,O
176,7,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
176,8,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
176,9,",",O
176,10,leaving,O
176,11,four,B-CASUALTY
176,12,passengers,I-CASUALTY
176,13,missing,I-CASUALTY
176,14,.,O
177,0,Search,O
177,1,crews,O
177,2,found,O
177,3,three,B-CASUALTY
177,4,drivers,I-CASUALTY
177,5,rescued,I-CASUALTY
177,6,under,O
177,7,the,O
177,8,collapsed,O
177,9,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
177,10,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
177,11,in,O
177,12,Luanda,B-LOCATION
177,13,.,O
178,0,Community,B-ORG
178,1,rescue,I-ORG
178,2,brigade,I-ORG
178,3,mapped,O
178,4,supply,O
178,5,gaps,O
178,6,near,O
178,7,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
178,8,",",O
178,9,where,O
178,10,elderly,B-CASUALTY
178,11,patients,I-CASUALTY
178,12,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
178,13,were,O
178,14,stranded,O
178,15,by,O
178,16,ash,B-DISASTER
178,17,cloud,I-DISASTER
178,18,.,O
179,0,A,O
179,1,torrential,B-DISASTER
179,2,rain,I-DISASTER
179,3,in,O
179,4,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
179,5,ruptured,O
179,6,the,O
179,7,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
179,8,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
179,9,",",O
179,10,and,O
179,11,coastal,B-CASUALTY
179,12,residents,I-CASUALTY
179,13,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
179,14,needed,O
179,15,emergency,B-AID_RESOURCE
179,16,meals,I-AID_RESOURCE
179,17,.,O
180,0,Water,B-ORG
180,1,Mission,I-ORG
180,2,warned,O
180,3,that,O
180,4,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
180,5,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
180,6,would,O
180,7,run,O
180,8,out,O
180,9,in,O
180,10,Asmara,B-LOCATION
180,11,if,O
180,12,the,O
180,13,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
180,14,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
180,15,remained,O
180,16,broken,O
180,17,.,O
181,0,Food,B-ORG
181,1,for,I-ORG
181,2,the,I-ORG
181,3,Hungry,I-ORG
181,4,reported,O
181,5,schoolchildren,B-CASUALTY
181,6,stranded,I-CASUALTY
181,7,when,O
181,8,the,O
181,9,earth,B-DISASTER
181,10,tremor,I-DISASTER
181,11,hit,O
181,12,the,O
181,13,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
181,14,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
181,15,outside,O
181,16,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
181,17,.,O
182,0,Search,O
182,1,crews,O
182,2,found,O
182,3,140,B-CASUALTY
182,4,people,I-CASUALTY
182,5,displaced,I-CASUALTY
182,6,under,O
182,7,the,O
182,8,collapsed,O
182,9,mobile,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
182,10,tower,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
182,11,in,O
182,12,Dakar,B-LOCATION
182,13,.,O
183,0,RescueNet,B-ORG
183,1,warned,O
183,2,that,O
183,3,infant,B-AID_RESOURCE
183,4,milk,I-AID_RESOURCE
183,5,would,O
183,6,run,O
183,7,out,O
183,8,in,O
183,9,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
183,10,if,O
183,11,the,O
183,12,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
183,13,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
183,14,remained,O
183,15,broken,O
183,16,.,O
184,0,Aviation,B-ORG
184,1,Sans,I-ORG
184,2,Frontieres,I-ORG
184,3,said,O
184,4,emergency,O
184,5,vehicles,O
184,6,could,O
184,7,not,O
184,8,reach,O
184,9,Kampala,B-LOCATION
184,10,after,O
184,11,the,O
184,12,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
184,13,Vira,I-DISASTER
184,14,damaged,O
184,15,the,O
184,16,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
184,17,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
184,18,.,O
185,0,Emergency,B-ORG
185,1,Logistics,I-ORG
185,2,Hub,I-ORG
185,3,treated,O
185,4,17,B-CASUALTY
185,5,residents,I-CASUALTY
185,6,injured,I-CASUALTY
185,7,after,O
185,8,ice,B-DISASTER
185,9,jam,I-DISASTER
185,10,damaged,O
185,11,the,O
185,12,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
185,13,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
185,14,in,O
185,15,Port,B-LOCATION
185,16,Vila,I-LOCATION
185,17,.,O
186,0,CARE,B-ORG
186,1,teams,I-ORG
186,2,moved,O
186,3,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
186,4,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
186,5,to,O
186,6,Bamako,B-LOCATION
186,7,after,O
186,8,the,O
186,9,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
186,10,Vira,I-DISASTER
186,11,damaged,O
186,12,the,O
186,13,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
186,14,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
186,15,.,O
187,0,Near,O
187,1,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
187,2,",",O
187,3,the,O
187,4,cold,B-DISASTER
187,5,snap,I-DISASTER
187,6,blocked,O
187,7,the,O
187,8,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
187,9,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
187,10,and,O
187,11,left,O
187,12,many,B-CASUALTY
187,13,households,I-CASUALTY
187,14,displaced,I-CASUALTY
187,15,.,O
188,0,The,O
188,1,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
188,2,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
188,3,in,O
188,4,Kigali,B-LOCATION
188,5,stayed,O
188,6,closed,O
188,7,while,O
188,8,Community,B-ORG
188,9,rescue,I-ORG
188,10,brigade,I-ORG
188,11,moved,O
188,12,search,B-AID_RESOURCE
188,13,drones,I-AID_RESOURCE
188,14,through,O
188,15,back,O
188,16,roads,O
188,17,.,O
189,0,Samaritan,B-ORG
189,1,Aviation,I-ORG
189,2,moved,O
189,3,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
189,4,gloves,I-AID_RESOURCE
189,5,to,O
189,6,Bergen,B-LOCATION
189,7,after,O
189,8,the,O
189,9,glacier,B-DISASTER
189,10,flood,I-DISASTER
189,11,shut,O
189,12,the,O
189,13,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
189,14,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
189,15,.,O
190,0,In,O
190,1,Dakar,B-LOCATION
190,2,",",O
190,3,Health,B-ORG
190,4,Bridge,I-ORG
190,5,reported,O
190,6,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
190,7,patients,I-CASUALTY
190,8,relocated,I-CASUALTY
190,9,when,O
190,10,the,O
190,11,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
190,12,generator,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
190,13,failed,O
190,14,.,O
191,0,In,O
191,1,Asmara,B-LOCATION
191,2,",",O
191,3,Emergency,B-ORG
191,4,Logistics,I-ORG
191,5,Hub,I-ORG
191,6,opened,O
191,7,a,O
191,8,field,O
191,9,post,O
191,10,for,O
191,11,five,B-CASUALTY
191,12,workers,I-CASUALTY
191,13,trapped,I-CASUALTY
191,14,after,O
191,15,ice,B-DISASTER
191,16,jam,I-DISASTER
191,17,.,O
192,0,After,O
192,1,the,O
192,2,urban,B-DISASTER
192,3,flash,I-DISASTER
192,4,flood,I-DISASTER
192,5,",",O
192,6,Crisis,B-ORG
192,7,Response,I-ORG
192,8,Unit,I-ORG
192,9,opened,O
192,10,a,O
192,11,staging,O
192,12,area,O
192,13,beside,O
192,14,the,O
192,15,fiber,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
192,16,line,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
192,17,for,O
192,18,five,B-CASUALTY
192,19,workers,I-CASUALTY
192,20,trapped,I-CASUALTY
192,21,.,O
193,0,The,O
193,1,ash,B-DISASTER
193,2,cloud,I-DISASTER
193,3,cracked,O
193,4,the,O
193,5,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
193,6,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
193,7,outside,O
193,8,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
193,9,",",O
193,10,so,O
193,11,Rapid,B-ORG
193,12,Relief,I-ORG
193,13,Team,I-ORG
193,14,sent,O
193,15,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
193,16,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
193,17,.,O
194,0,In,O
194,1,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
194,2,",",O
194,3,a,O
194,4,land,B-DISASTER
194,5,subsidence,I-DISASTER
194,6,buried,O
194,7,the,O
194,8,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
194,9,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
194,10,where,O
194,11,elderly,B-CASUALTY
194,12,patients,I-CASUALTY
194,13,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
194,14,had,O
194,15,taken,O
194,16,shelter,O
194,17,.,O
195,0,torrential,B-DISASTER
195,1,rain,I-DISASTER
195,2,froze,O
195,3,the,O
195,4,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
195,5,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
195,6,near,O
195,7,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
195,8,",",O
195,9,delaying,O
195,10,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
195,11,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
195,12,from,O
195,13,Health,B-ORG
195,14,Bridge,I-ORG
195,15,.,O
196,0,In,O
196,1,Dili,B-LOCATION
196,2,",",O
196,3,crews,O
196,4,requested,O
196,5,trauma,B-AID_RESOURCE
196,6,bandages,I-AID_RESOURCE
196,7,because,O
196,8,the,O
196,9,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
196,10,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
196,11,failed,O
196,12,during,O
196,13,the,O
196,14,ice,B-DISASTER
196,15,jam,I-DISASTER
196,16,.,O
197,0,Food,B-ORG
197,1,for,I-ORG
197,2,the,I-ORG
197,3,Hungry,I-ORG
197,4,said,O
197,5,the,O
197,6,peat,B-DISASTER
197,7,fire,I-DISASTER
197,8,flooded,O
197,9,the,O
197,10,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
197,11,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
197,12,and,O
197,13,spoiled,O
197,14,tarpaulin,B-AID_RESOURCE
197,15,rolls,I-AID_RESOURCE
197,16,.,O
198,0,In,O
198,1,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
198,2,",",O
198,3,a,O
198,4,snow,B-DISASTER
198,5,squall,I-DISASTER
198,6,buried,O
198,7,the,O
198,8,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
198,9,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
198,10,where,O
198,11,port,B-CASUALTY
198,12,staff,I-CASUALTY
198,13,missing,I-CASUALTY
198,14,had,O
198,15,taken,O
198,16,shelter,O
198,17,.,O
199,0,The,O
199,1,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
199,2,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
199,3,in,O
199,4,Tbilisi,B-LOCATION
199,5,stayed,O
199,6,closed,O
199,7,while,O
199,8,Islamic,B-ORG
199,9,Relief,I-ORG
199,10,moved,O
199,11,thermal,B-AID_RESOURCE
199,12,blankets,I-AID_RESOURCE
199,13,through,O
199,14,back,O
199,15,roads,O
199,16,.,O
200,0,Humanity,B-ORG
200,1,First,I-ORG
200,2,said,O
200,3,the,O
200,4,ice,B-DISASTER
200,5,jam,I-DISASTER
200,6,flooded,O
200,7,the,O
200,8,mobile,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
200,9,tower,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
200,10,and,O
200,11,spoiled,O
200,12,diesel,B-AID_RESOURCE
200,13,drums,I-AID_RESOURCE
200,14,.,O
201,0,After,O
201,1,the,O
201,2,ice,B-DISASTER
201,3,jam,I-DISASTER
201,4,",",O
201,5,the,O
201,6,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
201,7,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
201,8,asked,O
201,9,Community,B-ORG
201,10,rescue,I-ORG
201,11,brigade,I-ORG
201,12,for,O
201,13,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
201,14,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
201,15,.,O
202,0,In,O
202,1,Luanda,B-LOCATION
202,2,",",O
202,3,Blue,B-ORG
202,4,Shield,I-ORG
202,5,volunteers,I-ORG
202,6,reported,O
202,7,17,B-CASUALTY
202,8,residents,I-CASUALTY
202,9,injured,I-CASUALTY
202,10,when,O
202,11,the,O
202,12,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
202,13,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
202,14,failed,O
202,15,.,O
203,0,After,O
203,1,the,O
203,2,monsoon,B-DISASTER
203,3,flood,I-DISASTER
203,4,",",O
203,5,the,O
203,6,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
203,7,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
203,8,asked,O
203,9,Samaritan,B-ORG
203,10,Aviation,I-ORG
203,11,for,O
203,12,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
203,13,.,O
204,0,A,O
204,1,damaged,O
204,2,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
204,3,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
204,4,slowed,O
204,5,evacuation,O
204,6,from,O
204,7,Rabat,B-LOCATION
204,8,;,O
204,9,Health,B-ORG
204,10,Bridge,I-ORG
204,11,asked,O
204,12,for,O
204,13,search,B-AID_RESOURCE
204,14,drones,I-AID_RESOURCE
204,15,.,O
205,0,In,O
205,1,Thimphu,B-LOCATION
205,2,",",O
205,3,CARE,B-ORG
205,4,teams,I-ORG
205,5,reported,O
205,6,many,B-CASUALTY
205,7,households,I-CASUALTY
205,8,displaced,I-CASUALTY
205,9,when,O
205,10,the,O
205,11,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
205,12,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
205,13,failed,O
205,14,.,O
206,0,In,O
206,1,Valparaiso,B-LOCATION
206,2,",",O
206,3,Emergency,B-ORG
206,4,Logistics,I-ORG
206,5,Hub,I-ORG
206,6,reported,O
206,7,140,B-CASUALTY
206,8,people,I-CASUALTY
206,9,displaced,I-CASUALTY
206,10,when,O
206,11,the,O
206,12,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
206,13,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
206,14,failed,O
206,15,.,O
207,0,Samaritan,B-ORG
207,1,Aviation,I-ORG
207,2,reported,O
207,3,four,B-CASUALTY
207,4,passengers,I-CASUALTY
207,5,missing,I-CASUALTY
207,6,when,O
207,7,the,O
207,8,earth,B-DISASTER
207,9,tremor,I-DISASTER
207,10,hit,O
207,11,the,O
207,12,radio,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
207,13,repeater,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
207,14,outside,O
207,15,Bergen,B-LOCATION
207,16,.,O
208,0,Local,O
208,1,officials,O
208,2,in,O
208,3,Bandar,B-LOCATION
208,4,Seri,I-LOCATION
208,5,Begawan,I-LOCATION
208,6,said,O
208,7,the,O
208,8,heatwave,B-DISASTER
208,9,forced,O
208,10,many,B-CASUALTY
208,11,households,I-CASUALTY
208,12,displaced,I-CASUALTY
208,13,from,O
208,14,homes,O
208,15,near,O
208,16,the,O
208,17,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
208,18,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
208,19,.,O
209,0,Community,B-ORG
209,1,rescue,I-ORG
209,2,brigade,I-ORG
209,3,reported,O
209,4,coastal,B-CASUALTY
209,5,residents,I-CASUALTY
209,6,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
209,7,when,O
209,8,the,O
209,9,ash,B-DISASTER
209,10,cloud,I-DISASTER
209,11,hit,O
209,12,the,O
209,13,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
209,14,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
209,15,outside,O
209,16,Kigali,B-LOCATION
209,17,.,O
210,0,MedGlobal,B-ORG
210,1,said,O
210,2,the,O
210,3,glacier,B-DISASTER
210,4,flood,I-DISASTER
210,5,flooded,O
210,6,the,O
210,7,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
210,8,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
210,9,and,O
210,10,spoiled,O
210,11,emergency,B-AID_RESOURCE
210,12,meals,I-AID_RESOURCE
210,13,.,O
211,0,MedGlobal,B-ORG
211,1,warned,O
211,2,that,O
211,3,satellite,B-AID_RESOURCE
211,4,terminals,I-AID_RESOURCE
211,5,were,O
211,6,running,O
211,7,low,O
211,8,in,O
211,9,Port,B-LOCATION
211,10,Vila,I-LOCATION
211,11,after,O
211,12,the,O
211,13,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
211,14,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
211,15,overflowed,O
211,16,.,O
212,0,heatwave,B-DISASTER
212,1,in,O
212,2,Nuku,B-LOCATION
212,3,',I-LOCATION
212,4,alofa,I-LOCATION
212,5,carried,O
212,6,away,O
212,7,the,O
212,8,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
212,9,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
212,10,",",O
212,11,isolating,O
212,12,many,B-CASUALTY
212,13,households,I-CASUALTY
212,14,displaced,I-CASUALTY
212,15,.,O
213,0,ice,B-DISASTER
213,1,jam,I-DISASTER
213,2,pushed,O
213,3,water,O
213,4,into,O
213,5,Luanda,B-LOCATION
213,6,",",O
213,7,knocking,O
213,8,out,O
213,9,the,O
213,10,fiber,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
213,11,line,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
213,12,.,O
214,0,Rapid,B-ORG
214,1,Relief,I-ORG
214,2,Team,I-ORG
214,3,moved,O
214,4,kitchen,B-AID_RESOURCE
214,5,sets,I-AID_RESOURCE
214,6,to,O
214,7,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
214,8,after,O
214,9,the,O
214,10,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
214,11,Kaito,I-DISASTER
214,12,shut,O
214,13,the,O
214,14,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
214,15,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
214,16,.,O
215,0,Health,B-ORG
215,1,Bridge,I-ORG
215,2,said,O
215,3,the,O
215,4,land,B-DISASTER
215,5,subsidence,I-DISASTER
215,6,flooded,O
215,7,the,O
215,8,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
215,9,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
215,10,and,O
215,11,spoiled,O
215,12,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
215,13,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
215,14,.,O
216,0,RescueNet,B-ORG
216,1,said,O
216,2,the,O
216,3,storm,B-DISASTER
216,4,cells,I-DISASTER
216,5,flooded,O
216,6,the,O
216,7,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
216,8,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
216,9,and,O
216,10,spoiled,O
216,11,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
216,12,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
216,13,.,O
217,0,storm,B-DISASTER
217,1,cells,I-DISASTER
217,2,in,O
217,3,Rabat,B-LOCATION
217,4,carried,O
217,5,away,O
217,6,the,O
217,7,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
217,8,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
217,9,",",O
217,10,isolating,O
217,11,many,B-CASUALTY
217,12,households,I-CASUALTY
217,13,displaced,I-CASUALTY
217,14,.,O
218,0,In,O
218,1,Manta,B-LOCATION
218,2,",",O
218,3,a,O
218,4,volcanic,B-DISASTER
218,5,eruption,I-DISASTER
218,6,buried,O
218,7,the,O
218,8,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
218,9,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
218,10,where,O
218,11,five,B-CASUALTY
218,12,workers,I-CASUALTY
218,13,trapped,I-CASUALTY
218,14,had,O
218,15,taken,O
218,16,shelter,O
218,17,.,O
219,0,A,O
219,1,torrential,B-DISASTER
219,2,rain,I-DISASTER
219,3,above,O
219,4,La,B-LOCATION
219,5,Paz,I-LOCATION
219,6,blocked,O
219,7,the,O
219,8,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
219,9,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
219,10,",",O
219,11,leaving,O
219,12,eight,B-CASUALTY
219,13,firefighters,I-CASUALTY
219,14,treated,I-CASUALTY
219,15,.,O
220,0,In,O
220,1,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
220,2,",",O
220,3,crews,O
220,4,requested,O
220,5,infant,B-AID_RESOURCE
220,6,milk,I-AID_RESOURCE
220,7,because,O
220,8,the,O
220,9,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
220,10,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
220,11,failed,O
220,12,during,O
220,13,the,O
220,14,urban,B-DISASTER
220,15,flash,I-DISASTER
220,16,flood,I-DISASTER
220,17,.,O
221,0,Community,B-ORG
221,1,rescue,I-ORG
221,2,brigade,I-ORG
221,3,delivered,O
221,4,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
221,5,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
221,6,to,O
221,7,Luanda,B-LOCATION
221,8,after,O
221,9,rainwater,O
221,10,contaminated,O
221,11,the,O
221,12,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
221,13,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
221,14,.,O
222,0,Local,O
222,1,officials,O
222,2,in,O
222,3,Port,B-LOCATION
222,4,Vila,I-LOCATION
222,5,said,O
222,6,the,O
222,7,chemical,B-DISASTER
222,8,spill,I-DISASTER
222,9,forced,O
222,10,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
222,11,patients,I-CASUALTY
222,12,relocated,I-CASUALTY
222,13,from,O
222,14,homes,O
222,15,near,O
222,16,the,O
222,17,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
222,18,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
222,19,.,O
223,0,A,O
223,1,earth,B-DISASTER
223,2,tremor,I-DISASTER
223,3,in,O
223,4,Luanda,B-LOCATION
223,5,ruptured,O
223,6,the,O
223,7,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
223,8,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
223,9,",",O
223,10,and,O
223,11,pregnant,B-CASUALTY
223,12,patients,I-CASUALTY
223,13,relocated,I-CASUALTY
223,14,needed,O
223,15,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
223,16,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
223,17,.,O
224,0,CARE,B-ORG
224,1,teams,I-ORG
224,2,moved,O
224,3,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
224,4,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
224,5,to,O
224,6,Kathmandu,B-LOCATION
224,7,after,O
224,8,the,O
224,9,ash,B-DISASTER
224,10,cloud,I-DISASTER
224,11,shut,O
224,12,the,O
224,13,radio,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
224,14,repeater,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
224,15,.,O
225,0,In,O
225,1,Zanzibar,B-LOCATION
225,2,",",O
225,3,a,O
225,4,debris,B-DISASTER
225,5,flow,I-DISASTER
225,6,buried,O
225,7,the,O
225,8,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
225,9,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
225,10,where,O
225,11,many,B-CASUALTY
225,12,households,I-CASUALTY
225,13,displaced,I-CASUALTY
225,14,had,O
225,15,taken,O
225,16,shelter,O
225,17,.,O
226,0,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
226,1,Kaito,I-DISASTER
226,2,froze,O
226,3,the,O
226,4,school,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
226,5,shelter,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
226,6,near,O
226,7,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
226,8,",",O
226,9,delaying,O
226,10,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
226,11,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
226,12,from,O
226,13,Local,B-ORG
226,14,Red,I-ORG
226,15,Crescent,I-ORG
226,16,.,O
227,0,In,O
227,1,Dili,B-LOCATION
227,2,",",O
227,3,Emergency,B-ORG
227,4,Logistics,I-ORG
227,5,Hub,I-ORG
227,6,reported,O
227,7,dozens,B-CASUALTY
227,8,of,I-CASUALTY
227,9,children,I-CASUALTY
227,10,missing,I-CASUALTY
227,11,when,O
227,12,the,O
227,13,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
227,14,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
227,15,failed,O
227,16,.,O
228,0,A,O
228,1,volcanic,B-DISASTER
228,2,eruption,I-DISASTER
228,3,closed,O
228,4,the,O
228,5,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
228,6,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
228,7,to,O
228,8,Manta,B-LOCATION
228,9,",",O
228,10,stranding,O
228,11,Emergency,B-ORG
228,12,Logistics,I-ORG
228,13,Hub,I-ORG
228,14,with,O
228,15,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
228,16,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
228,17,.,O
229,0,Humanity,B-ORG
229,1,First,I-ORG
229,2,reported,O
229,3,coastal,B-CASUALTY
229,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
229,5,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
229,6,when,O
229,7,the,O
229,8,cold,B-DISASTER
229,9,snap,I-DISASTER
229,10,hit,O
229,11,the,O
229,12,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
229,13,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
229,14,outside,O
229,15,Kampala,B-LOCATION
229,16,.,O
230,0,Search,O
230,1,crews,O
230,2,found,O
230,3,port,B-CASUALTY
230,4,staff,I-CASUALTY
230,5,missing,I-CASUALTY
230,6,under,O
230,7,the,O
230,8,collapsed,O
230,9,fiber,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
230,10,line,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
230,11,in,O
230,12,Asmara,B-LOCATION
230,13,.,O
231,0,Before,O
231,1,dawn,O
231,2,",",O
231,3,ice,B-DISASTER
231,4,jam,I-DISASTER
231,5,cut,O
231,6,power,O
231,7,in,O
231,8,Dakar,B-LOCATION
231,9,while,O
231,10,Telecoms,B-ORG
231,11,Without,I-ORG
231,12,Borders,I-ORG
231,13,requested,O
231,14,oxygen,B-AID_RESOURCE
231,15,tanks,I-AID_RESOURCE
231,16,.,O
232,0,Islamic,B-ORG
232,1,Relief,I-ORG
232,2,warned,O
232,3,that,O
232,4,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
232,5,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
232,6,would,O
232,7,run,O
232,8,out,O
232,9,in,O
232,10,Rabat,B-LOCATION
232,11,if,O
232,12,the,O
232,13,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
232,14,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
232,15,remained,O
232,16,broken,O
232,17,.,O
233,0,Near,O
233,1,Rabat,B-LOCATION
233,2,",",O
233,3,the,O
233,4,rockfall,B-DISASTER
233,5,swept,O
233,6,through,O
233,7,the,O
233,8,coastal,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
233,9,pier,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
233,10,and,O
233,11,left,O
233,12,coastal,B-CASUALTY
233,13,residents,I-CASUALTY
233,14,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
233,15,.,O
234,0,port,B-CASUALTY
234,1,staff,I-CASUALTY
234,2,missing,I-CASUALTY
234,3,were,O
234,4,found,O
234,5,near,O
234,6,Georgetown,B-LOCATION
234,7,after,O
234,8,the,O
234,9,chemical,B-DISASTER
234,10,spill,I-DISASTER
234,11,swept,O
234,12,across,O
234,13,the,O
234,14,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
234,15,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
234,16,.,O
235,0,Health,B-ORG
235,1,Bridge,I-ORG
235,2,used,O
235,3,trauma,B-AID_RESOURCE
235,4,bandages,I-AID_RESOURCE
235,5,to,O
235,6,support,O
235,7,six,B-CASUALTY
235,8,volunteers,I-CASUALTY
235,9,hurt,I-CASUALTY
235,10,after,O
235,11,the,O
235,12,monsoon,B-DISASTER
235,13,flood,I-DISASTER
235,14,isolated,O
235,15,Bandar,B-LOCATION
235,16,Seri,I-LOCATION
235,17,Begawan,I-LOCATION
235,18,.,O
236,0,Emergency,B-ORG
236,1,Logistics,I-ORG
236,2,Hub,I-ORG
236,3,treated,O
236,4,three,B-CASUALTY
236,5,drivers,I-CASUALTY
236,6,rescued,I-CASUALTY
236,7,after,O
236,8,cold,B-DISASTER
236,9,snap,I-DISASTER
236,10,damaged,O
236,11,the,O
236,12,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
236,13,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
236,14,in,O
236,15,Bamako,B-LOCATION
236,16,.,O
237,0,Islamic,B-ORG
237,1,Relief,I-ORG
237,2,warned,O
237,3,that,O
237,4,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
237,5,were,O
237,6,running,O
237,7,low,O
237,8,in,O
237,9,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
237,10,after,O
237,11,the,O
237,12,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
237,13,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
237,14,overflowed,O
237,15,.,O
238,0,Humanity,B-ORG
238,1,First,I-ORG
238,2,reported,O
238,3,coastal,B-CASUALTY
238,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
238,5,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
238,6,when,O
238,7,the,O
238,8,ice,B-DISASTER
238,9,jam,I-DISASTER
238,10,hit,O
238,11,the,O
238,12,rail,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
238,13,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
238,14,outside,O
238,15,Paramaribo,B-LOCATION
238,16,.,O
239,0,Near,O
239,1,Dili,B-LOCATION
239,2,",",O
239,3,the,O
239,4,volcanic,B-DISASTER
239,5,eruption,I-DISASTER
239,6,swept,O
239,7,through,O
239,8,the,O
239,9,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
239,10,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
239,11,and,O
239,12,left,O
239,13,three,B-CASUALTY
239,14,drivers,I-CASUALTY
239,15,rescued,I-CASUALTY
239,16,.,O
240,0,Community,B-ORG
240,1,rescue,I-ORG
240,2,brigade,I-ORG
240,3,warned,O
240,4,that,O
240,5,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
240,6,were,O
240,7,running,O
240,8,low,O
240,9,in,O
240,10,Manta,B-LOCATION
240,11,after,O
240,12,the,O
240,13,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
240,14,runway,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
240,15,overflowed,O
240,16,.,O
241,0,CARE,B-ORG
241,1,teams,I-ORG
241,2,warned,O
241,3,that,O
241,4,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
241,5,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
241,6,were,O
241,7,running,O
241,8,low,O
241,9,in,O
241,10,Bamako,B-LOCATION
241,11,after,O
241,12,the,O
241,13,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
241,14,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
241,15,overflowed,O
241,16,.,O
242,0,The,O
242,1,peat,B-DISASTER
242,2,fire,I-DISASTER
242,3,cut,O
242,4,access,O
242,5,to,O
242,6,the,O
242,7,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
242,8,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
242,9,",",O
242,10,so,O
242,11,Crisis,B-ORG
242,12,Response,I-ORG
242,13,Unit,I-ORG
242,14,routed,O
242,15,thermal,B-AID_RESOURCE
242,16,blankets,I-AID_RESOURCE
242,17,toward,O
242,18,Bandar,B-LOCATION
242,19,Seri,I-LOCATION
242,20,Begawan,I-LOCATION
242,21,.,O
243,0,river,B-DISASTER
243,1,overflow,I-DISASTER
243,2,pushed,O
243,3,water,O
243,4,into,O
243,5,Zanzibar,B-LOCATION
243,6,",",O
243,7,knocking,O
243,8,out,O
243,9,the,O
243,10,mountain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
243,11,pass,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
243,12,.,O
244,0,Before,O
244,1,dawn,O
244,2,",",O
244,3,cold,B-DISASTER
244,4,snap,I-DISASTER
244,5,cut,O
244,6,power,O
244,7,in,O
244,8,Bamako,B-LOCATION
244,9,while,O
244,10,Relief,B-ORG
244,11,International,I-ORG
244,12,requested,O
244,13,infant,B-AID_RESOURCE
244,14,milk,I-AID_RESOURCE
244,15,.,O
245,0,The,O
245,1,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
245,2,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
245,3,in,O
245,4,Tbilisi,B-LOCATION
245,5,stayed,O
245,6,closed,O
245,7,while,O
245,8,CARE,B-ORG
245,9,teams,I-ORG
245,10,moved,O
245,11,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
245,12,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
245,13,through,O
245,14,back,O
245,15,roads,O
245,16,.,O
246,0,After,O
246,1,the,O
246,2,rockfall,B-DISASTER
246,3,",",O
246,4,the,O
246,5,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
246,6,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
246,7,asked,O
246,8,Blue,B-ORG
246,9,Shield,I-ORG
246,10,volunteers,I-ORG
246,11,for,O
246,12,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
246,13,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
246,14,.,O
247,0,Humanity,B-ORG
247,1,First,I-ORG
247,2,warned,O
247,3,that,O
247,4,search,B-AID_RESOURCE
247,5,drones,I-AID_RESOURCE
247,6,were,O
247,7,running,O
247,8,low,O
247,9,in,O
247,10,Cebu,B-LOCATION
247,11,after,O
247,12,the,O
247,13,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
247,14,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
247,15,overflowed,O
247,16,.,O
248,0,Samaritan,B-ORG
248,1,Aviation,I-ORG
248,2,delivered,O
248,3,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
248,4,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
248,5,to,O
248,6,Bukhara,B-LOCATION
248,7,after,O
248,8,rainwater,O
248,9,contaminated,O
248,10,the,O
248,11,fiber,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
248,12,line,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
248,13,.,O
249,0,A,O
249,1,damaged,O
249,2,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
249,3,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
249,4,slowed,O
249,5,evacuation,O
249,6,from,O
249,7,Rabat,B-LOCATION
249,8,;,O
249,9,Telecoms,B-ORG
249,10,Without,I-ORG
249,11,Borders,I-ORG
249,12,asked,O
249,13,for,O
249,14,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
249,15,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
249,16,.,O
250,0,In,O
250,1,Reykjavik,B-LOCATION
250,2,",",O
250,3,a,O
250,4,chemical,B-DISASTER
250,5,spill,I-DISASTER
250,6,buried,O
250,7,the,O
250,8,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
250,9,intake,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
250,10,where,O
250,11,many,B-CASUALTY
250,12,households,I-CASUALTY
250,13,displaced,I-CASUALTY
250,14,had,O
250,15,taken,O
250,16,shelter,O
250,17,.,O
251,0,The,O
251,1,ice,B-DISASTER
251,2,jam,I-DISASTER
251,3,cracked,O
251,4,the,O
251,5,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
251,6,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
251,7,outside,O
251,8,Luanda,B-LOCATION
251,9,",",O
251,10,so,O
251,11,Aviation,B-ORG
251,12,Sans,I-ORG
251,13,Frontieres,I-ORG
251,14,sent,O
251,15,family,B-AID_RESOURCE
251,16,tents,I-AID_RESOURCE
251,17,.,O
252,0,A,O
252,1,damaged,O
252,2,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
252,3,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
252,4,slowed,O
252,5,evacuation,O
252,6,from,O
252,7,Reykjavik,B-LOCATION
252,8,;,O
252,9,Telecoms,B-ORG
252,10,Without,I-ORG
252,11,Borders,I-ORG
252,12,asked,O
252,13,for,O
252,14,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
252,15,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
252,16,.,O
253,0,Search,O
253,1,crews,O
253,2,found,O
253,3,five,B-CASUALTY
253,4,workers,I-CASUALTY
253,5,trapped,I-CASUALTY
253,6,under,O
253,7,the,O
253,8,collapsed,O
253,9,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
253,10,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
253,11,in,O
253,12,Zanzibar,B-LOCATION
253,13,.,O
254,0,Blue,B-ORG
254,1,Shield,I-ORG
254,2,volunteers,I-ORG
254,3,moved,O
254,4,diesel,B-AID_RESOURCE
254,5,drums,I-AID_RESOURCE
254,6,to,O
254,7,Kigali,B-LOCATION
254,8,after,O
254,9,the,O
254,10,ash,B-DISASTER
254,11,cloud,I-DISASTER
254,12,shut,O
254,13,the,O
254,14,community,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
254,15,well,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
254,16,.,O
255,0,CARE,B-ORG
255,1,teams,I-ORG
255,2,mapped,O
255,3,supply,O
255,4,gaps,O
255,5,near,O
255,6,Cebu,B-LOCATION
255,7,",",O
255,8,where,O
255,9,families,B-CASUALTY
255,10,cut,I-CASUALTY
255,11,off,I-CASUALTY
255,12,were,O
255,13,stranded,O
255,14,by,O
255,15,storm,B-DISASTER
255,16,cells,I-DISASTER
255,17,.,O
256,0,volcanic,B-DISASTER
256,1,eruption,I-DISASTER
256,2,in,O
256,3,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
256,4,carried,O
256,5,away,O
256,6,the,O
256,7,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
256,8,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
256,9,",",O
256,10,isolating,O
256,11,elderly,B-CASUALTY
256,12,patients,I-CASUALTY
256,13,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
256,14,.,O
257,0,In,O
257,1,Kigali,B-LOCATION
257,2,",",O
257,3,Food,B-ORG
257,4,for,I-ORG
257,5,the,I-ORG
257,6,Hungry,I-ORG
257,7,reported,O
257,8,two,B-CASUALTY
257,9,nurses,I-CASUALTY
257,10,injured,I-CASUALTY
257,11,when,O
257,12,the,O
257,13,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
257,14,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
257,15,failed,O
257,16,.,O
258,0,After,O
258,1,the,O
258,2,chemical,B-DISASTER
258,3,spill,I-DISASTER
258,4,",",O
258,5,the,O
258,6,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
258,7,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
258,8,asked,O
258,9,Action,B-ORG
258,10,Against,I-ORG
258,11,Hunger,I-ORG
258,12,for,O
258,13,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
258,14,bladders,I-AID_RESOURCE
258,15,.,O
259,0,Search,O
259,1,crews,O
259,2,found,O
259,3,many,B-CASUALTY
259,4,households,I-CASUALTY
259,5,displaced,I-CASUALTY
259,6,under,O
259,7,the,O
259,8,collapsed,O
259,9,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
259,10,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
259,11,in,O
259,12,Cebu,B-LOCATION
259,13,.,O
260,0,In,O
260,1,Dili,B-LOCATION
260,2,",",O
260,3,a,O
260,4,torrential,B-DISASTER
260,5,rain,I-DISASTER
260,6,buried,O
260,7,the,O
260,8,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
260,9,substation,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
260,10,where,O
260,11,six,B-CASUALTY
260,12,volunteers,I-CASUALTY
260,13,hurt,I-CASUALTY
260,14,had,O
260,15,taken,O
260,16,shelter,O
260,17,.,O
261,0,The,O
261,1,torrential,B-DISASTER
261,2,rain,I-DISASTER
261,3,cracked,O
261,4,the,O
261,5,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
261,6,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
261,7,outside,O
261,8,Asmara,B-LOCATION
261,9,",",O
261,10,so,O
261,11,Blue,B-ORG
261,12,Shield,I-ORG
261,13,volunteers,I-ORG
261,14,sent,O
261,15,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
261,16,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
261,17,.,O
262,0,Blue,B-ORG
262,1,Shield,I-ORG
262,2,volunteers,I-ORG
262,3,mapped,O
262,4,supply,O
262,5,gaps,O
262,6,near,O
262,7,Suva,B-LOCATION
262,8,",",O
262,9,where,O
262,10,dozens,B-CASUALTY
262,11,of,I-CASUALTY
262,12,children,I-CASUALTY
262,13,missing,I-CASUALTY
262,14,were,O
262,15,stranded,O
262,16,by,O
262,17,debris,B-DISASTER
262,18,flow,I-DISASTER
262,19,.,O
263,0,Near,O
263,1,Bukhara,B-LOCATION
263,2,",",O
263,3,the,O
263,4,torrential,B-DISASTER
263,5,rain,I-DISASTER
263,6,swept,O
263,7,through,O
263,8,the,O
263,9,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
263,10,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
263,11,and,O
263,12,left,O
263,13,schoolchildren,B-CASUALTY
263,14,stranded,I-CASUALTY
263,15,.,O
264,0,The,O
264,1,land,B-DISASTER
264,2,subsidence,I-DISASTER
264,3,cracked,O
264,4,the,O
264,5,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
264,6,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
264,7,outside,O
264,8,La,B-LOCATION
264,9,Paz,I-LOCATION
264,10,",",O
264,11,so,O
264,12,Aviation,B-ORG
264,13,Sans,I-ORG
264,14,Frontieres,I-ORG
264,15,sent,O
264,16,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
264,17,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
264,18,.,O
265,0,Humanity,B-ORG
265,1,First,I-ORG
265,2,delivered,O
265,3,chlorine,B-AID_RESOURCE
265,4,tablets,I-AID_RESOURCE
265,5,to,O
265,6,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
265,7,after,O
265,8,rainwater,O
265,9,contaminated,O
265,10,the,O
265,11,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
265,12,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
265,13,.,O
266,0,storm,B-DISASTER
266,1,cells,I-DISASTER
266,2,in,O
266,3,Cebu,B-LOCATION
266,4,carried,O
266,5,away,O
266,6,the,O
266,7,rail,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
266,8,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
266,9,",",O
266,10,isolating,O
266,11,many,B-CASUALTY
266,12,households,I-CASUALTY
266,13,displaced,I-CASUALTY
266,14,.,O
267,0,In,O
267,1,Bukhara,B-LOCATION
267,2,",",O
267,3,crews,O
267,4,requested,O
267,5,cash,B-AID_RESOURCE
267,6,vouchers,I-AID_RESOURCE
267,7,because,O
267,8,the,O
267,9,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
267,10,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
267,11,failed,O
267,12,during,O
267,13,the,O
267,14,torrential,B-DISASTER
267,15,rain,I-DISASTER
267,16,.,O
268,0,After,O
268,1,the,O
268,2,earth,B-DISASTER
268,3,tremor,I-DISASTER
268,4,",",O
268,5,the,O
268,6,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
268,7,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
268,8,asked,O
268,9,Community,B-ORG
268,10,rescue,I-ORG
268,11,brigade,I-ORG
268,12,for,O
268,13,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
268,14,.,O
269,0,Samaritan,B-ORG
269,1,Aviation,I-ORG
269,2,warned,O
269,3,that,O
269,4,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
269,5,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
269,6,were,O
269,7,running,O
269,8,low,O
269,9,in,O
269,10,Valparaiso,B-LOCATION
269,11,after,O
269,12,the,O
269,13,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
269,14,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
269,15,overflowed,O
269,16,.,O
270,0,A,O
270,1,damaged,O
270,2,ferry,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
270,3,dock,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
270,4,slowed,O
270,5,evacuation,O
270,6,from,O
270,7,Port,B-LOCATION
270,8,Vila,I-LOCATION
270,9,;,O
270,10,Crisis,B-ORG
270,11,Response,I-ORG
270,12,Unit,I-ORG
270,13,asked,O
270,14,for,O
270,15,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
270,16,.,O
271,0,Local,O
271,1,officials,O
271,2,in,O
271,3,Dakar,B-LOCATION
271,4,said,O
271,5,the,O
271,6,urban,B-DISASTER
271,7,flash,I-DISASTER
271,8,flood,I-DISASTER
271,9,forced,O
271,10,three,B-CASUALTY
271,11,drivers,I-CASUALTY
271,12,rescued,I-CASUALTY
271,13,from,O
271,14,homes,O
271,15,near,O
271,16,the,O
271,17,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
271,18,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
271,19,.,O
272,0,Water,B-ORG
272,1,Mission,I-ORG
272,2,reported,O
272,3,17,B-CASUALTY
272,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
272,5,injured,I-CASUALTY
272,6,when,O
272,7,the,O
272,8,dam,B-DISASTER
272,9,burst,I-DISASTER
272,10,hit,O
272,11,the,O
272,12,coastal,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
272,13,pier,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
272,14,outside,O
272,15,La,B-LOCATION
272,16,Paz,I-LOCATION
272,17,.,O
273,0,Local,O
273,1,officials,O
273,2,in,O
273,3,Tbilisi,B-LOCATION
273,4,said,O
273,5,the,O
273,6,Typhoon,B-DISASTER
273,7,Kaito,I-DISASTER
273,8,forced,O
273,9,coastal,B-CASUALTY
273,10,residents,I-CASUALTY
273,11,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
273,12,from,O
273,13,homes,O
273,14,near,O
273,15,the,O
273,16,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
273,17,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
273,18,.,O
274,0,Water,B-ORG
274,1,Mission,I-ORG
274,2,used,O
274,3,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
274,4,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
274,5,to,O
274,6,support,O
274,7,port,B-CASUALTY
274,8,staff,I-CASUALTY
274,9,missing,I-CASUALTY
274,10,after,O
274,11,the,O
274,12,chemical,B-DISASTER
274,13,spill,I-DISASTER
274,14,isolated,O
274,15,Reykjavik,B-LOCATION
274,16,.,O
275,0,peat,B-DISASTER
275,1,fire,I-DISASTER
275,2,in,O
275,3,La,B-LOCATION
275,4,Paz,I-LOCATION
275,5,carried,O
275,6,away,O
275,7,the,O
275,8,distribution,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
275,9,warehouse,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
275,10,",",O
275,11,isolating,O
275,12,four,B-CASUALTY
275,13,passengers,I-CASUALTY
275,14,missing,I-CASUALTY
275,15,.,O
276,0,Food,B-ORG
276,1,for,I-ORG
276,2,the,I-ORG
276,3,Hungry,I-ORG
276,4,warned,O
276,5,that,O
276,6,satellite,B-AID_RESOURCE
276,7,terminals,I-AID_RESOURCE
276,8,were,O
276,9,running,O
276,10,low,O
276,11,in,O
276,12,Kampala,B-LOCATION
276,13,after,O
276,14,the,O
276,15,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
276,16,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
276,17,overflowed,O
276,18,.,O
277,0,In,O
277,1,Kampala,B-LOCATION
277,2,",",O
277,3,crews,O
277,4,requested,O
277,5,sleeping,B-AID_RESOURCE
277,6,mats,I-AID_RESOURCE
277,7,because,O
277,8,the,O
277,9,grain,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
277,10,silo,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
277,11,failed,O
277,12,during,O
277,13,the,O
277,14,chemical,B-DISASTER
277,15,spill,I-DISASTER
277,16,.,O
278,0,A,O
278,1,Cyclone,B-DISASTER
278,2,Vira,I-DISASTER
278,3,above,O
278,4,Bamako,B-LOCATION
278,5,blocked,O
278,6,the,O
278,7,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
278,8,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
278,9,",",O
278,10,leaving,O
278,11,six,B-CASUALTY
278,12,volunteers,I-CASUALTY
278,13,hurt,I-CASUALTY
278,14,.,O
279,0,A,O
279,1,damaged,O
279,2,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
279,3,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
279,4,slowed,O
279,5,evacuation,O
279,6,from,O
279,7,Zanzibar,B-LOCATION
279,8,;,O
279,9,Community,B-ORG
279,10,rescue,I-ORG
279,11,brigade,I-ORG
279,12,asked,O
279,13,for,O
279,14,tarpaulin,B-AID_RESOURCE
279,15,rolls,I-AID_RESOURCE
279,16,.,O
280,0,Telecoms,B-ORG
280,1,Without,I-ORG
280,2,Borders,I-ORG
280,3,moved,O
280,4,splints,B-AID_RESOURCE
280,5,to,O
280,6,Asmara,B-LOCATION
280,7,after,O
280,8,the,O
280,9,ice,B-DISASTER
280,10,jam,I-DISASTER
280,11,shut,O
280,12,the,O
280,13,primary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
280,14,clinic,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
280,15,.,O
281,0,peat,B-DISASTER
281,1,fire,I-DISASTER
281,2,froze,O
281,3,the,O
281,4,sewage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
281,5,pump,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
281,6,near,O
281,7,Bandar,B-LOCATION
281,8,Seri,I-LOCATION
281,9,Begawan,I-LOCATION
281,10,",",O
281,11,delaying,O
281,12,kitchen,B-AID_RESOURCE
281,13,sets,I-AID_RESOURCE
281,14,from,O
281,15,Humanity,B-ORG
281,16,First,I-ORG
281,17,.,O
282,0,In,O
282,1,Antananarivo,B-LOCATION
282,2,",",O
282,3,Crisis,B-ORG
282,4,Response,I-ORG
282,5,Unit,I-ORG
282,6,opened,O
282,7,a,O
282,8,field,O
282,9,post,O
282,10,for,O
282,11,140,B-CASUALTY
282,12,people,I-CASUALTY
282,13,displaced,I-CASUALTY
282,14,after,O
282,15,heatwave,B-DISASTER
282,16,.,O
283,0,Rapid,B-ORG
283,1,Relief,I-ORG
283,2,Team,I-ORG
283,3,mapped,O
283,4,supply,O
283,5,gaps,O
283,6,near,O
283,7,Thimphu,B-LOCATION
283,8,",",O
283,9,where,O
283,10,three,B-CASUALTY
283,11,drivers,I-CASUALTY
283,12,rescued,I-CASUALTY
283,13,were,O
283,14,stranded,O
283,15,by,O
283,16,cold,B-DISASTER
283,17,snap,I-DISASTER
283,18,.,O
284,0,Food,B-ORG
284,1,for,I-ORG
284,2,the,I-ORG
284,3,Hungry,I-ORG
284,4,moved,O
284,5,kitchen,B-AID_RESOURCE
284,6,sets,I-AID_RESOURCE
284,7,to,O
284,8,Suva,B-LOCATION
284,9,after,O
284,10,the,O
284,11,earth,B-DISASTER
284,12,tremor,I-DISASTER
284,13,damaged,O
284,14,the,O
284,15,temporary,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
284,16,bridge,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
284,17,.,O
285,0,The,O
285,1,market,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
285,2,hall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
285,3,in,O
285,4,Rabat,B-LOCATION
285,5,stayed,O
285,6,closed,O
285,7,while,O
285,8,RescueNet,B-ORG
285,9,moved,O
285,10,solar,B-AID_RESOURCE
285,11,lamps,I-AID_RESOURCE
285,12,through,O
285,13,back,O
285,14,roads,O
285,15,.,O
286,0,A,O
286,1,damaged,O
286,2,drainage,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
286,3,canal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
286,4,slowed,O
286,5,evacuation,O
286,6,from,O
286,7,Georgetown,B-LOCATION
286,8,;,O
286,9,Telecoms,B-ORG
286,10,Without,I-ORG
286,11,Borders,I-ORG
286,12,asked,O
286,13,for,O
286,14,kitchen,B-AID_RESOURCE
286,15,sets,I-AID_RESOURCE
286,16,.,O
287,0,Food,B-ORG
287,1,for,I-ORG
287,2,the,I-ORG
287,3,Hungry,I-ORG
287,4,moved,O
287,5,diesel,B-AID_RESOURCE
287,6,drums,I-AID_RESOURCE
287,7,to,O
287,8,La,B-LOCATION
287,9,Paz,I-LOCATION
287,10,after,O
287,11,the,O
287,12,urban,B-DISASTER
287,13,flash,I-DISASTER
287,14,flood,I-DISASTER
287,15,shut,O
287,16,the,O
287,17,fuel,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
287,18,depot,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
287,19,.,O
288,0,In,O
288,1,Arequipa,B-LOCATION
288,2,",",O
288,3,MedGlobal,B-ORG
288,4,reported,O
288,5,six,B-CASUALTY
288,6,volunteers,I-CASUALTY
288,7,hurt,I-CASUALTY
288,8,when,O
288,9,the,O
288,10,mobile,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
288,11,tower,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
288,12,failed,O
288,13,.,O
289,0,Samaritan,B-ORG
289,1,Aviation,I-ORG
289,2,used,O
289,3,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
289,4,radios,I-AID_RESOURCE
289,5,to,O
289,6,support,O
289,7,nine,B-CASUALTY
289,8,families,I-CASUALTY
289,9,stranded,I-CASUALTY
289,10,after,O
289,11,the,O
289,12,cold,B-DISASTER
289,13,snap,I-DISASTER
289,14,isolated,O
289,15,Kampala,B-LOCATION
289,16,.,O
290,0,After,O
290,1,the,O
290,2,glacier,B-DISASTER
290,3,flood,I-DISASTER
290,4,",",O
290,5,the,O
290,6,reservoir,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
290,7,wall,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
290,8,asked,O
290,9,Rapid,B-ORG
290,10,Relief,I-ORG
290,11,Team,I-ORG
290,12,for,O
290,13,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
290,14,bladders,I-AID_RESOURCE
290,15,.,O
291,0,Humanity,B-ORG
291,1,First,I-ORG
291,2,moved,O
291,3,hygiene,B-AID_RESOURCE
291,4,kits,I-AID_RESOURCE
291,5,to,O
291,6,Anchorage,B-LOCATION
291,7,after,O
291,8,the,O
291,9,snow,B-DISASTER
291,10,squall,I-DISASTER
291,11,damaged,O
291,12,the,O
291,13,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
291,14,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
291,15,.,O
292,0,Humanity,B-ORG
292,1,First,I-ORG
292,2,sent,O
292,3,infant,B-AID_RESOURCE
292,4,milk,I-AID_RESOURCE
292,5,to,O
292,6,Kampala,B-LOCATION
292,7,after,O
292,8,the,O
292,9,rockfall,B-DISASTER
292,10,damaged,O
292,11,the,O
292,12,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
292,13,generator,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
292,14,.,O
293,0,A,O
293,1,earth,B-DISASTER
293,2,tremor,I-DISASTER
293,3,closed,O
293,4,the,O
293,5,evacuation,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
293,6,road,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
293,7,to,O
293,8,Nuku,B-LOCATION
293,9,',I-LOCATION
293,10,alofa,I-LOCATION
293,11,",",O
293,12,stranding,O
293,13,Community,B-ORG
293,14,rescue,I-ORG
293,15,brigade,I-ORG
293,16,with,O
293,17,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
293,18,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
293,19,.,O
294,0,Before,O
294,1,dawn,O
294,2,",",O
294,3,cold,B-DISASTER
294,4,snap,I-DISASTER
294,5,cut,O
294,6,power,O
294,7,in,O
294,8,Kigali,B-LOCATION
294,9,while,O
294,10,Action,B-ORG
294,11,Against,I-ORG
294,12,Hunger,I-ORG
294,13,requested,O
294,14,mosquito,B-AID_RESOURCE
294,15,nets,I-AID_RESOURCE
294,16,.,O
295,0,The,O
295,1,bus,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
295,2,terminal,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
295,3,in,O
295,4,La,B-LOCATION
