sentence_id,token_id,token,tag
0,0,World,B-ORG
0,1,Food,I-ORG
0,2,Programme,I-ORG
0,3,confirmed,O
0,4,hundreds,B-CASUALTY
0,5,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
0,6,near,O
0,7,Puerto,B-LOCATION
0,8,Rico,I-LOCATION
0,9,after,O
0,10,the,O
0,11,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
0,12,Irma,I-DISASTER
0,13,",",O
0,14,and,O
0,15,survivors,O
0,16,asked,O
0,17,for,O
0,18,blankets,B-AID_RESOURCE
0,19,instead,O
0,20,of,O
0,21,more,O
0,22,cameras,O
0,23,.,O
1,0,Emergency,O
1,1,update,O
1,2,:,O
1,3,BBC,B-ORG
1,4,warned,O
1,5,that,O
1,6,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
1,7,Irma,I-DISASTER
1,8,could,O
1,9,reach,O
1,10,Florida,B-LOCATION
1,11,after,O
1,12,flooding,O
1,13,around,O
1,14,Kingston,B-LOCATION
1,15,damaged,O
1,16,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
1,17,.,O
4,0,rescue,B-ORG
4,1,teams,I-ORG
4,2,warned,O
4,3,that,O
4,4,residents,O
4,5,in,O
4,6,Monterrey,B-LOCATION
4,7,urgently,O
4,8,need,O
4,9,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
4,10,after,O
4,11,the,O
4,12,flood,B-DISASTER
4,13,.,O
5,0,Residents,O
5,1,across,O
5,2,Ponce,B-LOCATION
5,3,are,O
5,4,waiting,O
5,5,for,O
5,6,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
5,7,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
5,8,as,O
5,9,damaged,O
5,10,port,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
5,11,slows,O
5,12,rescue,O
5,13,after,O
5,14,the,O
5,15,forest,B-DISASTER
5,16,fire,I-DISASTER
5,17,.,O
6,0,In,O
6,1,Naples,B-LOCATION
6,2,",",O
6,3,Red,B-ORG
6,4,Cross,I-ORG
6,5,said,O
6,6,injured,B-CASUALTY
6,7,residents,I-CASUALTY
6,8,were,O
6,9,reported,O
6,10,after,O
6,11,the,O
6,12,tropical,B-DISASTER
6,13,storm,I-DISASTER
6,14,",",O
6,15,and,O
6,16,crews,O
6,17,are,O
6,18,clearing,O
6,19,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
6,20,.,O
7,0,CNN,B-ORG
7,1,and,O
7,2,World,B-ORG
7,3,Food,I-ORG
7,4,Programme,I-ORG
7,5,delivered,O
7,6,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
7,7,and,O
7,8,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
7,9,to,O
7,10,Monterrey,B-LOCATION
7,11,after,O
7,12,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
7,13,Maria,I-DISASTER
7,14,caused,O
7,15,5,B-CASUALTY
7,16,confirmed,I-CASUALTY
7,17,deaths,I-CASUALTY
7,18,.,O
8,0,Severe,O
8,1,landslide,B-DISASTER
8,2,near,O
8,3,Veracruz,B-LOCATION
8,4,destroyed,O
8,5,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
8,6,while,O
8,7,UNICEF,B-ORG
8,8,moved,O
8,9,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
8,10,to,O
8,11,nearby,O
8,12,shelters,O
8,13,.,O
9,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
9,1,confirmed,O
9,2,3,B-CASUALTY
9,3,people,I-CASUALTY
9,4,missing,I-CASUALTY
9,5,near,O
9,6,San,B-LOCATION
9,7,Juan,I-LOCATION
9,8,after,O
9,9,the,O
9,10,flood,B-DISASTER
9,11,",",O
9,12,and,O
9,13,survivors,O
9,14,asked,O
9,15,for,O
9,16,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
9,17,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
9,18,instead,O
9,19,of,O
9,20,more,O
9,21,cameras,O
9,22,.,O
10,0,Volunteers,O
10,1,in,O
10,2,Key,B-LOCATION
10,3,West,I-LOCATION
10,4,are,O
10,5,distributing,O
10,6,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
10,7,to,O
10,8,families,O
10,9,displaced,O
10,10,by,O
10,11,the,O
10,12,earth,B-DISASTER
10,13,tremor,I-DISASTER
10,14,",",O
10,15,while,O
10,16,CNN,B-ORG
10,17,repairs,O
10,18,communication,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
10,19,network,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
10,20,.,O
14,0,Residents,O
14,1,across,O
14,2,Ponce,B-LOCATION
14,3,are,O
14,4,waiting,O
14,5,for,O
14,6,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
14,7,as,O
14,8,damaged,O
14,9,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
14,10,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
14,11,slows,O
14,12,rescue,O
14,13,after,O
14,14,the,O
14,15,tropical,B-DISASTER
14,16,storm,I-DISASTER
14,17,.,O
18,0,Doctors,B-ORG
18,1,Without,I-ORG
18,2,Borders,I-ORG
18,3,warned,O
18,4,that,O
18,5,residents,O
18,6,in,O
18,7,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
18,8,urgently,O
18,9,need,O
18,10,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
18,11,after,O
18,12,the,O
18,13,tropical,B-DISASTER
18,14,storm,I-DISASTER
18,15,.,O
19,0,Photos,O
19,1,from,O
19,2,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
19,3,show,O
19,4,collapsed,O
19,5,roads,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
19,6,after,O
19,7,the,O
19,8,earthquake,B-DISASTER
19,9,;,O
19,10,Doctors,B-ORG
19,11,Without,I-ORG
19,12,Borders,I-ORG
19,13,expects,O
19,14,more,O
19,15,requests,O
19,16,for,O
19,17,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
19,18,.,O
21,0,In,O
21,1,St,B-LOCATION
21,2,.,I-LOCATION
21,3,Thomas,I-LOCATION
21,4,",",O
21,5,FEMA,B-ORG
21,6,said,O
21,7,3,B-CASUALTY
21,8,people,I-CASUALTY
21,9,missing,I-CASUALTY
21,10,were,O
21,11,reported,O
21,12,after,O
21,13,the,O
21,14,tornado,B-DISASTER
21,15,",",O
21,16,and,O
21,17,crews,O
21,18,are,O
21,19,clearing,O
21,20,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
21,21,.,O
23,0,3,B-CASUALTY
23,1,people,I-CASUALTY
23,2,missing,I-CASUALTY
23,3,in,O
23,4,Santa,B-LOCATION
23,5,Rosa,I-LOCATION
23,6,after,O
23,7,tropical,B-DISASTER
23,8,storm,I-DISASTER
23,9,",",O
23,10,according,O
23,11,to,O
23,12,UNICEF,B-ORG
23,13,",",O
23,14,with,O
23,15,outages,O
23,16,affecting,O
23,17,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
23,18,.,O
24,0,Road,O
24,1,crews,O
24,2,reopened,O
24,3,part,O
24,4,of,O
24,5,the,O
24,6,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
24,7,in,O
24,8,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
24,9,after,O
24,10,the,O
24,11,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
24,12,Harvey,I-DISASTER
24,13,",",O
24,14,but,O
24,15,Army,B-ORG
24,16,Corps,I-ORG
24,17,says,O
24,18,senior,B-CASUALTY
24,19,citizens,I-CASUALTY
24,20,missing,I-CASUALTY
24,21,still,O
24,22,need,O
24,23,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
24,24,.,O
26,0,12,B-CASUALTY
26,1,injured,I-CASUALTY
26,2,in,O
26,3,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
26,4,after,O
26,5,tropical,B-DISASTER
26,6,storm,I-DISASTER
26,7,",",O
26,8,according,O
26,9,to,O
26,10,Red,B-ORG
26,11,Cross,I-ORG
26,12,",",O
26,13,with,O
26,14,outages,O
26,15,affecting,O
26,16,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
26,17,.,O
29,0,Road,O
29,1,crews,O
29,2,reopened,O
29,3,part,O
29,4,of,O
29,5,the,O
29,6,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
29,7,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
29,8,in,O
29,9,San,B-LOCATION
29,10,Juan,I-LOCATION
29,11,after,O
29,12,the,O
29,13,landslide,B-DISASTER
29,14,",",O
29,15,but,O
29,16,World,B-ORG
29,17,Food,I-ORG
29,18,Programme,I-ORG
29,19,says,O
29,20,families,B-CASUALTY
29,21,displaced,I-CASUALTY
29,22,still,O
29,23,need,O
29,24,water,O
29,25,.,O
30,0,Severe,O
30,1,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
30,2,Harvey,I-DISASTER
30,3,near,O
30,4,Cape,B-LOCATION
30,5,Town,I-LOCATION
30,6,destroyed,O
30,7,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
30,8,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
30,9,while,O
30,10,Red,B-ORG
30,11,Cross,I-ORG
30,12,moved,O
30,13,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
30,14,to,O
30,15,nearby,O
30,16,shelters,O
30,17,.,O
31,0,Photos,O
31,1,from,O
31,2,Kingston,B-LOCATION
31,3,show,O
31,4,collapsed,O
31,5,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
31,6,after,O
31,7,the,O
31,8,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
31,9,Irma,I-DISASTER
31,10,;,O
31,11,UNICEF,B-ORG
31,12,expects,O
31,13,more,O
31,14,requests,O
31,15,for,O
31,16,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
31,17,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
31,18,.,O
32,0,Field,O
32,1,report,O
32,2,:,O
32,3,UNICEF,B-ORG
32,4,warned,O
32,5,that,O
32,6,flood,B-DISASTER
32,7,could,O
32,8,reach,O
32,9,Naples,B-LOCATION
32,10,after,O
32,11,flooding,O
32,12,around,O
32,13,Dominica,B-LOCATION
32,14,damaged,O
32,15,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
32,16,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
32,17,.,O
33,0,multiple,B-CASUALTY
33,1,casualties,I-CASUALTY
33,2,in,O
33,3,Houston,B-LOCATION
33,4,after,O
33,5,flood,B-DISASTER
33,6,",",O
33,7,according,O
33,8,to,O
33,9,FEMA,B-ORG
33,10,",",O
33,11,with,O
33,12,outages,O
33,13,affecting,O
33,14,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
33,15,.,O
34,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
34,1,and,O
34,2,rescue,B-ORG
34,3,teams,I-ORG
34,4,delivered,O
34,5,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
34,6,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
34,7,and,O
34,8,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
34,9,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
34,10,to,O
34,11,Houston,B-LOCATION
34,12,after,O
34,13,earth,B-DISASTER
34,14,tremor,I-DISASTER
34,15,caused,O
34,16,families,B-CASUALTY
34,17,displaced,I-CASUALTY
34,18,.,O
35,0,Army,B-ORG
35,1,Corps,I-ORG
35,2,confirmed,O
35,3,3,B-CASUALTY
35,4,people,I-CASUALTY
35,5,missing,I-CASUALTY
35,6,near,O
35,7,Puerto,B-LOCATION
35,8,Rico,I-LOCATION
35,9,after,O
35,10,the,O
35,11,landslide,B-DISASTER
35,12,",",O
35,13,and,O
35,14,survivors,O
35,15,asked,O
35,16,for,O
35,17,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
35,18,instead,O
35,19,of,O
35,20,more,O
35,21,cameras,O
35,22,.,O
36,0,National,B-ORG
36,1,Guard,I-ORG
36,2,announced,O
36,3,that,O
36,4,residents,O
36,5,in,O
36,6,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
36,7,urgently,O
36,8,need,O
36,9,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
36,10,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
36,11,after,O
36,12,the,O
36,13,mudslide,B-DISASTER
36,14,.,O
37,0,Update,O
37,1,:,O
37,2,NOAA,B-ORG
37,3,warned,O
37,4,that,O
37,5,storm,B-DISASTER
37,6,surge,I-DISASTER
37,7,could,O
37,8,reach,O
37,9,Lima,B-LOCATION
37,10,after,O
37,11,flooding,O
37,12,around,O
37,13,Dominica,B-LOCATION
37,14,damaged,O
37,15,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
37,16,.,O
38,0,World,B-ORG
38,1,Food,I-ORG
38,2,Programme,I-ORG
38,3,confirmed,O
38,4,victims,B-CASUALTY
38,5,stranded,I-CASUALTY
38,6,near,O
38,7,California,B-LOCATION
38,8,after,O
38,9,the,O
38,10,wildfire,B-DISASTER
38,11,",",O
38,12,and,O
38,13,survivors,O
38,14,asked,O
38,15,for,O
38,16,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
38,17,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
38,18,instead,O
38,19,of,O
38,20,more,O
38,21,cameras,O
38,22,.,O
39,0,Severe,O
39,1,landslide,B-DISASTER
39,2,near,O
39,3,San,B-LOCATION
39,4,Juan,I-LOCATION
39,5,destroyed,O
39,6,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
39,7,while,O
39,8,NOAA,B-ORG
39,9,moved,O
39,10,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
39,11,to,O
39,12,nearby,O
39,13,shelters,O
39,14,.,O
41,0,Road,O
41,1,crews,O
41,2,reopened,O
41,3,part,O
41,4,of,O
41,5,the,O
41,6,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
41,7,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
41,8,in,O
41,9,St,B-LOCATION
41,10,.,I-LOCATION
41,11,Thomas,I-LOCATION
41,12,after,O
41,13,the,O
41,14,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
41,15,Maria,I-DISASTER
41,16,",",O
41,17,but,O
41,18,NOAA,B-ORG
41,19,says,O
41,20,200,B-CASUALTY
41,21,dead,I-CASUALTY
41,22,still,O
41,23,need,O
41,24,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
41,25,.,O
42,0,Photos,O
42,1,from,O
42,2,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
42,3,show,O
42,4,collapsed,O
42,5,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
42,6,after,O
42,7,the,O
42,8,tropical,B-DISASTER
42,9,storm,I-DISASTER
42,10,;,O
42,11,NOAA,B-ORG
42,12,expects,O
42,13,more,O
42,14,requests,O
42,15,for,O
42,16,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
42,17,.,O
43,0,Alert,O
43,1,:,O
43,2,forest,B-DISASTER
43,3,fire,I-DISASTER
43,4,struck,O
43,5,Sicily,B-LOCATION
43,6,",",O
43,7,leaving,O
43,8,5,B-CASUALTY
43,9,confirmed,I-CASUALTY
43,10,deaths,I-CASUALTY
43,11,and,O
43,12,damaging,O
43,13,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
43,14,.,O
45,0,Witness,O
45,1,:,O
45,2,Red,B-ORG
45,3,Cross,I-ORG
45,4,warned,O
45,5,that,O
45,6,flood,B-DISASTER
45,7,could,O
45,8,reach,O
45,9,Haiti,B-LOCATION
45,10,after,O
45,11,flooding,O
45,12,around,O
45,13,Puerto,B-LOCATION
45,14,Rico,I-LOCATION
45,15,damaged,O
45,16,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
45,17,.,O
46,0,BBC,B-ORG
46,1,and,O
46,2,UNICEF,B-ORG
46,3,delivered,O
46,4,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
46,5,and,O
46,6,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
46,7,to,O
46,8,Orlando,B-LOCATION
46,9,after,O
46,10,mudslide,B-DISASTER
46,11,caused,O
46,12,children,B-CASUALTY
46,13,rescued,I-CASUALTY
46,14,.,O
48,0,World,B-ORG
48,1,Food,I-ORG
48,2,Programme,I-ORG
48,3,and,O
48,4,Army,B-ORG
48,5,Corps,I-ORG
48,6,delivered,O
48,7,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
48,8,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
48,9,and,O
48,10,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
48,11,to,O
48,12,Texas,B-LOCATION
48,13,after,O
48,14,aftershock,B-DISASTER
48,15,caused,O
48,16,missing,B-CASUALTY
48,17,tourists,I-CASUALTY
48,18,.,O
50,0,Volunteers,O
50,1,in,O
50,2,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
50,3,City,I-LOCATION
50,4,are,O
50,5,distributing,O
50,6,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
50,7,to,O
50,8,families,O
50,9,displaced,O
50,10,by,O
50,11,the,O
50,12,wildfire,B-DISASTER
50,13,",",O
50,14,while,O
50,15,fire,B-ORG
50,16,department,I-ORG
50,17,repairs,O
50,18,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
50,19,.,O
55,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
55,1,said,O
55,2,that,O
55,3,residents,O
55,4,in,O
55,5,Santa,B-LOCATION
55,6,Rosa,I-LOCATION
55,7,urgently,O
55,8,need,O
55,9,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
55,10,after,O
55,11,the,O
55,12,tropical,B-DISASTER
55,13,storm,I-DISASTER
55,14,.,O
56,0,rescue,B-ORG
56,1,teams,I-ORG
56,2,confirmed,O
56,3,evacuees,B-CASUALTY
56,4,injured,I-CASUALTY
56,5,near,O
56,6,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
56,7,after,O
56,8,the,O
56,9,landslide,B-DISASTER
56,10,",",O
56,11,and,O
56,12,survivors,O
56,13,asked,O
56,14,for,O
56,15,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
56,16,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
56,17,instead,O
56,18,of,O
56,19,more,O
56,20,cameras,O
56,21,.,O
60,0,BBC,B-ORG
60,1,and,O
60,2,local,B-ORG
60,3,police,I-ORG
60,4,delivered,O
60,5,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
60,6,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
60,7,and,O
60,8,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
60,9,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
60,10,to,O
60,11,Lima,B-LOCATION
60,12,after,O
60,13,landslide,B-DISASTER
60,14,caused,O
60,15,12,B-CASUALTY
60,16,injured,I-CASUALTY
60,17,.,O
61,0,Witness,O
61,1,:,O
61,2,forest,B-DISASTER
61,3,fire,I-DISASTER
61,4,devastated,O
61,5,Kingston,B-LOCATION
61,6,",",O
61,7,leaving,O
61,8,multiple,B-CASUALTY
61,9,casualties,I-CASUALTY
61,10,and,O
61,11,damaging,O
61,12,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
61,13,.,O
62,0,Road,O
62,1,crews,O
62,2,reopened,O
62,3,part,O
62,4,of,O
62,5,the,O
62,6,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
62,7,in,O
62,8,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
62,9,after,O
62,10,the,O
62,11,mudslide,B-DISASTER
62,12,",",O
62,13,but,O
62,14,Doctors,B-ORG
62,15,Without,I-ORG
62,16,Borders,I-ORG
62,17,says,O
62,18,children,B-CASUALTY
62,19,rescued,I-CASUALTY
62,20,still,O
62,21,need,O
62,22,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
62,23,.,O
64,0,Update,O
64,1,:,O
64,2,earth,B-DISASTER
64,3,tremor,I-DISASTER
64,4,hit,O
64,5,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
64,6,City,I-LOCATION
64,7,",",O
64,8,leaving,O
64,9,children,B-CASUALTY
64,10,rescued,I-CASUALTY
64,11,and,O
64,12,damaging,O
64,13,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
64,14,.,O
65,0,Residents,O
65,1,across,O
65,2,Orlando,B-LOCATION
65,3,are,O
65,4,waiting,O
65,5,for,O
65,6,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
65,7,as,O
65,8,damaged,O
65,9,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
65,10,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
65,11,slows,O
65,12,rescue,O
65,13,after,O
65,14,the,O
65,15,flash,B-DISASTER
65,16,flood,I-DISASTER
65,17,.,O
66,0,Residents,O
66,1,across,O
66,2,Houston,B-LOCATION
66,3,are,O
66,4,waiting,O
66,5,for,O
66,6,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
66,7,as,O
66,8,damaged,O
66,9,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
66,10,slows,O
66,11,rescue,O
66,12,after,O
66,13,the,O
66,14,forest,B-DISASTER
66,15,fire,I-DISASTER
66,16,.,O
67,0,Breaking,O
67,1,:,O
67,2,tropical,B-DISASTER
67,3,storm,I-DISASTER
67,4,devastated,O
67,5,Puerto,B-LOCATION
67,6,Rico,I-LOCATION
67,7,",",O
67,8,leaving,O
67,9,5,B-CASUALTY
67,10,confirmed,I-CASUALTY
67,11,deaths,I-CASUALTY
67,12,and,O
67,13,damaging,O
67,14,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
67,15,.,O
68,0,In,O
68,1,Key,B-LOCATION
68,2,West,I-LOCATION
68,3,",",O
68,4,Reuters,B-ORG
68,5,said,O
68,6,victims,B-CASUALTY
68,7,stranded,I-CASUALTY
68,8,were,O
68,9,reported,O
68,10,after,O
68,11,the,O
68,12,storm,B-DISASTER
68,13,surge,I-DISASTER
68,14,",",O
68,15,and,O
68,16,crews,O
68,17,are,O
68,18,clearing,O
68,19,port,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
68,20,.,O
69,0,Severe,O
69,1,wildfire,B-DISASTER
69,2,near,O
69,3,Texas,B-LOCATION
69,4,destroyed,O
69,5,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
69,6,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
69,7,while,O
69,8,rescue,B-ORG
69,9,teams,I-ORG
69,10,moved,O
69,11,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
69,12,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
69,13,to,O
69,14,nearby,O
69,15,shelters,O
69,16,.,O
70,0,NOAA,B-ORG
70,1,warned,O
70,2,that,O
70,3,residents,O
70,4,in,O
70,5,Key,B-LOCATION
70,6,West,I-LOCATION
70,7,urgently,O
70,8,need,O
70,9,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
70,10,after,O
70,11,the,O
70,12,tornado,B-DISASTER
70,13,.,O
72,0,Witness,O
72,1,:,O
72,2,forest,B-DISASTER
72,3,fire,I-DISASTER
72,4,struck,O
72,5,Santa,B-LOCATION
72,6,Rosa,I-LOCATION
72,7,",",O
72,8,leaving,O
72,9,multiple,B-CASUALTY
72,10,casualties,I-CASUALTY
72,11,and,O
72,12,damaging,O
72,13,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
72,14,.,O
73,0,Road,O
73,1,crews,O
73,2,reopened,O
73,3,part,O
73,4,of,O
73,5,the,O
73,6,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
73,7,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
73,8,in,O
73,9,Ponce,B-LOCATION
73,10,after,O
73,11,the,O
73,12,landslide,B-DISASTER
73,13,",",O
73,14,but,O
73,15,Reuters,B-ORG
73,16,says,O
73,17,children,B-CASUALTY
73,18,rescued,I-CASUALTY
73,19,still,O
73,20,need,O
73,21,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
73,22,.,O
75,0,NOAA,B-ORG
75,1,and,O
75,2,CNN,B-ORG
75,3,delivered,O
75,4,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
75,5,and,O
75,6,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
75,7,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
75,8,to,O
75,9,Sicily,B-LOCATION
75,10,after,O
75,11,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
75,12,Harvey,I-DISASTER
75,13,caused,O
75,14,families,B-CASUALTY
75,15,displaced,I-CASUALTY
75,16,.,O
76,0,Residents,O
76,1,across,O
76,2,Haiti,B-LOCATION
76,3,are,O
76,4,waiting,O
76,5,for,O
76,6,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
76,7,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
76,8,as,O
76,9,damaged,O
76,10,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
76,11,slows,O
76,12,rescue,O
76,13,after,O
76,14,the,O
76,15,earth,B-DISASTER
76,16,tremor,I-DISASTER
76,17,.,O
77,0,Road,O
77,1,crews,O
77,2,reopened,O
77,3,part,O
77,4,of,O
77,5,the,O
77,6,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
77,7,in,O
77,8,Sicily,B-LOCATION
77,9,after,O
77,10,the,O
77,11,flash,B-DISASTER
77,12,flood,I-DISASTER
77,13,",",O
77,14,but,O
77,15,fire,B-ORG
77,16,department,I-ORG
77,17,says,O
77,18,victims,B-CASUALTY
77,19,stranded,I-CASUALTY
77,20,still,O
77,21,need,O
77,22,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
77,23,.,O
78,0,Emergency,O
78,1,update,O
78,2,:,O
78,3,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
78,4,Irma,I-DISASTER
78,5,damaged,O
78,6,Naples,B-LOCATION
78,7,",",O
78,8,leaving,O
78,9,20,B-CASUALTY
78,10,residents,I-CASUALTY
78,11,trapped,I-CASUALTY
78,12,and,O
78,13,damaging,O
78,14,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
78,15,.,O
80,0,In,O
80,1,Texas,B-LOCATION
80,2,",",O
80,3,World,B-ORG
80,4,Food,I-ORG
80,5,Programme,I-ORG
80,6,said,O
80,7,evacuees,B-CASUALTY
80,8,injured,I-CASUALTY
80,9,were,O
80,10,reported,O
80,11,after,O
80,12,the,O
80,13,flood,B-DISASTER
80,14,",",O
80,15,and,O
80,16,crews,O
80,17,are,O
80,18,clearing,O
80,19,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
80,20,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
80,21,.,O
82,0,Residents,O
82,1,across,O
82,2,Key,B-LOCATION
82,3,West,I-LOCATION
82,4,are,O
82,5,waiting,O
82,6,for,O
82,7,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
82,8,as,O
82,9,damaged,O
82,10,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
82,11,slows,O
82,12,rescue,O
82,13,after,O
82,14,the,O
82,15,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
82,16,Harvey,I-DISASTER
82,17,.,O
83,0,Red,B-ORG
83,1,Cross,I-ORG
83,2,confirmed,O
83,3,multiple,B-CASUALTY
83,4,casualties,I-CASUALTY
83,5,near,O
83,6,Sicily,B-LOCATION
83,7,after,O
83,8,the,O
83,9,forest,B-DISASTER
83,10,fire,I-DISASTER
83,11,",",O
83,12,and,O
83,13,survivors,O
83,14,asked,O
83,15,for,O
83,16,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
83,17,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
83,18,instead,O
83,19,of,O
83,20,more,O
83,21,cameras,O
83,22,.,O
84,0,Severe,O
84,1,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
84,2,Harvey,I-DISASTER
84,3,near,O
84,4,Dominica,B-LOCATION
84,5,destroyed,O
84,6,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
84,7,while,O
84,8,NOAA,B-ORG
84,9,moved,O
84,10,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
84,11,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
84,12,to,O
84,13,nearby,O
84,14,shelters,O
84,15,.,O
85,0,National,B-ORG
85,1,Guard,I-ORG
85,2,confirmed,O
85,3,injured,B-CASUALTY
85,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
85,5,near,O
85,6,San,B-LOCATION
85,7,Juan,I-LOCATION
85,8,after,O
85,9,the,O
85,10,aftershock,B-DISASTER
85,11,",",O
85,12,and,O
85,13,survivors,O
85,14,asked,O
85,15,for,O
85,16,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
85,17,instead,O
85,18,of,O
85,19,more,O
85,20,cameras,O
85,21,.,O
86,0,Volunteers,O
86,1,in,O
86,2,Haiti,B-LOCATION
86,3,are,O
86,4,distributing,O
86,5,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
86,6,to,O
86,7,families,O
86,8,displaced,O
86,9,by,O
86,10,the,O
86,11,tornado,B-DISASTER
86,12,",",O
86,13,while,O
86,14,UNICEF,B-ORG
86,15,repairs,O
86,16,gas,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
86,17,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
86,18,.,O
87,0,Volunteers,O
87,1,in,O
87,2,San,B-LOCATION
87,3,Juan,I-LOCATION
87,4,are,O
87,5,distributing,O
87,6,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
87,7,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
87,8,to,O
87,9,families,O
87,10,displaced,O
87,11,by,O
87,12,the,O
87,13,tornado,B-DISASTER
87,14,",",O
87,15,while,O
87,16,rescue,B-ORG
87,17,teams,I-ORG
87,18,repairs,O
87,19,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
87,20,.,O
88,0,National,B-ORG
88,1,Guard,I-ORG
88,2,said,O
88,3,that,O
88,4,residents,O
88,5,in,O
88,6,St,B-LOCATION
88,7,.,I-LOCATION
88,8,Thomas,I-LOCATION
88,9,urgently,O
88,10,need,O
88,11,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
88,12,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
88,13,after,O
88,14,the,O
88,15,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
88,16,Maria,I-DISASTER
88,17,.,O
89,0,Residents,O
89,1,across,O
89,2,St,B-LOCATION
89,3,.,I-LOCATION
89,4,Thomas,I-LOCATION
89,5,are,O
89,6,waiting,O
89,7,for,O
89,8,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
89,9,as,O
89,10,damaged,O
89,11,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
89,12,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
89,13,slows,O
89,14,rescue,O
89,15,after,O
89,16,the,O
89,17,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
89,18,Harvey,I-DISASTER
89,19,.,O
90,0,Residents,O
90,1,across,O
90,2,Ponce,B-LOCATION
90,3,are,O
90,4,waiting,O
90,5,for,O
90,6,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
90,7,as,O
90,8,damaged,O
90,9,roads,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
90,10,slows,O
90,11,rescue,O
90,12,after,O
90,13,the,O
90,14,tropical,B-DISASTER
90,15,storm,I-DISASTER
90,16,.,O
91,0,Residents,O
91,1,across,O
91,2,Mexico,B-LOCATION
91,3,City,I-LOCATION
91,4,are,O
91,5,waiting,O
91,6,for,O
91,7,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
91,8,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
91,9,as,O
91,10,damaged,O
91,11,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
91,12,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
91,13,slows,O
91,14,rescue,O
91,15,after,O
91,16,the,O
91,17,forest,B-DISASTER
91,18,fire,I-DISASTER
91,19,.,O
92,0,Residents,O
92,1,across,O
92,2,Texas,B-LOCATION
92,3,are,O
92,4,waiting,O
92,5,for,O
92,6,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
92,7,as,O
92,8,damaged,O
92,9,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
92,10,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
92,11,slows,O
92,12,rescue,O
92,13,after,O
92,14,the,O
92,15,storm,B-DISASTER
92,16,surge,I-DISASTER
92,17,.,O
93,0,missing,B-CASUALTY
93,1,tourists,I-CASUALTY
93,2,in,O
93,3,Haiti,B-LOCATION
93,4,after,O
93,5,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
93,6,Irma,I-DISASTER
93,7,",",O
93,8,according,O
93,9,to,O
93,10,FEMA,B-ORG
93,11,",",O
93,12,with,O
93,13,outages,O
93,14,affecting,O
93,15,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
93,16,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
93,17,.,O
94,0,In,O
94,1,Kingston,B-LOCATION
94,2,",",O
94,3,rescue,B-ORG
94,4,teams,I-ORG
94,5,said,O
94,6,12,B-CASUALTY
94,7,injured,I-CASUALTY
94,8,were,O
94,9,reported,O
94,10,after,O
94,11,the,O
94,12,aftershock,B-DISASTER
94,13,",",O
94,14,and,O
94,15,crews,O
94,16,are,O
94,17,clearing,O
94,18,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
94,19,.,O
95,0,Field,O
95,1,report,O
95,2,:,O
95,3,Reuters,B-ORG
95,4,warned,O
95,5,that,O
95,6,aftershock,B-DISASTER
95,7,could,O
95,8,reach,O
95,9,Cape,B-LOCATION
95,10,Town,I-LOCATION
95,11,after,O
95,12,flooding,O
95,13,around,O
95,14,Lima,B-LOCATION
95,15,damaged,O
95,16,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
95,17,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
95,18,.,O
96,0,NOAA,B-ORG
96,1,and,O
96,2,local,B-ORG
96,3,police,I-ORG
96,4,delivered,O
96,5,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
96,6,and,O
96,7,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
96,8,to,O
96,9,Texas,B-LOCATION
96,10,after,O
96,11,aftershock,B-DISASTER
96,12,caused,O
96,13,200,B-CASUALTY
96,14,dead,I-CASUALTY
96,15,.,O
98,0,local,B-ORG
98,1,police,I-ORG
98,2,confirmed,O
98,3,injured,B-CASUALTY
98,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
98,5,near,O
98,6,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
98,7,after,O
98,8,the,O
98,9,forest,B-DISASTER
98,10,fire,I-DISASTER
98,11,",",O
98,12,and,O
98,13,survivors,O
98,14,asked,O
98,15,for,O
98,16,blankets,B-AID_RESOURCE
98,17,instead,O
98,18,of,O
98,19,more,O
98,20,cameras,O
98,21,.,O
99,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
99,1,confirmed,O
99,2,3,B-CASUALTY
99,3,people,I-CASUALTY
99,4,missing,I-CASUALTY
99,5,near,O
99,6,San,B-LOCATION
99,7,Juan,I-LOCATION
99,8,after,O
99,9,the,O
99,10,storm,B-DISASTER
99,11,surge,I-DISASTER
99,12,",",O
99,13,and,O
99,14,survivors,O
99,15,asked,O
99,16,for,O
99,17,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
99,18,instead,O
99,19,of,O
99,20,more,O
99,21,cameras,O
99,22,.,O
100,0,World,B-ORG
100,1,Food,I-ORG
100,2,Programme,I-ORG
100,3,confirmed,O
100,4,3,B-CASUALTY
100,5,people,I-CASUALTY
100,6,missing,I-CASUALTY
100,7,near,O
100,8,St,B-LOCATION
100,9,.,I-LOCATION
103,0,Severe,O
103,1,forest,B-DISASTER
103,2,fire,I-DISASTER
103,3,near,O
103,4,Houston,B-LOCATION
103,5,destroyed,O
103,6,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
103,7,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
103,8,while,O
103,9,Reuters,B-ORG
103,10,moved,O
103,11,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
103,12,to,O
103,13,nearby,O
103,14,shelters,O
103,15,.,O
105,0,BBC,B-ORG
105,1,and,O
105,2,Doctors,B-ORG
105,3,Without,I-ORG
105,4,Borders,I-ORG
105,5,delivered,O
105,6,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
105,7,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
105,8,and,O
105,9,blankets,B-AID_RESOURCE
105,10,to,O
105,11,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
105,12,after,O
105,13,landslide,B-DISASTER
105,14,caused,O
105,15,multiple,B-CASUALTY
105,16,casualties,I-CASUALTY
105,17,.,O
106,0,In,O
106,1,Santa,B-LOCATION
106,2,Rosa,I-LOCATION
106,3,",",O
106,4,FEMA,B-ORG
106,5,said,O
106,6,families,B-CASUALTY
106,7,displaced,I-CASUALTY
106,8,were,O
106,9,reported,O
106,10,after,O
106,11,the,O
106,12,forest,B-DISASTER
106,13,fire,I-DISASTER
106,14,",",O
106,15,and,O
106,16,crews,O
106,17,are,O
106,18,clearing,O
106,19,communication,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
106,20,network,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
106,21,.,O
107,0,FEMA,B-ORG
107,1,confirmed,O
107,2,children,B-CASUALTY
107,3,rescued,I-CASUALTY
107,4,near,O
107,5,Sicily,B-LOCATION
107,6,after,O
107,7,the,O
107,8,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
107,9,Maria,I-DISASTER
107,10,",",O
107,11,and,O
107,12,survivors,O
107,13,asked,O
107,14,for,O
107,15,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
107,16,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
107,17,instead,O
107,18,of,O
107,19,more,O
107,20,cameras,O
107,21,.,O
108,0,20,B-CASUALTY
108,1,residents,I-CASUALTY
108,2,trapped,I-CASUALTY
108,3,in,O
108,4,Veracruz,B-LOCATION
108,5,after,O
108,6,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
108,7,Harvey,I-DISASTER
108,8,",",O
108,9,according,O
108,10,to,O
108,11,National,B-ORG
108,12,Guard,I-ORG
108,13,",",O
108,14,with,O
108,15,outages,O
108,16,affecting,O
108,17,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
108,18,.,O
109,0,Road,O
109,1,crews,O
109,2,reopened,O
109,3,part,O
109,4,of,O
109,5,the,O
109,6,port,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
109,7,in,O
109,8,Ponce,B-LOCATION
109,9,after,O
109,10,the,O
109,11,flash,B-DISASTER
109,12,flood,I-DISASTER
109,13,",",O
109,14,but,O
109,15,Red,B-ORG
109,16,Cross,I-ORG
109,17,says,O
109,18,injured,B-CASUALTY
109,19,residents,I-CASUALTY
109,20,still,O
109,21,need,O
109,22,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
109,23,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
109,24,.,O
113,0,Emergency,O
113,1,update,O
113,2,:,O
113,3,Army,B-ORG
113,4,Corps,I-ORG
113,5,warned,O
113,6,that,O
113,7,flash,B-DISASTER
113,8,flood,I-DISASTER
113,9,could,O
113,10,reach,O
113,11,California,B-LOCATION
113,12,after,O
113,13,flooding,O
113,14,around,O
113,15,Kingston,B-LOCATION
113,16,damaged,O
113,17,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
113,18,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
113,19,.,O
117,0,Residents,O
117,1,across,O
117,2,Naples,B-LOCATION
117,3,are,O
117,4,waiting,O
117,5,for,O
117,6,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
117,7,as,O
117,8,damaged,O
117,9,gas,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
117,10,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
117,11,slows,O
117,12,rescue,O
117,13,after,O
117,14,the,O
117,15,mudslide,B-DISASTER
117,16,.,O
118,0,Alert,O
118,1,:,O
118,2,earth,B-DISASTER
118,3,tremor,I-DISASTER
118,4,struck,O
118,5,Haiti,B-LOCATION
118,6,",",O
118,7,leaving,O
118,8,multiple,B-CASUALTY
118,9,casualties,I-CASUALTY
118,10,and,O
118,11,damaging,O
118,12,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
118,13,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
118,14,.,O
120,0,hundreds,B-CASUALTY
120,1,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
120,2,in,O
120,3,Kingston,B-LOCATION
120,4,after,O
120,5,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
120,6,Harvey,I-DISASTER
120,7,",",O
120,8,according,O
120,9,to,O
120,10,CNN,B-ORG
120,11,",",O
120,12,with,O
120,13,outages,O
120,14,affecting,O
120,15,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
120,16,.,O
122,0,Road,O
122,1,crews,O
122,2,reopened,O
122,3,part,O
122,4,of,O
122,5,the,O
122,6,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
122,7,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
122,8,in,O
122,9,Orlando,B-LOCATION
122,10,after,O
122,11,the,O
122,12,forest,B-DISASTER
122,13,fire,I-DISASTER
122,14,",",O
122,15,but,O
122,16,Doctors,B-ORG
122,17,Without,I-ORG
122,18,Borders,I-ORG
122,19,says,O
122,20,3,B-CASUALTY
122,21,people,I-CASUALTY
122,22,missing,I-CASUALTY
122,23,still,O
122,24,need,O
122,25,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
122,26,.,O
123,0,Road,O
123,1,crews,O
123,2,reopened,O
123,3,part,O
123,4,of,O
123,5,the,O
123,6,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
123,7,in,O
123,8,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
123,9,City,I-LOCATION
123,10,after,O
123,11,the,O
123,12,aftershock,B-DISASTER
123,13,",",O
123,14,but,O
123,15,NOAA,B-ORG
123,16,says,O
123,17,victims,B-CASUALTY
123,18,stranded,I-CASUALTY
123,19,still,O
123,20,need,O
123,21,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
123,22,.,O
124,0,senior,B-CASUALTY
124,1,citizens,I-CASUALTY
124,2,missing,I-CASUALTY
124,3,in,O
124,4,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
124,5,after,O
124,6,flood,B-DISASTER
124,7,",",O
124,8,according,O
124,9,to,O
124,10,World,B-ORG
124,11,Food,I-ORG
124,12,Programme,I-ORG
124,13,",",O
124,14,with,O
124,15,outages,O
124,16,affecting,O
124,17,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
124,18,.,O
126,0,senior,B-CASUALTY
126,1,citizens,I-CASUALTY
126,2,missing,I-CASUALTY
126,3,in,O
126,4,Key,B-LOCATION
126,5,West,I-LOCATION
126,6,after,O
126,7,earth,B-DISASTER
126,8,tremor,I-DISASTER
126,9,",",O
126,10,according,O
126,11,to,O
126,12,Reuters,B-ORG
126,13,",",O
126,14,with,O
126,15,outages,O
126,16,affecting,O
126,17,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
126,18,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
126,19,.,O
127,0,fire,B-ORG
127,1,department,I-ORG
127,2,said,O
127,3,that,O
127,4,residents,O
127,5,in,O
127,6,St,B-LOCATION
127,7,.,I-LOCATION
127,8,Thomas,I-LOCATION
127,9,urgently,O
127,10,need,O
127,11,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
127,12,after,O
127,13,the,O
127,14,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
127,15,Irma,I-DISASTER
127,16,.,O
129,0,Alert,O
129,1,:,O
129,2,mudslide,B-DISASTER
129,3,damaged,O
129,4,Monterrey,B-LOCATION
129,5,",",O
129,6,leaving,O
129,7,multiple,B-CASUALTY
129,8,casualties,I-CASUALTY
129,9,and,O
129,10,damaging,O
129,11,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
129,12,.,O
130,0,Breaking,O
130,1,:,O
130,2,flash,B-DISASTER
130,3,flood,I-DISASTER
130,4,hit,O
130,5,Dominica,B-LOCATION
130,6,",",O
130,7,leaving,O
130,8,3,B-CASUALTY
130,9,people,I-CASUALTY
130,10,missing,I-CASUALTY
130,11,and,O
130,12,damaging,O
130,13,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
130,14,.,O
131,0,Doctors,B-ORG
131,1,Without,I-ORG
131,2,Borders,I-ORG
131,3,and,O
131,4,UNICEF,B-ORG
131,5,delivered,O
131,6,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
131,7,and,O
131,8,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
131,9,to,O
131,10,Mexico,B-LOCATION
131,11,City,I-LOCATION
131,12,after,O
131,13,earthquake,B-DISASTER
131,14,caused,O
131,15,children,B-CASUALTY
131,16,rescued,I-CASUALTY
131,17,.,O
133,0,Severe,O
133,1,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
133,2,Irma,I-DISASTER
133,3,near,O
133,4,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
133,5,destroyed,O
133,6,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
133,7,while,O
133,8,NOAA,B-ORG
133,9,moved,O
133,10,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
133,11,to,O
133,12,nearby,O
133,13,shelters,O
133,14,.,O
134,0,Reuters,B-ORG
134,1,and,O
134,2,rescue,B-ORG
134,3,teams,I-ORG
134,4,delivered,O
134,5,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
134,6,and,O
134,7,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
134,8,to,O
134,9,California,B-LOCATION
134,10,after,O
134,11,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
134,12,Harvey,I-DISASTER
134,13,caused,O
134,14,12,B-CASUALTY
134,15,injured,I-CASUALTY
134,16,.,O
136,0,local,B-ORG
136,1,police,I-ORG
136,2,confirmed,O
136,3,hundreds,B-CASUALTY
136,4,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
136,5,near,O
136,6,Naples,B-LOCATION
136,7,after,O
136,8,the,O
136,9,landslide,B-DISASTER
136,10,",",O
136,11,and,O
136,12,survivors,O
136,13,asked,O
136,14,for,O
136,15,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
136,16,instead,O
136,17,of,O
136,18,more,O
136,19,cameras,O
136,20,.,O
137,0,missing,B-CASUALTY
137,1,tourists,I-CASUALTY
137,2,in,O
137,3,Lima,B-LOCATION
137,4,after,O
137,5,mudslide,B-DISASTER
137,6,",",O
137,7,according,O
137,8,to,O
137,9,Red,B-ORG
137,10,Cross,I-ORG
137,11,",",O
137,12,with,O
137,13,outages,O
137,14,affecting,O
137,15,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
137,16,.,O
138,0,Volunteers,O
138,1,in,O
138,2,Kingston,B-LOCATION
138,3,are,O
138,4,distributing,O
138,5,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
138,6,to,O
138,7,families,O
138,8,displaced,O
138,9,by,O
138,10,the,O
138,11,aftershock,B-DISASTER
138,12,",",O
138,13,while,O
138,14,fire,B-ORG
138,15,department,I-ORG
138,16,repairs,O
138,17,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
138,18,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
138,19,.,O
141,0,Army,B-ORG
141,1,Corps,I-ORG
141,2,and,O
141,3,local,B-ORG
141,4,police,I-ORG
141,5,delivered,O
141,6,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
141,7,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
141,8,and,O
141,9,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
141,10,to,O
141,11,Orlando,B-LOCATION
141,12,after,O
141,13,flash,B-DISASTER
141,14,flood,I-DISASTER
141,15,caused,O
141,16,dozens,B-CASUALTY
141,17,of,I-CASUALTY
141,18,survivors,I-CASUALTY
141,19,.,O
143,0,BBC,B-ORG
143,1,and,O
143,2,Reuters,B-ORG
143,3,delivered,O
143,4,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
143,5,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
143,6,and,O
143,7,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
143,8,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
143,9,to,O
143,10,Texas,B-LOCATION
143,11,after,O
143,12,aftershock,B-DISASTER
143,13,caused,O
143,14,families,B-CASUALTY
143,15,displaced,I-CASUALTY
143,16,.,O
144,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
144,1,announced,O
144,2,that,O
144,3,residents,O
144,4,in,O
144,5,Cape,B-LOCATION
144,6,Town,I-LOCATION
144,7,urgently,O
144,8,need,O
144,9,blankets,B-AID_RESOURCE
144,10,after,O
144,11,the,O
144,12,tornado,B-DISASTER
144,13,.,O
145,0,Volunteers,O
145,1,in,O
145,2,Santa,B-LOCATION
145,3,Rosa,I-LOCATION
145,4,are,O
145,5,distributing,O
145,6,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
145,7,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
145,8,to,O
145,9,families,O
145,10,displaced,O
145,11,by,O
145,12,the,O
145,13,earthquake,B-DISASTER
145,14,",",O
145,15,while,O
145,16,NOAA,B-ORG
145,17,repairs,O
145,18,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
145,19,.,O
146,0,Residents,O
146,1,across,O
146,2,Naples,B-LOCATION
146,3,are,O
146,4,waiting,O
146,5,for,O
146,6,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
146,7,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
146,8,as,O
146,9,damaged,O
146,10,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
146,11,slows,O
146,12,rescue,O
146,13,after,O
146,14,the,O
146,15,mudslide,B-DISASTER
146,16,.,O
148,0,Residents,O
148,1,across,O
148,2,Orlando,B-LOCATION
148,3,are,O
148,4,waiting,O
148,5,for,O
148,6,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
148,7,as,O
148,8,damaged,O
148,9,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
148,10,slows,O
148,11,rescue,O
148,12,after,O
148,13,the,O
148,14,mudslide,B-DISASTER
148,15,.,O
149,0,local,B-ORG
149,1,police,I-ORG
149,2,confirmed,O
149,3,dozens,B-CASUALTY
149,4,of,I-CASUALTY
149,5,survivors,I-CASUALTY
149,6,near,O
149,7,Dominica,B-LOCATION
149,8,after,O
149,9,the,O
149,10,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
149,11,Irma,I-DISASTER
149,12,",",O
149,13,and,O
149,14,survivors,O
149,15,asked,O
149,16,for,O
149,17,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
149,18,instead,O
149,19,of,O
149,20,more,O
149,21,cameras,O
149,22,.,O
151,0,Field,O
151,1,report,O
151,2,:,O
151,3,earthquake,B-DISASTER
151,4,damaged,O
151,5,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
151,6,City,I-LOCATION
151,7,",",O
151,8,leaving,O
151,9,12,B-CASUALTY
151,10,injured,I-CASUALTY
151,11,and,O
151,12,damaging,O
151,13,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
151,14,.,O
152,0,local,B-ORG
152,1,police,I-ORG
152,2,and,O
152,3,BBC,B-ORG
152,4,delivered,O
152,5,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
152,6,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
152,7,and,O
152,8,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
152,9,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
152,10,to,O
152,11,Puerto,B-LOCATION
152,12,Rico,I-LOCATION
152,13,after,O
152,14,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
152,15,Irma,I-DISASTER
152,16,caused,O
152,17,hundreds,B-CASUALTY
152,18,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
152,19,.,O
153,0,Breaking,O
153,1,:,O
153,2,Doctors,B-ORG
153,3,Without,I-ORG
153,4,Borders,I-ORG
153,5,warned,O
153,6,that,O
153,7,landslide,B-DISASTER
153,8,could,O
153,9,reach,O
153,10,San,B-LOCATION
153,11,Juan,I-LOCATION
153,12,after,O
153,13,flooding,O
153,14,around,O
153,15,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
153,16,damaged,O
153,17,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
153,18,.,O
154,0,rescue,B-ORG
154,1,teams,I-ORG
154,2,and,O
154,3,BBC,B-ORG
154,4,delivered,O
154,5,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
154,6,and,O
154,7,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
154,8,to,O
154,9,Santa,B-LOCATION
154,10,Rosa,I-LOCATION
154,11,after,O
154,12,tornado,B-DISASTER
154,13,caused,O
154,14,20,B-CASUALTY
154,15,residents,I-CASUALTY
154,16,trapped,I-CASUALTY
154,17,.,O
156,0,Alert,O
156,1,:,O
156,2,NOAA,B-ORG
156,3,warned,O
156,4,that,O
156,5,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
156,6,Irma,I-DISASTER
156,7,could,O
156,8,reach,O
156,9,Orlando,B-LOCATION
156,10,after,O
156,11,flooding,O
156,12,around,O
156,13,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
156,14,City,I-LOCATION
156,15,damaged,O
156,16,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
156,17,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
156,18,.,O
157,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
157,1,announced,O
157,2,that,O
157,3,residents,O
157,4,in,O
157,5,Cape,B-LOCATION
157,6,Town,I-LOCATION
157,7,urgently,O
157,8,need,O
157,9,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
157,10,after,O
157,11,the,O
157,12,landslide,B-DISASTER
157,13,.,O
160,0,victims,B-CASUALTY
160,1,stranded,I-CASUALTY
160,2,in,O
160,3,Ponce,B-LOCATION
160,4,after,O
160,5,storm,B-DISASTER
160,6,surge,I-DISASTER
160,7,",",O
160,8,according,O
160,9,to,O
160,10,Reuters,B-ORG
160,11,",",O
160,12,with,O
160,13,outages,O
160,14,affecting,O
160,15,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
160,16,.,O
161,0,families,B-CASUALTY
161,1,displaced,I-CASUALTY
161,2,in,O
161,3,San,B-LOCATION
161,4,Juan,I-LOCATION
161,5,after,O
161,6,storm,B-DISASTER
161,7,surge,I-DISASTER
161,8,",",O
161,9,according,O
161,10,to,O
161,11,FEMA,B-ORG
161,12,",",O
161,13,with,O
161,14,outages,O
161,15,affecting,O
161,16,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
161,17,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
161,18,.,O
162,0,Photos,O
162,1,from,O
162,2,Kingston,B-LOCATION
162,3,show,O
162,4,collapsed,O
162,5,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
162,6,after,O
162,7,the,O
162,8,storm,B-DISASTER
162,9,surge,I-DISASTER
162,10,;,O
162,11,fire,B-ORG
162,12,department,I-ORG
162,13,expects,O
162,14,more,O
162,15,requests,O
162,16,for,O
162,17,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
162,18,.,O
163,0,multiple,B-CASUALTY
163,1,casualties,I-CASUALTY
163,2,in,O
163,3,Mexico,B-LOCATION
163,4,City,I-LOCATION
163,5,after,O
163,6,landslide,B-DISASTER
163,7,",",O
163,8,according,O
163,9,to,O
163,10,FEMA,B-ORG
163,11,",",O
163,12,with,O
163,13,outages,O
163,14,affecting,O
163,15,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
163,16,.,O
164,0,Severe,O
164,1,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
164,2,Harvey,I-DISASTER
164,3,near,O
164,4,St,B-LOCATION
164,5,.,I-LOCATION
164,6,Thomas,I-LOCATION
164,7,destroyed,O
164,8,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
164,9,while,O
164,10,World,B-ORG
164,11,Food,I-ORG
164,12,Programme,I-ORG
164,13,moved,O
164,14,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
164,15,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
164,16,to,O
164,17,nearby,O
164,18,shelters,O
164,19,.,O
165,0,Residents,O
165,1,across,O
165,2,Santa,B-LOCATION
165,3,Rosa,I-LOCATION
165,4,are,O
165,5,waiting,O
165,6,for,O
165,7,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
165,8,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
165,9,as,O
165,10,damaged,O
165,11,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
165,12,slows,O
165,13,rescue,O
165,14,after,O
165,15,the,O
165,16,flash,B-DISASTER
165,17,flood,I-DISASTER
165,18,.,O
166,0,BBC,B-ORG
166,1,warned,O
166,2,that,O
166,3,residents,O
166,4,in,O
166,5,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
166,6,urgently,O
166,7,need,O
166,8,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
166,9,after,O
166,10,the,O
166,11,landslide,B-DISASTER
166,12,.,O
167,0,Reuters,B-ORG
167,1,confirmed,O
167,2,dozens,B-CASUALTY
167,3,of,I-CASUALTY
167,4,survivors,I-CASUALTY
167,5,near,O
167,6,Monterrey,B-LOCATION
167,7,after,O
167,8,the,O
167,9,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
167,10,Maria,I-DISASTER
167,11,",",O
167,12,and,O
167,13,survivors,O
167,14,asked,O
167,15,for,O
167,16,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
167,17,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
167,18,instead,O
167,19,of,O
167,20,more,O
167,21,cameras,O
167,22,.,O
168,0,Photos,O
168,1,from,O
168,2,Orlando,B-LOCATION
168,3,show,O
168,4,collapsed,O
168,5,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
168,6,after,O
168,7,the,O
168,8,aftershock,B-DISASTER
168,9,;,O
168,10,NOAA,B-ORG
168,11,expects,O
168,12,more,O
168,13,requests,O
168,14,for,O
168,15,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
168,16,.,O
170,0,NOAA,B-ORG
170,1,said,O
170,2,that,O
170,3,residents,O
170,4,in,O
170,5,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
170,6,urgently,O
170,7,need,O
170,8,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
170,9,after,O
170,10,the,O
170,11,landslide,B-DISASTER
170,12,.,O
171,0,Severe,O
171,1,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
171,2,Maria,I-DISASTER
171,3,near,O
171,4,California,B-LOCATION
171,5,destroyed,O
171,6,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
171,7,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
171,8,while,O
171,9,NOAA,B-ORG
171,10,moved,O
171,11,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
171,12,to,O
171,13,nearby,O
171,14,shelters,O
171,15,.,O
175,0,World,B-ORG
175,1,Food,I-ORG
175,2,Programme,I-ORG
175,3,and,O
175,4,NOAA,B-ORG
175,5,delivered,O
175,6,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
175,7,and,O
175,8,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
175,9,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
175,10,to,O
175,11,Texas,B-LOCATION
175,12,after,O
175,13,landslide,B-DISASTER
175,14,caused,O
175,15,injured,B-CASUALTY
175,16,residents,I-CASUALTY
175,17,.,O
177,0,Alert,O
177,1,:,O
177,2,BBC,B-ORG
177,3,warned,O
177,4,that,O
177,5,flood,B-DISASTER
177,6,could,O
177,7,reach,O
177,8,Puerto,B-LOCATION
177,9,Rico,I-LOCATION
177,10,after,O
177,11,flooding,O
177,12,around,O
177,13,St,B-LOCATION
177,14,.,I-LOCATION
177,15,Thomas,I-LOCATION
177,16,damaged,O
177,17,port,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
177,18,.,O
178,0,National,B-ORG
178,1,Guard,I-ORG
178,2,and,O
178,3,Doctors,B-ORG
178,4,Without,I-ORG
178,5,Borders,I-ORG
178,6,delivered,O
178,7,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
178,8,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
178,9,and,O
178,10,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
178,11,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
178,12,to,O
178,13,Mexico,B-LOCATION
178,14,City,I-LOCATION
178,15,after,O
178,16,tropical,B-DISASTER
178,17,storm,I-DISASTER
178,18,caused,O
178,19,12,B-CASUALTY
178,20,injured,I-CASUALTY
178,21,.,O
179,0,missing,B-CASUALTY
179,1,tourists,I-CASUALTY
179,2,in,O
179,3,Haiti,B-LOCATION
179,4,after,O
179,5,storm,B-DISASTER
179,6,surge,I-DISASTER
179,7,",",O
179,8,according,O
179,9,to,O
179,10,FEMA,B-ORG
179,11,",",O
179,12,with,O
179,13,outages,O
179,14,affecting,O
179,15,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
179,16,.,O
181,0,local,B-ORG
181,1,police,I-ORG
181,2,confirmed,O
181,3,12,B-CASUALTY
181,4,injured,I-CASUALTY
181,5,near,O
181,6,Haiti,B-LOCATION
181,7,after,O
181,8,the,O
181,9,tropical,B-DISASTER
181,10,storm,I-DISASTER
181,11,",",O
181,12,and,O
181,13,survivors,O
181,14,asked,O
181,15,for,O
181,16,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
181,17,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
181,18,instead,O
181,19,of,O
181,20,more,O
181,21,cameras,O
181,22,.,O
182,0,Witness,O
182,1,:,O
182,2,World,B-ORG
182,3,Food,I-ORG
182,4,Programme,I-ORG
182,5,warned,O
182,6,that,O
182,7,tornado,B-DISASTER
182,8,could,O
182,9,reach,O
182,10,Puerto,B-LOCATION
182,11,Rico,I-LOCATION
182,12,after,O
182,13,flooding,O
182,14,around,O
182,15,St,B-LOCATION
182,16,.,I-LOCATION
182,17,Thomas,I-LOCATION
182,18,damaged,O
182,19,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
182,20,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
182,21,.,O
184,0,Field,O
184,1,report,O
184,2,:,O
184,3,NOAA,B-ORG
184,4,warned,O
184,5,that,O
184,6,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
184,7,Harvey,I-DISASTER
184,8,could,O
184,9,reach,O
184,10,Santa,B-LOCATION
184,11,Rosa,I-LOCATION
184,12,after,O
184,13,flooding,O
184,14,around,O
184,15,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
184,16,City,I-LOCATION
184,17,damaged,O
184,18,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
184,19,.,O
186,0,NOAA,B-ORG
186,1,and,O
186,2,local,B-ORG
186,3,police,I-ORG
186,4,delivered,O
186,5,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
186,6,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
186,7,and,O
186,8,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
186,9,to,O
186,10,Orlando,B-LOCATION
186,11,after,O
186,12,landslide,B-DISASTER
186,13,caused,O
186,14,senior,B-CASUALTY
186,15,citizens,I-CASUALTY
186,16,missing,I-CASUALTY
186,17,.,O
187,0,Severe,O
187,1,tropical,B-DISASTER
187,2,storm,I-DISASTER
187,3,near,O
187,4,Mexico,B-LOCATION
187,5,City,I-LOCATION
187,6,destroyed,O
187,7,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
187,8,while,O
187,9,Red,B-ORG
187,10,Cross,I-ORG
187,11,moved,O
187,12,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
187,13,to,O
187,14,nearby,O
187,15,shelters,O
187,16,.,O
188,0,Field,O
188,1,report,O
188,2,:,O
188,3,flood,B-DISASTER
188,4,hit,O
188,5,Naples,B-LOCATION
188,6,",",O
188,7,leaving,O
188,8,20,B-CASUALTY
188,9,residents,I-CASUALTY
188,10,trapped,I-CASUALTY
188,11,and,O
188,12,damaging,O
188,13,communication,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
188,14,network,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
188,15,.,O
189,0,Red,B-ORG
189,1,Cross,I-ORG
189,2,confirmed,O
189,3,20,B-CASUALTY
189,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
189,5,trapped,I-CASUALTY
189,6,near,O
189,7,Dominica,B-LOCATION
189,8,after,O
189,9,the,O
189,10,flood,B-DISASTER
189,11,",",O
189,12,and,O
189,13,survivors,O
189,14,asked,O
189,15,for,O
189,16,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
189,17,instead,O
189,18,of,O
189,19,more,O
189,20,cameras,O
189,21,.,O
190,0,Severe,O
190,1,storm,B-DISASTER
190,2,surge,I-DISASTER
190,3,near,O
190,4,Key,B-LOCATION
190,5,West,I-LOCATION
190,6,destroyed,O
190,7,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
190,8,while,O
190,9,local,B-ORG
190,10,police,I-ORG
190,11,moved,O
190,12,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
190,13,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
190,14,to,O
190,15,nearby,O
190,16,shelters,O
190,17,.,O
191,0,Volunteers,O
191,1,in,O
191,2,California,B-LOCATION
191,3,are,O
191,4,distributing,O
191,5,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
191,6,to,O
191,7,families,O
191,8,displaced,O
191,9,by,O
191,10,the,O
191,11,forest,B-DISASTER
191,12,fire,I-DISASTER
191,13,",",O
191,14,while,O
191,15,fire,B-ORG
191,16,department,I-ORG
191,17,repairs,O
191,18,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
191,19,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
191,20,.,O
192,0,200,B-CASUALTY
192,1,dead,I-CASUALTY
192,2,in,O
192,3,Key,B-LOCATION
192,4,West,I-LOCATION
192,5,after,O
192,6,tornado,B-DISASTER
192,7,",",O
192,8,according,O
192,9,to,O
192,10,BBC,B-ORG
192,11,",",O
192,12,with,O
192,13,outages,O
192,14,affecting,O
192,15,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
192,16,.,O
195,0,rescue,B-ORG
195,1,teams,I-ORG
195,2,and,O
195,3,CNN,B-ORG
195,4,delivered,O
195,5,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
195,6,and,O
195,7,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
195,8,to,O
195,9,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
195,10,City,I-LOCATION
195,11,after,O
195,12,flood,B-DISASTER
195,13,caused,O
195,14,12,B-CASUALTY
195,15,injured,I-CASUALTY
195,16,.,O
196,0,fire,B-ORG
196,1,department,I-ORG
196,2,confirmed,O
196,3,that,O
196,4,residents,O
196,5,in,O
196,6,Mexico,B-LOCATION
196,7,City,I-LOCATION
196,8,urgently,O
196,9,need,O
196,10,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
196,11,after,O
196,12,the,O
196,13,tornado,B-DISASTER
196,14,.,O
198,0,Residents,O
198,1,across,O
198,2,Sicily,B-LOCATION
198,3,are,O
198,4,waiting,O
198,5,for,O
198,6,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
198,7,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
198,8,as,O
198,9,damaged,O
198,10,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
198,11,slows,O
198,12,rescue,O
198,13,after,O
198,14,the,O
198,15,mudslide,B-DISASTER
198,16,.,O
199,0,NOAA,B-ORG
199,1,announced,O
199,2,that,O
199,3,residents,O
199,4,in,O
199,5,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
199,6,urgently,O
199,7,need,O
199,8,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
199,9,after,O
199,10,the,O
199,11,tropical,B-DISASTER
199,12,storm,I-DISASTER
199,13,.,O
200,0,Severe,O
200,1,mudslide,B-DISASTER
200,2,near,O
200,3,Key,B-LOCATION
200,4,West,I-LOCATION
200,5,destroyed,O
200,6,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
200,7,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
200,8,while,O
200,9,World,B-ORG
200,10,Food,I-ORG
200,11,Programme,I-ORG
200,12,moved,O
200,13,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
200,14,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
200,15,to,O
200,16,nearby,O
200,17,shelters,O
200,18,.,O
201,0,Severe,O
201,1,earthquake,B-DISASTER
201,2,near,O
201,3,Sicily,B-LOCATION
201,4,destroyed,O
201,5,port,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
201,6,while,O
201,7,FEMA,B-ORG
201,8,moved,O
201,9,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
201,10,to,O
201,11,nearby,O
201,12,shelters,O
201,13,.,O
202,0,Residents,O
202,1,across,O
202,2,Key,B-LOCATION
202,3,West,I-LOCATION
202,4,are,O
202,5,waiting,O
202,6,for,O
202,7,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
202,8,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
202,9,as,O
202,10,damaged,O
202,11,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
202,12,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
202,13,slows,O
202,14,rescue,O
202,15,after,O
202,16,the,O
202,17,flash,B-DISASTER
202,18,flood,I-DISASTER
202,19,.,O
203,0,local,B-ORG
203,1,police,I-ORG
203,2,confirmed,O
203,3,200,B-CASUALTY
203,4,dead,I-CASUALTY
203,5,near,O
203,6,Lima,B-LOCATION
203,7,after,O
203,8,the,O
203,9,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
203,10,Irma,I-DISASTER
203,11,",",O
203,12,and,O
203,13,survivors,O
203,14,asked,O
203,15,for,O
203,16,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
203,17,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
203,18,instead,O
203,19,of,O
203,20,more,O
203,21,cameras,O
203,22,.,O
204,0,Severe,O
204,1,flash,B-DISASTER
204,2,flood,I-DISASTER
204,3,near,O
204,4,Cape,B-LOCATION
204,5,Town,I-LOCATION
204,6,destroyed,O
204,7,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
204,8,while,O
204,9,NOAA,B-ORG
204,10,moved,O
204,11,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
204,12,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
204,13,to,O
204,14,nearby,O
204,15,shelters,O
204,16,.,O
205,0,Road,O
205,1,crews,O
205,2,reopened,O
205,3,part,O
205,4,of,O
205,5,the,O
205,6,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
205,7,in,O
205,8,Monterrey,B-LOCATION
205,9,after,O
205,10,the,O
205,11,earthquake,B-DISASTER
205,12,",",O
205,13,but,O
205,14,fire,B-ORG
205,15,department,I-ORG
205,16,says,O
205,17,missing,B-CASUALTY
205,18,tourists,I-CASUALTY
205,19,still,O
205,20,need,O
205,21,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
205,22,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
205,23,.,O
206,0,Residents,O
206,1,across,O
206,2,Ponce,B-LOCATION
206,3,are,O
206,4,waiting,O
206,5,for,O
206,6,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
206,7,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
206,8,as,O
206,9,damaged,O
206,10,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
206,11,slows,O
206,12,rescue,O
206,13,after,O
206,14,the,O
206,15,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
206,16,Maria,I-DISASTER
206,17,.,O
207,0,Severe,O
207,1,aftershock,B-DISASTER
207,2,near,O
207,3,Haiti,B-LOCATION
207,4,destroyed,O
207,5,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
207,6,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
207,7,while,O
207,8,World,B-ORG
207,9,Food,I-ORG
207,10,Programme,I-ORG
207,11,moved,O
207,12,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
207,13,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
207,14,to,O
207,15,nearby,O
207,16,shelters,O
207,17,.,O
208,0,Reuters,B-ORG
208,1,confirmed,O
208,2,hundreds,B-CASUALTY
208,3,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
208,4,near,O
208,5,Kingston,B-LOCATION
208,6,after,O
208,7,the,O
208,8,tropical,B-DISASTER
208,9,storm,I-DISASTER
208,10,",",O
208,11,and,O
208,12,survivors,O
208,13,asked,O
208,14,for,O
208,15,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
208,16,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
208,17,instead,O
208,18,of,O
208,19,more,O
208,20,cameras,O
208,21,.,O
210,0,Residents,O
210,1,across,O
210,2,Houston,B-LOCATION
210,3,are,O
210,4,waiting,O
210,5,for,O
210,6,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
210,7,as,O
210,8,damaged,O
210,9,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
210,10,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
210,11,slows,O
210,12,rescue,O
210,13,after,O
210,14,the,O
210,15,storm,B-DISASTER
210,16,surge,I-DISASTER
210,17,.,O
211,0,Volunteers,O
211,1,in,O
211,2,Orlando,B-LOCATION
211,3,are,O
211,4,distributing,O
211,5,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
211,6,to,O
211,7,families,O
211,8,displaced,O
211,9,by,O
211,10,the,O
211,11,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
211,12,Maria,I-DISASTER
211,13,",",O
211,14,while,O
211,15,NOAA,B-ORG
211,16,repairs,O
211,17,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
211,18,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
211,19,.,O
212,0,Breaking,O
212,1,:,O
212,2,CNN,B-ORG
212,3,warned,O
212,4,that,O
212,5,landslide,B-DISASTER
212,6,could,O
212,7,reach,O
212,8,Naples,B-LOCATION
212,9,after,O
212,10,flooding,O
212,11,around,O
212,12,Texas,B-LOCATION
212,13,damaged,O
212,14,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
212,15,.,O
213,0,Residents,O
213,1,across,O
213,2,Haiti,B-LOCATION
213,3,are,O
213,4,waiting,O
213,5,for,O
213,6,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
213,7,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
213,8,as,O
213,9,damaged,O
213,10,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
213,11,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
213,12,slows,O
213,13,rescue,O
213,14,after,O
213,15,the,O
213,16,flash,B-DISASTER
213,17,flood,I-DISASTER
213,18,.,O
215,0,In,O
215,1,Kingston,B-LOCATION
215,2,",",O
215,3,CNN,B-ORG
215,4,said,O
215,5,12,B-CASUALTY
215,6,injured,I-CASUALTY
215,7,were,O
215,8,reported,O
215,9,after,O
215,10,the,O
215,11,earthquake,B-DISASTER
215,12,",",O
215,13,and,O
215,14,crews,O
215,15,are,O
215,16,clearing,O
215,17,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
215,18,.,O
217,0,FEMA,B-ORG
217,1,and,O
217,2,CNN,B-ORG
217,3,delivered,O
217,4,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
217,5,and,O
217,6,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
217,7,to,O
217,8,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
217,9,City,I-LOCATION
217,10,after,O
217,11,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
217,12,Harvey,I-DISASTER
217,13,caused,O
217,14,children,B-CASUALTY
217,15,rescued,I-CASUALTY
217,16,.,O
219,0,Field,O
219,1,report,O
219,2,:,O
219,3,UNICEF,B-ORG
219,4,warned,O
219,5,that,O
219,6,flood,B-DISASTER
219,7,could,O
219,8,reach,O
219,9,San,B-LOCATION
219,10,Juan,I-LOCATION
219,11,after,O
219,12,flooding,O
219,13,around,O
219,14,Mexico,B-LOCATION
219,15,City,I-LOCATION
219,16,damaged,O
219,17,gas,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
219,18,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
219,19,.,O
220,0,children,B-CASUALTY
220,1,rescued,I-CASUALTY
220,2,in,O
220,3,Lima,B-LOCATION
220,4,after,O
220,5,landslide,B-DISASTER
220,6,",",O
220,7,according,O
220,8,to,O
220,9,National,B-ORG
220,10,Guard,I-ORG
220,11,",",O
220,12,with,O
220,13,outages,O
220,14,affecting,O
220,15,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
220,16,.,O
222,0,Red,B-ORG
222,1,Cross,I-ORG
222,2,and,O
222,3,World,B-ORG
222,4,Food,I-ORG
222,5,Programme,I-ORG
222,6,delivered,O
222,7,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
222,8,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
222,9,and,O
222,10,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
222,11,to,O
222,12,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
222,13,after,O
222,14,flood,B-DISASTER
222,15,caused,O
222,16,20,B-CASUALTY
222,17,residents,I-CASUALTY
222,18,trapped,I-CASUALTY
222,19,.,O
223,0,Residents,O
223,1,across,O
223,2,Kingston,B-LOCATION
223,3,are,O
223,4,waiting,O
223,5,for,O
223,6,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
223,7,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
223,8,as,O
223,9,damaged,O
223,10,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
223,11,slows,O
223,12,rescue,O
223,13,after,O
223,14,the,O
223,15,aftershock,B-DISASTER
223,16,.,O
224,0,Volunteers,O
224,1,in,O
224,2,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
224,3,City,I-LOCATION
224,4,are,O
224,5,distributing,O
224,6,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
224,7,to,O
224,8,families,O
224,9,displaced,O
224,10,by,O
224,11,the,O
224,12,tropical,B-DISASTER
224,13,storm,I-DISASTER
224,14,",",O
224,15,while,O
224,16,National,B-ORG
224,17,Guard,I-ORG
224,18,repairs,O
224,19,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
224,20,.,O
225,0,20,B-CASUALTY
225,1,residents,I-CASUALTY
225,2,trapped,I-CASUALTY
225,3,in,O
225,4,Santa,B-LOCATION
225,5,Rosa,I-LOCATION
225,6,after,O
225,7,flood,B-DISASTER
225,8,",",O
225,9,according,O
225,10,to,O
225,11,National,B-ORG
225,12,Guard,I-ORG
225,13,",",O
225,14,with,O
225,15,outages,O
225,16,affecting,O
225,17,roads,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
225,18,.,O
226,0,Road,O
226,1,crews,O
226,2,reopened,O
226,3,part,O
226,4,of,O
226,5,the,O
226,6,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
226,7,in,O
226,8,San,B-LOCATION
226,9,Juan,I-LOCATION
226,10,after,O
226,11,the,O
226,12,mudslide,B-DISASTER
226,13,",",O
226,14,but,O
226,15,World,B-ORG
226,16,Food,I-ORG
226,17,Programme,I-ORG
226,18,says,O
226,19,200,B-CASUALTY
226,20,dead,I-CASUALTY
226,21,still,O
226,22,need,O
226,23,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
226,24,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
226,25,.,O
227,0,fire,B-ORG
227,1,department,I-ORG
227,2,and,O
227,3,World,B-ORG
227,4,Food,I-ORG
227,5,Programme,I-ORG
227,6,delivered,O
227,7,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
227,8,and,O
227,9,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
227,10,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
227,11,to,O
227,12,Lima,B-LOCATION
227,13,after,O
227,14,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
227,15,Maria,I-DISASTER
227,16,caused,O
227,17,families,B-CASUALTY
227,18,displaced,I-CASUALTY
227,19,.,O
230,0,Witness,O
230,1,:,O
230,2,NOAA,B-ORG
230,3,warned,O
230,4,that,O
230,5,flash,B-DISASTER
230,6,flood,I-DISASTER
230,7,could,O
230,8,reach,O
230,9,San,B-LOCATION
230,10,Juan,I-LOCATION
230,11,after,O
230,12,flooding,O
230,13,around,O
230,14,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
230,15,City,I-LOCATION
230,16,damaged,O
230,17,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
230,18,.,O
231,0,local,B-ORG
231,1,police,I-ORG
231,2,confirmed,O
231,3,victims,B-CASUALTY
231,4,stranded,I-CASUALTY
231,5,near,O
231,6,Veracruz,B-LOCATION
231,7,after,O
231,8,the,O
231,9,wildfire,B-DISASTER
231,10,",",O
231,11,and,O
231,12,survivors,O
231,13,asked,O
231,14,for,O
231,15,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
231,16,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
231,17,instead,O
231,18,of,O
231,19,more,O
231,20,cameras,O
231,21,.,O
232,0,Severe,O
232,1,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
232,2,Irma,I-DISASTER
232,3,near,O
232,4,Haiti,B-LOCATION
232,5,destroyed,O
232,6,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
232,7,while,O
232,8,World,B-ORG
232,9,Food,I-ORG
232,10,Programme,I-ORG
232,11,moved,O
232,12,blankets,B-AID_RESOURCE
232,13,to,O
232,14,nearby,O
232,15,shelters,O
232,16,.,O
233,0,In,O
233,1,Texas,B-LOCATION
233,2,",",O
233,3,BBC,B-ORG
233,4,said,O
233,5,families,B-CASUALTY
233,6,displaced,I-CASUALTY
233,7,were,O
233,8,reported,O
233,9,after,O
233,10,the,O
233,11,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
233,12,Harvey,I-DISASTER
233,13,",",O
233,14,and,O
233,15,crews,O
233,16,are,O
233,17,clearing,O
233,18,communication,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
233,19,network,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
233,20,.,O
234,0,Severe,O
234,1,flash,B-DISASTER
234,2,flood,I-DISASTER
234,3,near,O
234,4,Ponce,B-LOCATION
234,5,destroyed,O
234,6,roads,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
234,7,while,O
234,8,local,B-ORG
234,9,police,I-ORG
234,10,moved,O
234,11,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
234,12,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
234,13,to,O
234,14,nearby,O
234,15,shelters,O
234,16,.,O
236,0,Severe,O
236,1,earth,B-DISASTER
236,2,tremor,I-DISASTER
236,3,near,O
236,4,Veracruz,B-LOCATION
236,5,destroyed,O
236,6,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
236,7,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
236,8,while,O
236,9,NOAA,B-ORG
236,10,moved,O
236,11,water,O
236,12,to,O
236,13,nearby,O
236,14,shelters,O
236,15,.,O
237,0,Army,B-ORG
237,1,Corps,I-ORG
237,2,and,O
237,3,local,B-ORG
237,4,police,I-ORG
237,5,delivered,O
237,6,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
237,7,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
237,8,and,O
237,9,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
237,10,to,O
237,11,Lima,B-LOCATION
237,12,after,O
237,13,wildfire,B-DISASTER
237,14,caused,O
237,15,evacuees,B-CASUALTY
237,16,injured,I-CASUALTY
237,17,.,O
238,0,World,B-ORG
238,1,Food,I-ORG
238,2,Programme,I-ORG
238,3,announced,O
238,4,that,O
238,5,residents,O
238,6,in,O
238,7,California,B-LOCATION
238,8,urgently,O
238,9,need,O
238,10,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
238,11,after,O
238,12,the,O
238,13,flood,B-DISASTER
238,14,.,O
240,0,National,B-ORG
240,1,Guard,I-ORG
240,2,confirmed,O
240,3,5,B-CASUALTY
240,4,confirmed,I-CASUALTY
240,5,deaths,I-CASUALTY
240,6,near,O
240,7,California,B-LOCATION
240,8,after,O
240,9,the,O
240,10,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
240,11,Irma,I-DISASTER
240,12,",",O
240,13,and,O
240,14,survivors,O
240,15,asked,O
240,16,for,O
240,17,blankets,B-AID_RESOURCE
240,18,instead,O
240,19,of,O
240,20,more,O
240,21,cameras,O
240,22,.,O
241,0,Residents,O
241,1,across,O
241,2,Naples,B-LOCATION
241,3,are,O
241,4,waiting,O
241,5,for,O
241,6,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
241,7,as,O
241,8,damaged,O
241,9,hospital,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
241,10,slows,O
241,11,rescue,O
241,12,after,O
241,13,the,O
241,14,flood,B-DISASTER
241,15,.,O
242,0,Reuters,B-ORG
242,1,confirmed,O
242,2,families,B-CASUALTY
242,3,displaced,I-CASUALTY
242,4,near,O
242,5,Lima,B-LOCATION
242,6,after,O
242,7,the,O
242,8,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
242,9,Irma,I-DISASTER
242,10,",",O
242,11,and,O
242,12,survivors,O
242,13,asked,O
242,14,for,O
242,15,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
242,16,instead,O
242,17,of,O
242,18,more,O
242,19,cameras,O
242,20,.,O
243,0,CNN,B-ORG
243,1,warned,O
243,2,that,O
243,3,residents,O
243,4,in,O
243,5,Naples,B-LOCATION
243,6,urgently,O
243,7,need,O
243,8,blankets,B-AID_RESOURCE
243,9,after,O
243,10,the,O
243,11,aftershock,B-DISASTER
243,12,.,O
244,0,fire,B-ORG
244,1,department,I-ORG
244,2,and,O
244,3,NOAA,B-ORG
244,4,delivered,O
244,5,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
244,6,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
244,7,and,O
244,8,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
244,9,to,O
244,10,Key,B-LOCATION
244,11,West,I-LOCATION
244,12,after,O
244,13,flash,B-DISASTER
244,14,flood,I-DISASTER
244,15,caused,O
244,16,missing,B-CASUALTY
244,17,tourists,I-CASUALTY
244,18,.,O
245,0,In,O
245,1,Haiti,B-LOCATION
245,2,",",O
245,3,NOAA,B-ORG
245,4,said,O
245,5,victims,B-CASUALTY
245,6,stranded,I-CASUALTY
245,7,were,O
245,8,reported,O
245,9,after,O
245,10,the,O
245,11,aftershock,B-DISASTER
245,12,",",O
245,13,and,O
245,14,crews,O
245,15,are,O
245,16,clearing,O
245,17,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
245,18,.,O
246,0,Volunteers,O
246,1,in,O
246,2,San,B-LOCATION
246,3,Juan,I-LOCATION
246,4,are,O
246,5,distributing,O
246,6,rescue,B-AID_RESOURCE
246,7,boats,I-AID_RESOURCE
246,8,to,O
246,9,families,O
246,10,displaced,O
246,11,by,O
246,12,the,O
246,13,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
246,14,Irma,I-DISASTER
246,15,",",O
246,16,while,O
246,17,NOAA,B-ORG
246,18,repairs,O
246,19,roads,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
246,20,.,O
247,0,Update,O
247,1,:,O
247,2,Army,B-ORG
247,3,Corps,I-ORG
247,4,warned,O
247,5,that,O
247,6,storm,B-DISASTER
247,7,surge,I-DISASTER
247,8,could,O
247,9,reach,O
247,10,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
247,11,after,O
247,12,flooding,O
247,13,around,O
247,14,Texas,B-LOCATION
247,15,damaged,O
247,16,communication,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
247,17,network,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
247,18,.,O
248,0,Breaking,O
248,1,:,O
248,2,rescue,B-ORG
248,3,teams,I-ORG
248,4,warned,O
248,5,that,O
248,6,flash,B-DISASTER
248,7,flood,I-DISASTER
248,8,could,O
248,9,reach,O
248,10,Naples,B-LOCATION
248,11,after,O
248,12,flooding,O
248,13,around,O
248,14,Lima,B-LOCATION
248,15,damaged,O
248,16,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
248,17,.,O
249,0,Road,O
249,1,crews,O
249,2,reopened,O
249,3,part,O
249,4,of,O
249,5,the,O
249,6,communication,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
249,7,network,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
249,8,in,O
249,9,Kingston,B-LOCATION
249,10,after,O
249,11,the,O
249,12,earthquake,B-DISASTER
249,13,",",O
249,14,but,O
249,15,Red,B-ORG
249,16,Cross,I-ORG
249,17,says,O
249,18,12,B-CASUALTY
249,19,injured,I-CASUALTY
249,20,still,O
249,21,need,O
249,22,generators,B-AID_RESOURCE
249,23,.,O
250,0,FEMA,B-ORG
250,1,said,O
250,2,that,O
250,3,residents,O
250,4,in,O
250,5,Sicily,B-LOCATION
250,6,urgently,O
250,7,need,O
250,8,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
250,9,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
250,10,after,O
250,11,the,O
250,12,earth,B-DISASTER
250,13,tremor,I-DISASTER
250,14,.,O
251,0,local,B-ORG
251,1,police,I-ORG
251,2,and,O
251,3,World,B-ORG
251,4,Food,I-ORG
251,5,Programme,I-ORG
251,6,delivered,O
251,7,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
251,8,and,O
251,9,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
251,10,to,O
251,11,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
251,12,City,I-LOCATION
251,13,after,O
251,14,earth,B-DISASTER
251,15,tremor,I-DISASTER
251,16,caused,O
251,17,injured,B-CASUALTY
251,18,residents,I-CASUALTY
251,19,.,O
252,0,Severe,O
252,1,aftershock,B-DISASTER
252,2,near,O
252,3,Monterrey,B-LOCATION
252,4,destroyed,O
252,5,gas,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
252,6,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
252,7,while,O
252,8,Red,B-ORG
252,9,Cross,I-ORG
252,10,moved,O
252,11,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
252,12,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
252,13,to,O
252,14,nearby,O
252,15,shelters,O
252,16,.,O
253,0,Update,O
253,1,:,O
253,2,wildfire,B-DISASTER
253,3,damaged,O
253,4,Lima,B-LOCATION
253,5,",",O
253,6,leaving,O
253,7,hundreds,B-CASUALTY
253,8,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
253,9,and,O
253,10,damaging,O
253,11,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
253,12,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
253,13,.,O
254,0,In,O
254,1,Veracruz,B-LOCATION
254,2,",",O
254,3,Doctors,B-ORG
254,4,Without,I-ORG
254,5,Borders,I-ORG
254,6,said,O
254,7,3,B-CASUALTY
254,8,people,I-CASUALTY
254,9,missing,I-CASUALTY
254,10,were,O
254,11,reported,O
254,12,after,O
254,13,the,O
254,14,earth,B-DISASTER
254,15,tremor,I-DISASTER
254,16,",",O
254,17,and,O
254,18,crews,O
254,19,are,O
254,20,clearing,O
254,21,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
254,22,.,O
255,0,Update,O
255,1,:,O
255,2,earthquake,B-DISASTER
255,3,threatened,O
255,4,Florida,B-LOCATION
255,5,",",O
255,6,leaving,O
255,7,3,B-CASUALTY
255,8,people,I-CASUALTY
255,9,missing,I-CASUALTY
255,10,and,O
255,11,damaging,O
255,12,hospitals,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
255,13,.,O
256,0,Alert,O
256,1,:,O
256,2,flash,B-DISASTER
256,3,flood,I-DISASTER
256,4,devastated,O
256,5,Lima,B-LOCATION
256,6,",",O
256,7,leaving,O
256,8,evacuees,B-CASUALTY
256,9,injured,I-CASUALTY
256,10,and,O
256,11,damaging,O
256,12,roads,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
256,13,.,O
259,0,BBC,B-ORG
259,1,and,O
259,2,local,B-ORG
259,3,police,I-ORG
259,4,delivered,O
259,5,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
259,6,and,O
259,7,medical,B-AID_RESOURCE
259,8,supplies,I-AID_RESOURCE
259,9,to,O
259,10,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
259,11,after,O
259,12,aftershock,B-DISASTER
259,13,caused,O
259,14,victims,B-CASUALTY
259,15,stranded,I-CASUALTY
259,16,.,O
260,0,Severe,O
260,1,tropical,B-DISASTER
260,2,storm,I-DISASTER
260,3,near,O
260,4,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
260,5,destroyed,O
260,6,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
260,7,while,O
260,8,local,B-ORG
260,9,police,I-ORG
260,10,moved,O
260,11,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
260,12,to,O
260,13,nearby,O
260,14,shelters,O
260,15,.,O
261,0,Breaking,O
261,1,:,O
261,2,landslide,B-DISASTER
261,3,swept,O
261,4,through,O
261,5,Santa,B-LOCATION
261,6,Rosa,I-LOCATION
261,7,",",O
261,8,leaving,O
261,9,evacuees,B-CASUALTY
261,10,injured,I-CASUALTY
261,11,and,O
261,12,damaging,O
261,13,airport,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
261,14,.,O
262,0,World,B-ORG
262,1,Food,I-ORG
262,2,Programme,I-ORG
262,3,and,O
262,4,BBC,B-ORG
262,5,delivered,O
262,6,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
262,7,and,O
262,8,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
262,9,to,O
262,10,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
262,11,after,O
262,12,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
262,13,Irma,I-DISASTER
262,14,caused,O
262,15,injured,B-CASUALTY
262,16,residents,I-CASUALTY
262,17,.,O
263,0,Update,O
263,1,:,O
263,2,forest,B-DISASTER
263,3,fire,I-DISASTER
263,4,threatened,O
263,5,Houston,B-LOCATION
263,6,",",O
263,7,leaving,O
263,8,victims,B-CASUALTY
263,9,stranded,I-CASUALTY
263,10,and,O
263,11,damaging,O
263,12,roads,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
263,13,.,O
264,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
264,1,said,O
264,2,that,O
264,3,residents,O
264,4,in,O
264,5,Sicily,B-LOCATION
264,6,urgently,O
264,7,need,O
264,8,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
264,9,after,O
264,10,the,O
264,11,mudslide,B-DISASTER
264,12,.,O
266,0,Road,O
266,1,crews,O
266,2,reopened,O
266,3,part,O
266,4,of,O
266,5,the,O
266,6,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
266,7,in,O
266,8,Orlando,B-LOCATION
266,9,after,O
266,10,the,O
266,11,storm,B-DISASTER
266,12,surge,I-DISASTER
266,13,",",O
266,14,but,O
266,15,UNICEF,B-ORG
266,16,says,O
266,17,families,B-CASUALTY
266,18,displaced,I-CASUALTY
266,19,still,O
266,20,need,O
266,21,donations,B-AID_RESOURCE
266,22,.,O
267,0,Emergency,O
267,1,update,O
267,2,:,O
267,3,wildfire,B-DISASTER
267,4,struck,O
267,5,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
267,6,",",O
267,7,leaving,O
267,8,children,B-CASUALTY
267,9,rescued,I-CASUALTY
267,10,and,O
267,11,damaging,O
267,12,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
267,13,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
267,14,.,O
268,0,families,B-CASUALTY
268,1,displaced,I-CASUALTY
268,2,in,O
268,3,Ponce,B-LOCATION
268,4,after,O
268,5,landslide,B-DISASTER
268,6,",",O
268,7,according,O
268,8,to,O
268,9,Army,B-ORG
268,10,Corps,I-ORG
268,11,",",O
268,12,with,O
268,13,outages,O
268,14,affecting,O
268,15,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
268,16,.,O
269,0,families,B-CASUALTY
269,1,displaced,I-CASUALTY
269,2,in,O
269,3,Veracruz,B-LOCATION
269,4,after,O
269,5,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
269,6,Maria,I-DISASTER
269,7,",",O
269,8,according,O
269,9,to,O
269,10,Doctors,B-ORG
269,11,Without,I-ORG
269,12,Borders,I-ORG
269,13,",",O
269,14,with,O
269,15,outages,O
269,16,affecting,O
269,17,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
269,18,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
269,19,.,O
270,0,Update,O
270,1,:,O
270,2,landslide,B-DISASTER
270,3,threatened,O
270,4,San,B-LOCATION
270,5,Juan,I-LOCATION
270,6,",",O
270,7,leaving,O
270,8,injured,B-CASUALTY
270,9,residents,I-CASUALTY
270,10,and,O
270,11,damaging,O
270,12,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
270,13,.,O
271,0,In,O
271,1,Key,B-LOCATION
271,2,West,I-LOCATION
271,3,",",O
271,4,National,B-ORG
271,5,Guard,I-ORG
271,6,said,O
271,7,12,B-CASUALTY
271,8,injured,I-CASUALTY
271,9,were,O
271,10,reported,O
271,11,after,O
271,12,the,O
271,13,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
271,14,Irma,I-DISASTER
271,15,",",O
271,16,and,O
271,17,crews,O
271,18,are,O
271,19,clearing,O
271,20,roads,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
271,21,.,O
272,0,local,B-ORG
272,1,police,I-ORG
272,2,confirmed,O
272,3,20,B-CASUALTY
272,4,residents,I-CASUALTY
272,5,trapped,I-CASUALTY
272,6,near,O
272,7,Haiti,B-LOCATION
272,8,after,O
272,9,the,O
272,10,earth,B-DISASTER
272,11,tremor,I-DISASTER
272,12,",",O
272,13,and,O
272,14,survivors,O
272,15,asked,O
272,16,for,O
272,17,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
272,18,instead,O
272,19,of,O
272,20,more,O
272,21,cameras,O
272,22,.,O
273,0,Update,O
273,1,:,O
273,2,landslide,B-DISASTER
273,3,hit,O
273,4,Veracruz,B-LOCATION
273,5,",",O
273,6,leaving,O
273,7,evacuees,B-CASUALTY
273,8,injured,I-CASUALTY
273,9,and,O
273,10,damaging,O
273,11,water,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
273,12,plant,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
273,13,.,O
274,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
274,1,announced,O
274,2,that,O
274,3,residents,O
274,4,in,O
274,5,Mexico,B-LOCATION
274,6,City,I-LOCATION
274,7,urgently,O
274,8,need,O
274,9,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
274,10,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
274,11,after,O
274,12,the,O
274,13,landslide,B-DISASTER
274,14,.,O
275,0,Photos,O
275,1,from,O
275,2,Kingston,B-LOCATION
275,3,show,O
275,4,collapsed,O
275,5,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
275,6,after,O
275,7,the,O
275,8,storm,B-DISASTER
275,9,surge,I-DISASTER
275,10,;,O
275,11,UNICEF,B-ORG
275,12,expects,O
275,13,more,O
275,14,requests,O
275,15,for,O
275,16,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
275,17,.,O
276,0,Witness,O
276,1,:,O
276,2,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
276,3,Irma,I-DISASTER
276,4,swept,O
276,5,through,O
276,6,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
276,7,City,I-LOCATION
276,8,",",O
276,9,leaving,O
276,10,20,B-CASUALTY
276,11,residents,I-CASUALTY
276,12,trapped,I-CASUALTY
276,13,and,O
276,14,damaging,O
276,15,communication,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
276,16,network,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
276,17,.,O
281,0,Severe,O
281,1,tropical,B-DISASTER
281,2,storm,I-DISASTER
281,3,near,O
281,4,Key,B-LOCATION
281,5,West,I-LOCATION
281,6,destroyed,O
281,7,port,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
281,8,while,O
281,9,World,B-ORG
281,10,Food,I-ORG
281,11,Programme,I-ORG
281,12,moved,O
281,13,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
281,14,to,O
281,15,nearby,O
281,16,shelters,O
281,17,.,O
282,0,rescue,B-ORG
282,1,teams,I-ORG
282,2,and,O
282,3,Reuters,B-ORG
282,4,delivered,O
282,5,water,B-AID_RESOURCE
282,6,and,O
282,7,portable,B-AID_RESOURCE
282,8,chargers,I-AID_RESOURCE
282,9,to,O
282,10,Haiti,B-LOCATION
282,11,after,O
282,12,tornado,B-DISASTER
282,13,caused,O
282,14,20,B-CASUALTY
282,15,residents,I-CASUALTY
282,16,trapped,I-CASUALTY
282,17,.,O
284,0,Volunteers,O
284,1,in,O
284,2,St,B-LOCATION
284,3,.,I-LOCATION
284,4,Thomas,I-LOCATION
284,5,are,O
284,6,distributing,O
284,7,shelter,B-AID_RESOURCE
284,8,to,O
284,9,families,O
284,10,displaced,O
284,11,by,O
284,12,the,O
284,13,wildfire,B-DISASTER
284,14,",",O
284,15,while,O
284,16,World,B-ORG
284,17,Food,I-ORG
284,18,Programme,I-ORG
284,19,repairs,O
284,20,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
284,21,.,O
285,0,Severe,O
285,1,mudslide,B-DISASTER
285,2,near,O
285,3,Guatemala,B-LOCATION
285,4,City,I-LOCATION
285,5,destroyed,O
285,6,bridges,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
285,7,while,O
285,8,CNN,B-ORG
285,9,moved,O
285,10,food,B-AID_RESOURCE
285,11,to,O
285,12,nearby,O
285,13,shelters,O
285,14,.,O
286,0,Residents,O
286,1,across,O
286,2,Mexico,B-LOCATION
286,3,City,I-LOCATION
286,4,are,O
286,5,waiting,O
286,6,for,O
286,7,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
286,8,as,O
286,9,damaged,O
286,10,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
286,11,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
286,12,slows,O
286,13,rescue,O
286,14,after,O
286,15,the,O
286,16,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
286,17,Irma,I-DISASTER
286,18,.,O
288,0,Field,O
288,1,report,O
288,2,:,O
288,3,rescue,B-ORG
288,4,teams,I-ORG
288,5,warned,O
288,6,that,O
288,7,earth,B-DISASTER
288,8,tremor,I-DISASTER
288,9,could,O
288,10,reach,O
288,11,Santa,B-LOCATION
288,12,Rosa,I-LOCATION
288,13,after,O
288,14,flooding,O
288,15,around,O
288,16,St,B-LOCATION
288,17,.,I-LOCATION
288,18,Thomas,I-LOCATION
288,19,damaged,O
288,20,power,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
288,21,lines,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
288,22,.,O
289,0,20,B-CASUALTY
289,1,residents,I-CASUALTY
289,2,trapped,I-CASUALTY
289,3,in,O
289,4,Houston,B-LOCATION
289,5,after,O
289,6,Hurricane,B-DISASTER
289,7,Maria,I-DISASTER
289,8,",",O
289,9,according,O
289,10,to,O
289,11,National,B-ORG
289,12,Guard,I-ORG
289,13,",",O
289,14,with,O
289,15,outages,O
289,16,affecting,O
289,17,schools,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
289,18,.,O
291,0,BBC,B-ORG
291,1,and,O
291,2,local,B-ORG
291,3,police,I-ORG
291,4,delivered,O
291,5,fuel,B-AID_RESOURCE
291,6,and,O
291,7,tarps,B-AID_RESOURCE
291,8,to,O
291,9,Haiti,B-LOCATION
291,10,after,O
291,11,forest,B-DISASTER
291,12,fire,I-DISASTER
291,13,caused,O
291,14,victims,B-CASUALTY
291,15,stranded,I-CASUALTY
291,16,.,O
294,0,UNICEF,B-ORG
294,1,confirmed,O
294,2,that,O
294,3,residents,O
294,4,in,O
294,5,Kingston,B-LOCATION
294,6,urgently,O
294,7,need,O
294,8,volunteers,B-AID_RESOURCE
294,9,after,O
294,10,the,O
294,11,earth,B-DISASTER
294,12,tremor,I-DISASTER
294,13,.,O
295,0,hundreds,B-CASUALTY
295,1,evacuated,I-CASUALTY
295,2,in,O
295,3,Naples,B-LOCATION
295,4,after,O
295,5,tropical,B-DISASTER
295,6,storm,I-DISASTER
295,7,",",O
295,8,according,O
295,9,to,O
295,10,NOAA,B-ORG
295,11,",",O
295,12,with,O
295,13,outages,O
295,14,affecting,O
295,15,bridge,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
295,16,.,O
296,0,Residents,O
296,1,across,O
296,2,Dominica,B-LOCATION
296,3,are,O
296,4,waiting,O
296,5,for,O
296,6,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
296,7,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
296,8,as,O
296,9,damaged,O
296,10,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
296,11,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
296,12,slows,O
296,13,rescue,O
296,14,after,O
296,15,the,O
296,16,earthquake,B-DISASTER
296,17,.,O
297,0,Volunteers,O
297,1,in,O
297,2,Jakarta,B-LOCATION
297,3,are,O
297,4,distributing,O
297,5,first,B-AID_RESOURCE
297,6,aid,I-AID_RESOURCE
297,7,to,O
297,8,families,O
297,9,displaced,O
297,10,by,O
297,11,the,O
297,12,flash,B-DISASTER
297,13,flood,I-DISASTER
297,14,",",O
297,15,while,O
297,16,fire,B-ORG
297,17,department,I-ORG
297,18,repairs,O
297,19,subway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
297,20,station,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
297,21,.,O
298,0,Breaking,O
298,1,:,O
298,2,Red,B-ORG
298,3,Cross,I-ORG
298,4,warned,O
298,5,that,O
298,6,tornado,B-DISASTER
298,7,could,O
298,8,reach,O
298,9,Key,B-LOCATION
298,10,West,I-LOCATION
298,11,after,O
298,12,flooding,O
298,13,around,O
298,14,Ponce,B-LOCATION
298,15,damaged,O
298,16,highway,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
298,17,.,O
299,0,Volunteers,O
299,1,in,O
299,2,Bayamon,B-LOCATION
299,3,are,O
299,4,distributing,O
299,5,baby,B-AID_RESOURCE
299,6,formula,I-AID_RESOURCE
299,7,to,O
299,8,families,O
299,9,displaced,O
299,10,by,O
299,11,the,O
299,12,aftershock,B-DISASTER
299,13,",",O
299,14,while,O
299,15,Army,B-ORG
299,16,Corps,I-ORG
299,17,repairs,O
299,18,cell,B-INFRASTRUCTURE
299,19,towers,I-INFRASTRUCTURE
299,20,.,O
